<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../../../../../../XSD/styles/kenya.xsl""?><!--Akoma_Ntoso document--><akomantoso xmlns="http://www.akomantoso.org/1.0" xmlns:cirsfid="http://www.cirsfid.unibo.it/proprietary" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><act contains="OriginalVersion"><meta><identification source="#au1"><Work><uri href="/ken/act/1993-12-16/9"/><date date="2007-02-21" name="Generation"/><author id="au1" href="http://www.cirsfid.unibo.it"/></Work><Expression><uri href="/ken/act/1993-12-16/9/eng"/><date date="2007-02-21" name="Generation"/><author href="#au1"/><components><component id="ce1" href="ken/act/1993-12-16/9/eng/main" showAs="main"/></components></Expression><Manifestation><uri href="/ken/act/1993-12-16/9/eng.xml"/><date date="2007-02-21" name="Generation"/><author href="#au1"/><components><component id="cm1" href="ken/act/1993-12-16/9/eng/main.xml" showAs="main"/></components></Manifestation></identification><publication name="" date="1993-12-31" showAs=""/><lifecycle source="#au1"><event id="e1" date="1993-12-31" source="#ro1" type="Generation"/></lifecycle><references source="#au1"><Original id="ro1" href="ken/act/1993-12-16/9/eng/main" showAs="Original"/></references><proprietary source="#au1"><cirsfid:proprietary><cirsfid:MissingInfo><cirsfid:mDocType>act</cirsfid:mDocType></cirsfid:MissingInfo></cirsfid:proprietary></proprietary></meta><preface><p>Kenya Gazette Supplement No. 86 {Acts No. 7)<eol/><eol/><ActTitle id="ActTitle">THE ROAD MAINTENANCE LEVY FUND ACT, 1993</ActTitle><eol/>No. <ActNumber>9</ActNumber> of 1993<eol/>Date of Assent: <ActDate date="1993-12-16">16th December, 1993</ActDate><eol/>Date of Commencement: 31st December, 1993<eol/>ARRANGEMENT OF SECTIONS<eol/>Section<eol/>1 - Short title.<eol/>2 - Interpretation.<eol/>3 - Imposition of levy. <eol/>4 - Registration of remitters.<eol/>5 - Levies collected to be remitted to the collector. <eol/>6 - Defaulting remitters to pay penalty. <eol/>7 - Establishment of Road Maintenance Levy Fund.<eol/>8 - Functions and powers of the officer administering the Fund.<eol/>9 - Offences. <eol/>10 - Amendment of Schedules.<eol/>11 - Regulations.<eol/><eol/>Schedules.</p></preface><preamble id="preamble"><p>An Act of Parliament to provide for the imposition of a road maintenance levy on petroleum fuels and for the establishment and administration of a Road Maintenance Levy Fund and for connected purposes<eol/><eol/><eol/>ENACTED by the Parliament of Kenya as follows: -</p></preamble><clauses><article id="art1"><title>Short title.</title><clause id="art1-cla1"><num>1.</num><p>This Act may be cited as the Road Maintenance Levy Fund Act, 1993.</p></clause></article><article id="art2"><clause id="art2-cla1"><sidenote>Cap. 399.</sidenote><p>2.  -In this Act, unless the context otherwise requires - <eol/>"classified road" means any public road which on or before the commencement of this Act is maintained by or under the authority of the Ministry of Public Works and Housing or which is dissatisfied as such with the approval of the Minister or any adopted street under the Streets Adoption Act;<eol/>"collector" means  the Commissioner of Customs and Excuse;<eol/>"levy" means the road maintenance fuel levy imposed under section 3;<eol/>"marketeer" means a person who engages in the business of importing, processing and marketing of petroleum products and for the time being specified in the First Schedule;<eol/>"Minister" means the Minister for the time being responsible for Public Works and Housing or for public roads;<eol/><eol/>Cap. 403. <eol/>"motor vehicle" has the meaning assigned to it in section 2 of the Traffic Act;<eol/>"officer administering the Fund" means the Permanent Secretary to the Treasury or any person appointed by him in writing for that purpose;<eol/>"petroleum fuel" means automotive diesel, ordinary petrol, super petrol or such other petroleum products as the Minister may from time to time by notice in the Gazette determine;<eol/>Cap. 399.<eol/>"public road" has the meaning assigned to it in the Public Roads and Roads of Access Act;<eol/>"remitter" means a marketeer registered under section 4;<eol/>"vehicle" includes a motor vehicle, a trailer or such other conveyance as the Minister may from time to time determine by notice in the Gazette.</p></clause></article><article id="art3"><title>Imposition of the levy.</title><clause id="art3-cla1"><p>3. (1) The Minister may, by  Order published  in the Gazette, impose on any or all petroleum fuels consumed in Kenya a road maintenance fuel levy (in this Act referred to as the "levy") which may be determined from time to time and in such manner as the Minister may specify in the Order.</p></clause><clause id="art3-cla2"><num>(2)</num><p>The levy shall be payable in respect of any vehicle for use on any classified road and shall be collected on behalf of the collector by the remitter.</p></clause></article><article id="art4"><title>Registration of remitters.</title><clause id="art4-cla1"><p>4. (1) Any person who - <eol/></p><ul id="ul1"><li id="art4-cla1-itma"><p>(a) at the commencement of this Act is a marketeer shall, on or before the expiration of thirty days after such commencement register as a remitter; or</p></li><li id="art4-cla1-itmb"><p>(b)on or after the commencement of this Act becomes a marketeer, shall before the last day of the month immediately following the month in which he becomes a marketeer register as a remitter.</p></li></ul></clause></article></clauses></act></akomantoso>