<akomaNtoso xmlns:an="http://www.akomantoso.org/1.0"><act contains="singleVersion"><meta><identification source="#kenyalaw"><FRBRWork><FRBRthis value="/ke/act/1934-07-01/30/main"/><FRBRuri value="/ke/act/1934-07-01/30"/><FRBRdate date="1934-07-01" name="Generation"/><FRBRauthor as="#author" href="#parliament"/><components><component href="#emain" id="wmain" name="main" showAs="Main Document"/></components></FRBRWork><FRBRExpression><FRBRthis value="/ke/act/1934-07-01/30/eng@/main"/><FRBRuri value="/ke/act/1934-07-01/30/eng@"/><FRBRdate date="1934-07-01" name="Generation"/><FRBRauthor as="#author" href="#parliament"/><components><component href="#mmain" id="emain" name="main" showAs="Main Document"/></components></FRBRExpression><FRBRManifestation><FRBRthis value="/ke/act/1934-07-01/30/eng@/main.xml"/><FRBRuri value="/ke/act/1934-07-01/30/eng@/.akn"/><FRBRdate date="1934-07-01" name="Generation"/><FRBRauthor as="#author" href="#parliament"/><components><component href="#mmain" id="mmain" name="main" showAs="Main Document"/></components></FRBRManifestation></identification><publication date="1934-07-01" name="" showAs=""/><lifecycle source="#bungeni"><event date="1934-07-01" id="e1" source="#ro1" type="generation"/></lifecycle><references source="#kenyalaw"><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActTitle" id="TheActTitle" showAs="Act Title"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActLongTitle" id="TheActLongTitle" showAs="Act Description"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/AssentDate" id="AssentDate" showAs="Assent Date"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/CommencementDate" id="CommencementDate" showAs="Commencement Date"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActNumber" id="TheActNumber" showAs="Act Number"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActID" id="TheActID" showAs="Act ID"/><TLCConcept href="http://bungeni-lexmigrate.googlecode.com" id="bungeni" showAs="Lex Migrator"/><TLCConcept href="http://kenyalaw.org" id="kenyalaw" showAs="Kenya Law"/></references><proprietary xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" source="#kenyalaw"><kl:meta name="gokcatid" num="4"/><kl:meta name="gokcatname">Civil Law and Procedure</kl:meta><kl:meta name="lexyy" num="1934"/><kl:meta name="lexmm" num="7"/><kl:meta name="lexdd" num="1"/></proprietary></meta><preface><block name="preface"><docTitle id="ActTitle" refersTo="#TheActTitle">Limited Partnerships</docTitle><docTitle id="ActLongTitle" refersTo="#TheActLongTitle">An Act of Parliament to establish limited partnerships</docTitle><docDate date="1934-07-01" refersTo="#CommencementDate">Jul 1, 1934</docDate><docDate date="1111-11-11" refersTo="#AssentDate">Nov 11, 1111</docDate><docNumber id="ActNumber" refersTo="#TheActNumber">30</docNumber><docNumber id="ActIdentifier" refersTo="#TheActID">32</docNumber></block></preface><preamble><p>ARRANGEMENT OF SECTIONS</p><toc><tocItem href="#section-24354" level="2"> THE LIMITED PARTNERSHIPS RULES</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12155" level="2">1 Short title.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12156" level="2">2 Interpretation.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12157" level="2">3 Definition and constitution.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12158" level="2">4 Registration required.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12159" level="2">5 Modifications of general law.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12160" level="2">6 Law as to private partnership to apply subject to this Act.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12161" level="2">7 Manner and particulars of registration.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12162" level="2">8 Registration of changes in partnerships.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12163" level="2">9 Notice of general partner becoming a limited partner or of assignment of share of limited partner to be advertised.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12164" level="2">10 Ad valorem stamp duty on contributions by limited partners.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12165" level="2">11 Making false returns to be an offence.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12166" level="2">12 Registrar to file statement and issue certificate of registration.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12167" level="2">13 Register and index to be kept.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12168" level="2">14 Inspection of statements registered.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12169" level="2">15 Rules.</tocItem></toc></preamble><body><section id="section-24354"><num/><heading>SECTION  THE LIMITED PARTNERSHIPS RULES</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:div>
  SUBSIDIARY LEGISLATION 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:p><xhtml:br/> Rules under Section 15</xhtml:p><xhtml:div>
  THE LIMITED PARTNERSHIPS RULES 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:p><xhtml:br/> 1. These Rules may be cited as the Limited Partnerships Rules.<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/> 2. The fees to be paid to the registrar of companies under the Act shall be as follows—<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/> (a) on the original registration of a limited partnership the sum of forty shillings;<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/> (b) on the registration of a statement of any change within the meaning of section 8 (1) of the Act occurring during the continuance of a limited partnership the sum of five shillings;<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/> (c) by any person inspecting the statements filed by the registrar of companies in the register office the sum of one shilling for each inspection;<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/> (d) by any person requiring a certificate of the registration of any limited partnership or a certified copy of or extract from any registered statement the sum of two shillings for each certificate and for such certified copy or extract the sum of fifty cents for each folio of one hundred words.<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/> 3. The forms in the Schedule hereto with such variation as the circumstances of each case may require shall be the forms to be used for the purposes of the Act.</xhtml:p><xhtml:div>
  SCHEDULE 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:div>
  (r. 3) 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:p> No. of Certificate</xhtml:p><xhtml:div>
  Form No. L.P.1. 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:div>
  THE LIMITED PARTNERSHIPS ACT 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:p> &#160;</xhtml:p><xhtml:div>
  APPLICATION FOR REGISTRATION OF A LIMITED PARTNERSHIP 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:p><xhtml:br/> We, the undersigned, being the partners of the firm of hereby apply for registration as a limited partnership, and for that purpose supply the following particulars, pursuant to section 7 of the Limited Partnerships Act: <xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/> The firm name: <xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/> The general nature of the business: <xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/> The principal place of business: <xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/> The term, if any, for which the partnership is entered into, and the date of its commencement: <xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/> Term if any:…………………………………. years, <xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/> If no definite term, the conditions of existence of the partnership: <xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/> Date of commencement: <xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/> The partnership is limited. <xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/> Presented or forwarded for filing by:— <xhtml:br/> Full name and address of each of the partners: <xhtml:br/> General partners: <xhtml:br/> Limited partners: <xhtml:br/> Amount contributed by each limited partner, and whether paid in cash, or how otherwise:* <xhtml:br/> Signatures of all the partners:</xhtml:p><xhtml:div>
  Date………………………….. 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:p> _____________________________________________________________________________________________________________________</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> * A separate statement (Form L.P.3) of the amounts contributed must accompany this application, for the purpose of payment of stamp duty, pursuant to section 10 of the Act. <xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/> No. of Certificate</xhtml:p><xhtml:div>
  Form No. L.P.2. 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:div>
  THE LIMITED PARTNERSHIPS ACT<xhtml:br/> Notice of Change in the Limited Partnership 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:p><xhtml:br/> † .....................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> Notice is hereby given, pursuant to section 8 of the Limited Partnerships Act, that the changes specified below have occurred in this limited partnership:—</xhtml:p><xhtml:div>
  (See footnote.) 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:p> (a)Change in the firm name: <xhtml:br/> Previous name: <xhtml:br/> New name: <xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/> (b)Change in the general nature of the business: <xhtml:br/> General nature of business as previously carried on: <xhtml:br/> General nature of business as now carried on: <xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/> (c)Change in the principal place of business: <xhtml:br/> Previous place of business: <xhtml:br/> New place of business: <xhtml:br/> Presented or forwarded for filing by:— <xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/> (d)Change in the partners, or the name of any partner: <xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/> Note.—Changes brought about by death, by transfer of interests, by increase in the number of partners, or by change of name of any partner, must be here notified. <xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/> (e)Change in the term or character of the partnership: <xhtml:br/> Previous term, if any, but, if no definite term, then the conditions under which <xhtml:br/> the partnership was constituted. <xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/> New term, if any, but, if no definite term, then the conditions under which the partnership is now constituted.<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/> (f) Change in the sum contributed by any limited partner. <xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/> Note.—Any variation in the sum contributed by any limited partner must be here stated. A statement (Form L.P.4) of any increase in the amount of the partnership capital, whether arising from an increase of contributions, or from introduction of fresh partners, must be made on a separate form, for the purpose of payment of stamp duty, pursuant to section 10 of the Act. <xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/> (g)Change in the liability any partner by reason of his becoming a limited instead of a general partner, or a general instead of a limited partner.</xhtml:p><xhtml:div>
  Signature of firm…………………… <xhtml:br/> Date………………………………… 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:p> _________________________________________________________________________________________________________________________</xhtml:p><xhtml:div>
  † Here insert name of firm or partnership. 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:p><xhtml:br/> Note.—Each change must be entered in the proper division (a), (b), (c), (d), (e), (f) or (g), as the case may be. <xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/> Provision is made in this form for notifying all the changes required by the Act to be notified, but it will frequently happen that only one item of change, such as change in the principal place of business, for instance, has to be notified. In any such case, the word “nil” should be inserted in the other divisions. <xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/> The statement must be signed at the end by the firm, and delivered for registration within seven days of the change or changes taking place. <xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/> No. of Certificate</xhtml:p><xhtml:div>
  Form No. L.P.3. 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:div>
  THE LIMITED PARTNERSHIPS ACT 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:div>
  *………………… 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:div>
  STATEMENT OF THE CAPITAL CONTRIBUTED BY LIMITED PARTNERS MADE PURSUANT TO SECTION 10 OF THE LIMITED PARTNERSHIPS ACT 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:p><xhtml:br/> The amounts contributed in cash or otherwise by the limited partners of the firm* ...................................................are as follows :—</xhtml:p><xhtml:table><xhtml:tbody><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="263"><xhtml:p> Names and addresses of limited partners</xhtml:p></xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="264"><xhtml:p> Amount contributed in cash, or otherwise </xhtml:p><xhtml:p> (if otherwise than in cash, that fact, </xhtml:p><xhtml:p> with particulars, must be stated) </xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="263"><xhtml:p> </xhtml:p></xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="264"><xhtml:p> </xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr></xhtml:tbody></xhtml:table><xhtml:div>
  Signature of a general partner <xhtml:br/> Date ……………………….. 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:p><xhtml:br/> Note.—The stamp duty on the nominal capital is five shillings for every two thousand shillings, or fraction of two thousand shillings, contributed by each limited partner. <xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/> This statement must accompany the application form L.P.1 for registration of a limited partnership. <xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/> Presented or forwarded for registration by</xhtml:p><xhtml:div>
  _______________________________________________________________________________________________________________________ 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:div>
  * Here insert name of firm or limited partnership. 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:p><xhtml:br/> No. of Certificate</xhtml:p><xhtml:div>
  Form No. L.P.4. 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:div>
  THE LIMITED PARTNERSHIPS ACT 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:p> †………………….</xhtml:p><xhtml:div>
  STATEMENT OF INCREASE OF CAPITAL CONTRIBUTED IN CASH, OR OTHERWISE, BY LIMITED PARTNERS, PURSUANT TO SECTION 10 OF THE LIMITED PARTNERSHIPS ACT 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:p><xhtml:br/> The capital of the limited partnership†………………………... has been increased by the addition thereto of sums contributed, in cash or otherwise, by the limited partners, as follows :—</xhtml:p><xhtml:table><xhtml:tbody><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="176"><xhtml:p> Names of limited partners</xhtml:p></xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="176"><xhtml:p> Increase or additional sum now contributed (if otherwise than in cash, that fact, with particulars, must be stated)</xhtml:p></xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="176"><xhtml:p> Total amount contributed </xhtml:p><xhtml:p> (if otherwise than in cash, </xhtml:p><xhtml:p> that fact, with particulars, </xhtml:p><xhtml:p> must be stated) </xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="176"><xhtml:p> </xhtml:p></xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="176"><xhtml:p> </xhtml:p></xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="176"><xhtml:p> </xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr></xhtml:tbody></xhtml:table><xhtml:div>
  † Here insert name of firm or limited partnership. 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:p> &#160;</xhtml:p><xhtml:div>
  Signature of a general partner .............. <xhtml:br/> Date ................................. 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:p><xhtml:br/> Notes.—In the case of a new limited partner, the first and third columns only will be used. <xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/> The stamp duty on an increase of capital is five shillings for every two thousand shillings, or fraction of two thousand shillings, contributed by each limited partner. <xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/> This statement is to be filed within seven days of the increase taking place. <xhtml:br/> Presented or forwarded for registration by <xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/> No.</xhtml:p><xhtml:div>
  CERTIFICATE OF REGISTRATION OF A LIMITED PARTNERSHIP 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:p><xhtml:br/> I hereby certify that the firm having lodged a statement of particulars pursuant to section 7 of the Limited Partnerships Act, is this day registered as a limited partnership. <xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/> Given under my hand at Nairobi this ………………………………..day of………….. , 19……..<xhtml:br/> Fee paid, Sh. …………………………………………… <xhtml:br/> Stamp duty on capital Sh. ………………………………</xhtml:p><xhtml:div>
  …………………………….<xhtml:br/> Registrar of Companies 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:p> PURSUANT TO SECTION 9 OF THE LIMITED PARTNERSHIPS ACT</xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:br/> Notice is hereby given that under an arrangement entered into on the…day of ……, 20……. , ………. ceases to be a general partner and becomes a limited partner in the firm of carrying on business as at <xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/> Dated this…………………………………….day of …………………, 19………………………</xhtml:p><xhtml:div>
  Signature: 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:p> Witness to the signature of ………………………………………………………………………….</xhtml:p><xhtml:div>
  Name:<xhtml:br/> Address: 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:div>
  &#160; 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:div>
  PURSUANT TO SECTION 9 OF THE LIMITED PARTNERSHIPS ACT 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:p><xhtml:br/> Notice is hereby given that under an arrangement entered into on the…………………………... day of…………………………, 19……….. , ………. of the firm carrying on business as <xhtml:br/> at has assigned his share as a limited partner in the above-named firm to ………………………….. <xhtml:br/> Dated this ………………………………….day of ………………………………., 20…………………..</xhtml:p><xhtml:div>
  Signature: 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:div>
  Witness to the signature of …………………………………………………………………………………….<xhtml:br/><xhtml:div>
   Name:<xhtml:br/> Address: 
 </xhtml:div></xhtml:div></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12155"><num>1</num><heading>SECTION 1 Short title.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>1. </xhtml:b>This Act may be cited as the Limited Partnerships Act.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12156"><num>2</num><heading>SECTION 2 Interpretation.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>2. </xhtml:b>In this Act, except where inconsistent with the context - 
<xhtml:p>"court" means the High Court; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"firm", "firm-name" and "business" have the same meanings as in the Partnership Act; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"general partner" means any partner who is not a limited partner as defined by this Act; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"registrar of companies" means the officer appointed for the registration of companies under the Companies Act. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12157"><num>3</num><heading>SECTION 3 Definition and constitution.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>3. </xhtml:b>(1) Limited partnerships may be formed in the manner and subject to the conditions provided by this Act. 
<xhtml:p>(2) A limited partnership shall not consist in any case of more than twenty persons, and must consist of one or more persons called general partners, who shall be liable for all debts and obligations of the firm, and one or more persons to be called limited partners, who shall at the time of entering into the partnership contribute thereto a sum or sums as capital or property valued at a stated amount, and who shall not be liable for the debts or obligations of the firm beyond the amount so contributed. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) A limited partner shall not, during the continuance of the partnership, either directly or indirectly draw out or receive back any part of his contribution, and if he does so draw out or receive back any such part, shall be liable for the debts and obligations of the firm up to the amount so drawn out or received back. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) A body corporate may be a limited partner. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12158"><num>4</num><heading>SECTION 4 Registration required.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>4. </xhtml:b>Every limited partnership must be registered as such in accordance with the provisions of this Act and of any rules thereunder, or in default thereof it shall be deemed to be a general partnership, and every limited partner shall be deemed to be a general partner.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12159"><num>5</num><heading>SECTION 5 Modifications of general law.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>5. </xhtml:b>(1) A limited partner shall not take part in the management of the partnership business, and shall not have power to bind the firm, but he may by himself or his agent at any time inspect the books of the firm and examine into the state and prospects of the partnership business, and may advise with the partners thereon; and if a limited partner takes part in the management of the partnership business he shall be liable for all debts and obligations of the firm incurred while he so takes part in the management as though he were a general partner. 
<xhtml:p>(2) A limited partnership shall not unless specifically provided in the partnership agreement be dissolved by the death or bankruptcy of a limited partner, and the lunacy of a limited partner shall not be a ground for dissolution of the partnership by the court unless the lunatic's share cannot be otherwise ascertained and realized. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) In the event of the dissolution of a limited partnership, its affairs shall be wound up by the general partners unless the court otherwise orders. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) Subject to any agreement expressed or implied between the partners - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) any difference arising as to ordinary matters connected with the partnership business may be decided by a majority of the general partners; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) a limited partner may, with the consent of the general partners, assign his share in the partnership, and upon such an assignment the assignee shall become a limited partner with all the rights of the assignor; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) the other partners shall not be entitled to dissolve the partnership by reason of any limited partner suffering his share to be charged for his separate debt; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(d) a person may be introduced as a partner without the consent of the existing limited partners;<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(e) a limited partner shall not be entitled to dissolve the partnership by notice. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12160"><num>6</num><heading>SECTION 6 Law as to private partnership to apply subject to this Act.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>6. </xhtml:b>Subject to the provisions of this Act, the Partnership Act, and rules of equity and of common law applicable to partnerships, except so far as they are inconsistent with the express provisions of the last-mentioned Act, shall apply to limited partnerships.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12161"><num>7</num><heading>SECTION 7 Manner and particulars of registration.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>7. </xhtml:b>The registration of a limited partnership shall be effected by sending by registered post or delivering to the registrar of companies a statement signed by the partners containing the following particulars - 
<xhtml:p>(a) the firm name; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) the general nature of the business; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) the principal place of business; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(d) the full name of each of the partners; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(e) the term, if any, for which the partnership is entered into, and the date of its commencement; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(f) a statement that the partnership is limited, and the description of every limited partner as such; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(g) the sum contributed by each limited partner, and whether paid in cash or how otherwise. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12162"><num>8</num><heading>SECTION 8 Registration of changes in partnerships.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>8. </xhtml:b>(1) If during the continuance of a limited partnership any change is made or occurs in - 
<xhtml:p>(a) the firm name; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) the general nature of the business; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) the principal place of business; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(d) the partners or the name of any partner; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(e) the term or character of the partnership; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(f) the sum contributed by any limited partner; or </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(g) the liability of any partner by reason of his becoming a limited instead of a general partner or a general instead of a limited partner, </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>a statement, signed by the firm, specifying the nature of the change shall within seven days be sent by post or delivered to the registrar of companies. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) If default is made in compliance with the requirements of this section, each of the general partners shall be guilty of an offence and liable to a fine not exceeding twenty shillings for each day during which the default continues. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12163"><num>9</num><heading>SECTION 9 Notice of general partner becoming a limited partner or of assignment of share of limited partner to be advertised.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>9. </xhtml:b>Notice of any arrangement or transaction under which any person will cease to be a general partner in any firm, and will become a limited partner in that firm, or under which the share of a limited partner in a firm will be assigned to any person, shall be forthwith advertised in the Gazette, and until notice of the arrangement or transaction is so advertised the arrangement or transaction shall, for the purposes of this Act, be deemed to be of no effect.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12164"><num>10</num><heading>SECTION 10 Ad valorem stamp duty on contributions by limited partners.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>10. </xhtml:b>The statement of the amount contributed by a limited partner, and a statement of any increase in that amount, sent to the registrar of companies for registration under this Act, shall be charged with an<xhtml:i> ad valorem </xhtml:i>stamp duty of five shillings for every two thousand shillings, and for any fraction of two thousand shillings over any multiple of two thousand shillings, of the amount so contributed, or of the increase of that amount, as the case may be; and, in default of payment of stamp duty thereon as herein required, the duty with interest thereon at the rate of eight per centum per annum from the date of delivery of the statement shall be a joint and several debt to the Government, recoverable from the partners, or any of them, named in the statements, or, in the case of an increase, from all or any of those partners whose discontinuance in the firm has not, before the date of delivery of the statement of increase, been duly notified to the registrar of companies.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12165"><num>11</num><heading>SECTION 11 Making false returns to be an offence.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>11. </xhtml:b>Any person who makes, signs, sends or delivers for the purpose of registration under this Act any false statement known by him to be false, is guilty of an offence and liable to imprisonment for a term not exceeding two years.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12166"><num>12</num><heading>SECTION 12 Registrar to file statement and issue certificate of registration.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>12. </xhtml:b>On receiving any statement made in pursuance of this Act, the registrar of companies shall cause it to be filed, and he shall send by registered post to the firm from whom the statement has been received a certificate of the registration thereof. 
<xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12167"><num>13</num><heading>SECTION 13 Register and index to be kept.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>13. </xhtml:b>The registrar of companies shall keep at his office, in proper books to be provided for the purpose, a register and an index of all the limited partnerships registered under this Act, and of all the statements registered in relation to those partnerships.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12168"><num>14</num><heading>SECTION 14 Inspection of statements registered.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>14. </xhtml:b>(1) Any person may inspect the statements filed by the registrar of companies, and there shall be paid for each inspection such fees as may be prescribed by the Minister, not exceeding five shillings for each inspection; and any person may require a certificate of the registration of a limited partnership, or a copy of extract from any registered statement, to be certified by the registrar of companies, and there shall be paid for a certificate of registration, certified copy, or extract such fees as the Minister may prescribe, not exceeding five shillings for the certificate of registration, and not exceeding fifty cents for each folio of one hundred words. 
<xhtml:p>(2) A certificate of registration, or a copy of or extract from any statement registered under this Act, if duly certified to be a true copy under the hand of the registrar of companies (whom it shall not be necessary to prove to be the registrar of companies), shall, in all legal proceedings, civil or criminal, and in all cases whatsoever, be received in evidence. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12169"><num>15</num><heading>SECTION 15 Rules.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>15. </xhtml:b>The Minister may make rules concerning any of the following matters - 
<xhtml:p>(a) the fees to be paid to the registrar of companies under this Act, so that they do not exceed in the case of the original registration of a limited partnership the sum of forty shillings, and in any other case the sum of five shillings; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) the duties or additional duties to be performed by the registrar of companies for the purposes of this Act; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) the performance by deputy registrars of companies and other officers of acts by this Act required to be done by the registrar of companies; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(d) the forms to be used for the purposes of this Act; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(e) generally the conduct and regulation of registration under this Act and any matters incidental thereto. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section></body><outOfLines><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-24354" id="w364aab1b9b1" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"/></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12155" id="w364aab1b9b3" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Short title.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12156" id="w364aab1b9b5" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Interpretation. Cap.29. Cap.486.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12157" id="w364aab1b9b7" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Definition and constitution.  
<xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12158" id="w364aab1b9b9" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Registration required.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12159" id="w364aab1b9c11" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Modifications of general law.  
<xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12160" id="w364aab1b9c13" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Law as to private partnership to apply subject to this Act. Cap.29.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12161" id="w364aab1b9c15" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Manner and particulars of registration.  
<xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12162" id="w364aab1b9c17" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Registration of changes in partnerships.  
<xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12163" id="w364aab1b9c19" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Notice of general partner becoming a limited partner or of assignment of share of limited partner to be advertised.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12164" id="w364aab1b9c21" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:i>Ad valorem</xhtml:i> stamp duty on contributions by limited partners.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12165" id="w364aab1b9c23" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Making false returns to be an offence.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12166" id="w364aab1b9c25" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Registrar to file statement and issue certificate of registration.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12167" id="w364aab1b9c27" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Register and index to be kept.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12168" id="w364aab1b9c29" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Inspection of statements registered. L.N. 300/1956, L.N. 173/1960.  
<xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12169" id="w364aab1b9c31" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Rules. L.N. 300/1956, L.N. 173/1960</xhtml:p><xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine></outOfLines></act></akomaNtoso>