<akomaNtoso xmlns:an="http://www.akomantoso.org/1.0"><act contains="singleVersion"><meta><identification source="#kenyalaw"><FRBRWork><FRBRthis value="/ke/act/1930-06-13/28/main"/><FRBRuri value="/ke/act/1930-06-13/28"/><FRBRdate date="1930-06-13" name="Generation"/><FRBRauthor as="#author" href="#parliament"/><components><component href="#emain" id="wmain" name="main" showAs="Main Document"/></components></FRBRWork><FRBRExpression><FRBRthis value="/ke/act/1930-06-13/28/eng@/main"/><FRBRuri value="/ke/act/1930-06-13/28/eng@"/><FRBRdate date="1930-06-13" name="Generation"/><FRBRauthor as="#author" href="#parliament"/><components><component href="#mmain" id="emain" name="main" showAs="Main Document"/></components></FRBRExpression><FRBRManifestation><FRBRthis value="/ke/act/1930-06-13/28/eng@/main.xml"/><FRBRuri value="/ke/act/1930-06-13/28/eng@/.akn"/><FRBRdate date="1930-06-13" name="Generation"/><FRBRauthor as="#author" href="#parliament"/><components><component href="#mmain" id="mmain" name="main" showAs="Main Document"/></components></FRBRManifestation></identification><publication date="1930-06-13" name="" showAs=""/><lifecycle source="#bungeni"><event date="1930-06-13" id="e1" source="#ro1" type="generation"/></lifecycle><references source="#kenyalaw"><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActTitle" id="TheActTitle" showAs="Act Title"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActLongTitle" id="TheActLongTitle" showAs="Act Description"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/AssentDate" id="AssentDate" showAs="Assent Date"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/CommencementDate" id="CommencementDate" showAs="Commencement Date"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActNumber" id="TheActNumber" showAs="Act Number"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActID" id="TheActID" showAs="Act ID"/><TLCConcept href="http://bungeni-lexmigrate.googlecode.com" id="bungeni" showAs="Lex Migrator"/><TLCConcept href="http://kenyalaw.org" id="kenyalaw" showAs="Kenya Law"/></references><proprietary xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" source="#kenyalaw"><kl:meta name="gokcatid" num="4"/><kl:meta name="gokcatname">Civil Law and Procedure</kl:meta><kl:meta name="lexyy" num="1930"/><kl:meta name="lexmm" num="6"/><kl:meta name="lexdd" num="13"/></proprietary></meta><preface><block name="preface"><docTitle id="ActTitle" refersTo="#TheActTitle">Chattels Transfer</docTitle><docTitle id="ActLongTitle" refersTo="#TheActLongTitle">An Act of Parliament to make provision relating to chattel securities and the transfer of chattels</docTitle><docDate date="1930-06-13" refersTo="#CommencementDate">Jun 13, 1930</docDate><docDate date="1111-11-11" refersTo="#AssentDate">Nov 11, 1111</docDate><docNumber id="ActNumber" refersTo="#TheActNumber">28</docNumber><docNumber id="ActIdentifier" refersTo="#TheActID">30</docNumber></block></preface><preamble><p>ARRANGEMENT OF SECTIONS</p><toc><tocItem href="#part-799" level="0">I PRELIMINARY</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12219" level="2">1 Short title.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12220" level="2">2 Interpretation.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12221" level="2">3 Attornment or agreement giving power of distress by way of security to be instrument within meaning of Act.</tocItem><tocItem href="#part-800" level="0">II REGISTRATION</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12222" level="2">4 Registration of instrument to be notice.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12223" level="2">5 Mode of registration.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12224" level="2">6 Limitation of time for registration.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12225" level="2">7 Register book and index to be kept.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12226" level="2">8 Deleted</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12227" level="2">9 Time for registration may be extended, and mistakes in register corrected.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12228" level="2">10 Renewal of registration.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12229" level="2">11 Register book and instruments may be searched and viewed.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12230" level="2">12 Office copies may be had.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12231" level="2">13 Unregistered instruments to be void in certain cases.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12232" level="2">14 Instrument not registered within time limited not to affect bona fide purchaser for value without notice.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-21008" level="2">14A Fee on registration.</tocItem><tocItem href="#part-801" level="0">III PROVISIONS RELATING TO INSTRUMENTS GENERALLY</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12233" level="2">15 Instrument to be attested.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12234" level="2">16 Instrument to take effect from registration.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12235" level="2">17 Instrument to have inventory of chattels.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12236" level="2">18 Instrument void where grantor not owner of chattels.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12237" level="2">19 Instrument subject to defeasance, etc., void in certain cases.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12238" level="2">20 Saving.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12239" level="2">21 Saving of laws prescribing formalities as to execution of instruments or securing rights thereunder.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12240" level="2">22 Form of instrument by way of security.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12241" level="2">23 Where successive securities are given over same chattels.</tocItem><tocItem href="#part-802" level="0">IV PROVISIONS RELATING TO CERTAIN SPECIFIC INSTRUMENTS</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12242" level="2">24 How stock to be described.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12243" level="2">25 Stock to include increase of stock, etc.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12244" level="2">26 Instrument may comprise book debts.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12245" level="2">27 Assignments of moneys payable to suppliers of dairy produce.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12246" level="2">28 Security may be given over crops.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12247" level="2">29 Saving of rights of landlord or mortgagee.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12248" level="2">30 Security may be given over wool.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12249" level="2">31 Wool securities not affected by sale, etc., of sheep.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12250" level="2">32 Security may be given over wool of mortgaged sheep.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12251" level="2">33 Further provision as to security given over wool.</tocItem><tocItem href="#part-803" level="0">V ENTRY OF SATISFACTION</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12252" level="2">34 Memorandum of satisfaction may be filed.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12253" level="2">35 Effect of filing memorandum.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12254" level="2">36 Public Trustee may sign memorandum in certain cases.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12255" level="2">37 Court may order memorandum to be filed.</tocItem><tocItem href="#part-804" level="0">VI SALE OF CHATTELS AND GRANTOR&amp;apos;S INTEREST THEREIN</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12256" level="2">38 Sale together with land.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12257" level="2">39 Grantor&amp;apos;s interest in chattels may be sold in execution of judgment against him.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12258" level="2">40 Saving in respect of interpleader process.</tocItem><tocItem href="#part-805" level="0">VII IMPLIED COVENANTS, ETC</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12259" level="2">41 Covenants for title.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12260" level="2">42 Covenants, etc., implied in instruments.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12261" level="2">43 Meaning of abbreviated expressions.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12262" level="2">44 Covenants to be several as well as joint.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12263" level="2">45 Covenants to bind executors.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12264" level="2">46 Covenants may be negatived or varied.</tocItem><tocItem href="#part-806" level="0">VIII TRANSFERS OF INSTRUMENTS</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12265" level="2">47 Form of transfer of instrument.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12266" level="2">48 Registration of transfers.</tocItem><tocItem href="#part-807" level="0">IX OFFENCES AND PENALTY</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12267" level="2">49 Offences and penalty.</tocItem></toc></preamble><body><part id="part-799"><num>I</num><heading>PART I PRELIMINARY</heading><section id="section-12219"><num>1</num><heading>SECTION 1 Short title.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>1.</xhtml:b> This Act may be cited as the Chattels Transfer Act. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12220"><num>2</num><heading>SECTION 2 Interpretation.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>2.</xhtml:b> In this Act, except where the context otherwise requires - 
<xhtml:p>"chattels" means any movable property that can be completely transferred by delivery, and includes machinery, stock and the natural increase of stock as hereinafter mentioned, crops and wool, but does not include the following - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) title deeds, choses in action or negotiable instruments; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) shares and interests in the stock, funds or securities of any government or local authority; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) shares and interests in the capital or property of any company or other corporate body; or </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(d) debentures and interest coupons issued by any government, or local authority, or company, or other corporate body; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"crops" means coffee berries, tea leaves, sisal leaves, sugar cane, cotton, hemp, hop, wheat, maize, wattle, barley, oat and grass (whether for hay or for grain), and all cereal and root crops, fruit, and all other crops grown above or below the ground; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"executed" means signed by the grantor or his attorney; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"factory" or "workshop" means any premises on which any manual labour is exercised by way of trade or for purposes of gain in or about the making, altering, repairing, ornamenting, finishing or adapting for sale of any article or part of any article; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"grantee" means the party to an instrument to whom chattels therein referred to, or any interest therein, are thereby granted or assigned, or agreed so to be, and includes his executors, administrators and assigns, and in the case of a company or corporation includes the successors and assigns of that company or corporation;<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>"grantor" means the party to an instrument who thereby grants or assigns, or agrees to grant or assign, chattels therein referred to, or any interest therein, and includes his executors, administrators and assigns, and in the case of a company or corporation includes the successors and assigns of that company or corporation;<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>"instrument" means any instrument given to secure the payment of money or the performance of some obligation and includes any bill of sale, mortgage, lien or any other document that transfers or purports to transfer the property in or right to the possession of chattels, whether permanently or temporarily, whether absolutely or conditionally, and whether by way of sale, security, pledge, gift, settlement or lease, and also the following - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) inventories of chattels with receipt thereto attached; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) receipts for purchase-money of chattels; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) other assurances of chattels; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(d) declarations of trust without transfer; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(e) powers of attorney, authorities or licences to take possession of chattels as security for any debt; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(f) any agreement, whether intended to be followed by the execution of any other instrument or not, by which a right in equity to any chattels, or to any charge or security thereon or thereover, is conferred; but does not include the following - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) securities over, or leases of, fixtures (except trade machinery as hereinafter defined, when mortgaged or charged apart from the land to which it is attached) when mortgaged, charged or leased in any mortgage, charge or lease of any freehold or leasehold interest in any land or building to which they are affixed, and whether or not those fixtures are specifically included in the mortgage, charge or lease by mention thereof in separate words; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) assignments for the benefit of the creditors of the person making them; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) transfers of or agreements to transfer instruments by way of security; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(d) transfers or assignments of any ship or vessel or any share thereof; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(e) transfers of chattels in the ordinary course of business of any trade or calling; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(f) debentures and interest coupons issued by any government or local authority; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(g) bills of sale of chattels in any foreign parts, or at sea; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(h) bills of lading, warehouse-keepers' certificates, warrants or orders for the delivery of chattels, entries in auctioneers' books or any other document used in the ordinary course of business as proof of the possession or control of chattels, or authorizing or purporting to authorize, either by endorsement or delivery, the possessor of the document to transfer or receive the chattels thereby represented; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(i) debentures and interest coupons issued by any company or other corporate body and secured upon the capital stock or chattels of that company or other corporate body; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(j) mortgages or charges granted or created by a company incorporated or registered under the Companies Act or by a co-operative society registered under the Co-operative Societies Act; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(k) hire-purchase agreements; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"Registrar" means the Registrar-General; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"registration" means the filing of an instrument with schedule or inventories, or a true copy thereof, with the affidavit hereinafter mentioned; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"schedule" includes inventory; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"stock" includes any sheep, cattle, horses, pigs, poultry and any other living animals; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"trade machinery" means the machinery used in or attached to any factory or workshop as defined in this section and machinery and plant used in connexion with the production, preparation or manufacture of agricultural products, but does not include - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) the fixed motive powers, such as the waterwheels and steam and other engines and the steam boilers, donkey engines and, other fixed appurtenances of those motive powers; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) the fixed power machinery (such as the shafts, wheels, drums and their fixed appurtenances) for transmitting the action of the motive powers to the other machinery, fixed and loose; or </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) the pipes for steam, gas and water. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12221"><num>3</num><heading>SECTION 3 Attornment or agreement giving power of distress by way of security to be instrument within meaning of Act.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>3.</xhtml:b> An attornment or agreement (not being a mining lease) whereby a power of distress is given or agreed to be given by one person to another by way of security for any present, future or contingent debt or advance, and whereby any rent is reserved or made payable as a means of providing for the payment of interest on the debt or advance, or otherwise for the purpose of the security only, shall be deemed to be an instrument within the meaning of this Act so far as regards any chattels seized or taken under the power of distress: 
<xhtml:p>Provided that where a mortgagee of any interest in land, after entering (under the powers contained or implied in the mortgage) into possession of the mortgaged land, or into receipt of rents and profits thereof, demises that land or any part thereof to the mortgagor at a fair and reasonable rent, the instrument whereby the demise is effected shall not be deemed to be an instrument within the meaning of this Act. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section></part><part id="part-800"><num>II</num><heading>PART II REGISTRATION</heading><section id="section-12222"><num>4</num><heading>SECTION 4 Registration of instrument to be notice.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>4. </xhtml:b>All persons shall be deemed to have notice of an instrument and of the contents thereof when that instrument has been registered as provided by this Act : </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Provided that if registration of the instrument is not renewed pursuant to the provisions of this Act, prior registration shall not be deemed to operate as notice after the lapse of the period within which renewal is required by this Act. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12223"><num>5</num><heading>SECTION 5 Mode of registration.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>5.</xhtml:b> Registration of an instrument shall be effected by filing it and all schedules endorsed thereon, annexed thereto or referred to therein, or a true copy of the instrument and the schedules, and an affidavit in Form 1 in the First Schedule or to the same effect, in the office of the Registrar.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12224"><num>6</num><heading>SECTION 6 Limitation of time for registration.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>6.</xhtml:b> (1) The period within which an instrument may be registered is twenty-one days from the day on which it was executed: 
<xhtml:p>Provided that when the time for registering an instrument expires on a day whereon the Registrar's office is closed, the registration shall be valid if made&#160;on the next following day on which the office is open. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) If there are more grantors than one, the date of execution of the instrument shall be deemed to be the date of the execution by the grantor who last executes the instrument. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) The day on which the instrument is executed shall not be included in the period for registration; but the instrument may be registered on that day. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12225"><num>7</num><heading>SECTION 7 Register book and index to be kept.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>7.</xhtml:b> (1) The Registrar shall cause every instrument registered in his office under this Act to be numbered, and shall mark on each such instrument, or on the filed copy thereof, the date of registration and the number, and shall at the time of registration enter in a register to be kept for the purpose in his office the particulars of the instrument registered according to Form 2 in the First Schedule. 
<xhtml:p>(2) The Registrar shall also keep an index of the names of grantors and grantees of instruments, and shall refer therein to the entries in the register book of the instruments given by each grantor. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) The index shall be arranged in divisions corresponding with the letters of the alphabet, so that all grantors and grantees whose surnames begin with the same letter (and no others) shall be comprised in one division, but the arrangement within each such division need not be strictly alphabetical. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) Where the instrument describes the residence of the person making or giving it to be in some place outside the province in which the registry is situated, or where the instrument describes the chattels enumerated therein as being in some place outside that province, the Registrar shall forthwith and within three clear days&#160;after registration in the&#160;registry, and in accordance with the prescribed directions, transmit an abstract in the prescribed form of the contents of the instrument to the Provincial Commissioner in whose province the places are situated, and if the places are in more provinces than one to each such Provincial Commissioner. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(5) Every abstract so transmitted shall be filed, kept and indexed by the Provincial Commissioner, and any person may search, inspect, make extracts from and obtain copies of the abstract so registered in the same manner and upon the same terms as to payment or otherwise as near as may be as in the case of instruments registered by the Registrar. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12226"><num>8</num><heading>SECTION 8 Deleted</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>8.</xhtml:b> (Deleted by A 7 of 2007)<xhtml:br/></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12227"><num>9</num><heading>SECTION 9 Time for registration may be extended, and mistakes in register corrected.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>9.</xhtml:b> The High Court, on being satisfied that the omission to register an instrument or an affidavit of renewal thereof within the time prescribed by this Act, or according to the form or effect required by this Act, or that the omission or misstatement in the register or in any affidavit of the name, residence or occupation of any person, or of any other matter, was accidental or due to inadvertence, may order the omission or misstatement to be rectified by extending the time for registration, or by the filing of a supplementary affidavit, or by the insertion in the register of the true name, residence or occupation, on such terms and conditions as it thinks fit.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12228"><num>10</num><heading>SECTION 10 Renewal of registration.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>10.</xhtml:b> (1) The registration of an instrument, whether executed before or after the commencement of this Act, shall, during the subsistence of the instrument, be renewed as provided in this section once in every period of five years, commencing from the day of the registration. 
<xhtml:p>(2) If not so renewed, the registration shall cease to be of any effect at the expiration of any period of five years during which a renewal has not been made as required under this section. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) The registration of an instrument shall be renewed by filing in the office of the Registrar an affidavit in Form 3 in the First Schedule or to the same effect. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) The Registrar shall thereupon number the affidavit as if it were an instrument presented for registration, and renumber the instrument originally registered or the filed copy thereof, with a similar number, and mark thereon the date of renewal of registration, and shall enter particulars of the instrument in the register book in the same manner as on an original registration, and shall, also enter the date of renewal of registration in the column provided therefor in the register book. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(5) (Deleted by 7 of 2007) </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(6) The provisions of subsections (4) and (5) of section 7 shall apply <xhtml:i>mutatis mutandis </xhtml:i>to the renewal of the registration of an instrument. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12229"><num>11</num><heading>SECTION 11 Register book and instruments may be searched and viewed.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>11.</xhtml:b> The register books and indices provided for, and every instrument registered, under this Part, or the filed copy thereof, may be searched and viewed by any person during the office hours of the Registrar upon payment of a fee of five shillings for every search against any one person.<xhtml:br/></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12230"><num>12</num><heading>SECTION 12 Office copies may be had.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>12. </xhtml:b>Any person shall be entitled to have an office copy or an extract of or from any instrument with the schedules filed therewith, or of or from the copy thereof registered under this Part and an office copy of any affidavit filed under this Act, on paying for it at the rate of one shilling for every folio of one hundred words contained in the copy or extract; or if he makes the copy or extract himself the Registrar shall, upon satisfying himself that the copy or extract is correctly made, certify it upon payment of a fee of ten shillings for each instrument or extract therefrom, and of fifty cents for every folio of one hundred words after the first ten folios.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12231"><num>13</num><heading>SECTION 13 Unregistered instruments to be void in certain cases.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>13. </xhtml:b>(1) Every instrument, unless registered in the manner provided under this Part, shall, upon the expiration of the time for registration or, if the time for registration is extended by the High Court, upon the expiration of the extended time, be deemed fraudulent and void as against - 
<xhtml:p>(a) the official receiver or trustee in bankruptcy of the estate of the person whose chattels or any of them are comprised in the instrument; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) the assignee or trustee acting under any assignment for the benefit of the creditors of that person; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) any person seizing the chattels or any part thereof comprised in the instrument, in execution of the process of any court authorizing the seizure of the chattels of the person by whom or concerning whose chattels the instrument was made, and against every person on whose behalf the process was issued, so far as regards the property in or right to the possession of any chattels comprised in or affected by the instrument which, at or after the time of bankruptcy, or of the execution by the grantor of the assignment for the benefit of his creditors, or of the execution of process (as the case may be), and after the expiration of the period within which the instrument is required to be registered, are in the possession or apparent possession of the person making or giving the instrument, or of any person against whom the process was issued under or in the execution of which the instrument was made or given, as the case may be. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) So long as an instrument continues to be registered hereunder, the chattels comprised in that instrument shall not be deemed to be in the possession, order or disposition of the grantor, within the meaning of the Bankruptcy Act. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12232"><num>14</num><heading>SECTION 14 Instrument not registered within time limited not to affect bona fide purchaser for value without notice.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>14.</xhtml:b> No unregistered instrument comprising any chattels whatsoever shall, without express notice, be valid and effectual as against any bona fide purchaser or mortgagee for valuable consideration, or as against any person bona fide selling or dealing with those chattels as auctioneer or dealer or agent in the ordinary course of his business.<xhtml:br/></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-21008"><num>14A</num><heading>SECTION 14A Fee on registration.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">14A. There shall be paid to the Registrar, upon the registration or renewal of registration of every instrument under this Act, such fees as the Minister may prescribe through regulations.  <xhtml:br/></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section></part><part id="part-801"><num>III</num><heading>PART III PROVISIONS RELATING TO INSTRUMENTS GENERALLY</heading><section id="section-12233"><num>15</num><heading>SECTION 15 Instrument to be attested.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>15. </xhtml:b>Sealing shall not be essential to the validity of an instrument; but execution of an instrument shall be attested by at least one witness, who shall add to his signature his residence and occupation. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12234"><num>16</num><heading>SECTION 16 Instrument to take effect from registration.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>16.</xhtml:b> An instrument shall be deemed to be made on the day on which it is executed, and shall take effect from the time of its registration.<xhtml:br/></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12235"><num>17</num><heading>SECTION 17 Instrument to have inventory of chattels.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>17.</xhtml:b> An instrument shall contain or shall have endorsed thereon or annexed thereto a schedule of the chattels comprised therein, and, save as is otherwise expressly provided by this Act, shall give a good title only to the chattels described in that schedule, and shall be void as against the persons mentioned in sections 13 and 14 in respect of any chattels not so described.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12236"><num>18</num><heading>SECTION 18 Instrument void where grantor not owner of chattels.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>18.</xhtml:b> Save as is otherwise expressly provided by this Act, an instrument shall be void as against the persons mentioned in sections 13 and 14 in respect of any chattels which the grantor acquires or becomes entitled to after the time of the execution of the instrument.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12237"><num>19</num><heading>SECTION 19 Instrument subject to defeasance, etc., void in certain cases.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>19.</xhtml:b> (1) If an instrument is made or given subject to any defeasance, condition or declaration of trust not contained in the body thereof, that defeasance, condition or declaration of trust shall for the purposes of this Act be taken as part of the instrument, and shall be written on the same paper or parchment on which the instrument is written, otherwise the instrument shall be void as against the persons mentioned in sections 13 and 14 so far as regards the property in or right to the possession of any chattels comprised in or affected by the instrument. 
<xhtml:p>(2) In the case of a document securing the payment of the moneys or of any part thereof payable by virtue of an instrument, it shall not be necessary for the purposes of this section to write that document on the same paper or parchment so long as the date, the names of the parties thereto and the nature of the security are set out in the instrument or in some schedule thereto. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12238"><num>20</num><heading>SECTION 20 Saving.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>20.</xhtml:b> Nothing in sections 17, 18 and 19 shall render an instrument void in respect of any of the following chattels - 
<xhtml:p>(a) stock, wool and crops; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) fixtures, plant or trade machinery where they are used in, attached to or brought upon any place in substitution for any things of the same nature described in, or on the schedule to, the instrument. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12239"><num>21</num><heading>SECTION 21 Saving of laws prescribing formalities as to execution of instruments or securing rights thereunder.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>21.</xhtml:b> Nothing in this Act shall be deemed to affect any law for the time being in force - 
<xhtml:p>(a) prescribing any formalities to be observed on or about the execution of instruments within the meaning of this Act; or </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) conferring or securing any rights or claims under or in respect of any such instrument. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12240"><num>22</num><heading>SECTION 22 Form of instrument by way of security.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>22.</xhtml:b> (1) An instrument under this Act may be in Form 4 in the First Schedule or to the same effect with such variations or modifications thereof and additions thereto as are expressed in the instrument. 
<xhtml:p>(2) An instrument securing an account current continues in full force and effect notwithstanding that the grantor may from time to time be in credit on that account. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12241"><num>23</num><heading>SECTION 23 Where successive securities are given over same chattels.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>23.</xhtml:b> Where an instrument is executed after the execution of a prior instrument which has never been registered, and comprises all or any of the chattels comprised in the prior instrument, then if the subsequent instrument is given as a security for the same debt as is secured by the prior instrument, or for any part of that debt, it shall, to the extent to which it is a security for the same debt or part thereof, and so far as respects the chattels comprised in the prior instrument be void as against the persons mentioned in sections 13 and 14, unless it is proved to the court hearing the case that the subsequent instrument was bona fide given for the purpose of correcting some material error in the prior instrument, and not for the purpose of evading this Act.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section></part><part id="part-802"><num>IV</num><heading>PART IV PROVISIONS RELATING TO CERTAIN SPECIFIC INSTRUMENTS</heading><section id="section-12242"><num>24</num><heading>SECTION 24 How stock to be described.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>24.</xhtml:b> Where stock are comprised in an instrument, they shall be described or referred to therein or in the schedule thereto by some brand or brands, earmark or earmarks, or other mark or marks upon them or shall be so described or referred to by sex, age, name, colour or other mode of description as to be reasonably capable of identification, otherwise the instrument shall be void as against the persons mentioned in sections 13 and 14, so far as regards such or so much of such stock as are not so described or referred to or are not reasonably capable of identification; and the land or premises on which the stock are or are intended to be depastured or kept shall be described or mentioned in the instrument or schedule. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12243"><num>25</num><heading>SECTION 25 Stock to include increase of stock, etc.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>25.</xhtml:b> (1) An instrument comprising stock shall, unless the contrary be expressed therein, be deemed to include not only the stock comprised therein as provided by section 24, but also the natural increase of that stock, and all stock of the class or classes described in the instrument, the property of the grantor, branded, earmarked, or marked as specified in the instrument, or which the grantor has covenanted or agreed by the instrument to so brand, earmark or mark, and which after the execution of the instrument are depasturing or are at, in, or upon any lands or premises mentioned therein or in the schedule thereto, or any land and premises used and worked as part of the first-mentioned land and premises, whether or not the stock be removed therefrom. 
<xhtml:p>(2) The grantee shall have the same legal property and right in all stock which by virtue of subsection (1) are deemed to be included in the instrument as he has in the stock described in the instrument or in the schedule thereto. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12244"><num>26</num><heading>SECTION 26 Instrument may comprise book debts.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>26.</xhtml:b>(1) Book or other debts shall be deemed to be chattels situated in the place where the grantor of the instrument comprising them longest resided or carried on business during the period of six months immediately before the execution of the instrument. 
<xhtml:p>(2) In every instrument comprising book or other debts each debt shall be deemed to be a separate chattel, and shall be described in the schedule thereto by setting forth the name of the debtor or firm of debtors and the amount of the debt, so far as is reasonably necessary to show by whom the debts are owing, and every such instrument shall be void as against the persons mentioned in sections 13 and 14 in respect of any debt not so described. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) Nothing in this section shall apply to any debt secured or charged on land. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) Nothing in this section shall apply to any floating security granted by a company registered under the Companies Act, over the assets of that company, where the security is registered in the manner required by that Act. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12245"><num>27</num><heading>SECTION 27 Assignments of moneys payable to suppliers of dairy produce.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>27. </xhtml:b>Nothing in section 26 shall apply to any deed or agreement in writing purporting to assign to or to authorize the grantee to receive any moneys due at the date thereof or thereafter from time to time to become due to the grantor for or in respect of any milk, cream or butterfat supplied by the grantor to any butter, cheese or other factory for the manufacture of dairy products; and such a deed or agreement is not an instrument to which this Act applies.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12246"><num>28</num><heading>SECTION 28 Security may be given over crops.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>28.</xhtml:b> An instrument may be granted over the crops described or referred to therein or in the schedule thereto then actually sown or growing or planted or to be sown or grown or planted in or upon the lands mentioned in the instrument, and shall entitle the grantee thereof to the whole of the crops therein mentioned, not only while growing but afterwards when cut or separated from the soil, and whether stacked or stored on the land where they were grown or on any other land or premises, or whether the nature of the crop has been altered by a process of curing or manufacture.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12247"><num>29</num><heading>SECTION 29 Saving of rights of landlord or mortgagee.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>29.</xhtml:b> No instrument referred to in section 28 shall prejudicially affect the rights of any landlord or mortgagee of any land whereon the crops are growing, unless and so far as the landlord or mortgagee has consented in writing to the instrument: 
<xhtml:p>Provided that no such instrument being duly registered shall be extinguished or prejudicially affected by any subsequent sale, lease, mortgage or other encumbrance of or upon the land described or referred to in the instrument or in any schedule thereto. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12248"><num>30</num><heading>SECTION 30 Security may be given over wool.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>30.</xhtml:b> An instrument may be granted over the wool of the next ensuing clip to be shorn from the sheep described or referred to therein, or in the schedule thereto, then depasturing upon the lands mentioned therein or in the schedule, and shall entitle the grantee thereof to the wool of those sheep, not only while growing but afterwards when shorn from the sheep, and wherever that wool may be.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12249"><num>31</num><heading>SECTION 31 Wool securities not affected by sale, etc., of sheep.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>31.</xhtml:b> No subsequent sale, mortgage or other encumbrance of or affecting the sheep mentioned in an instrument referred to in section 30 shall extinguish, suspend, impair or prejudicially affect that instrument if duly registered, or the rights of the grantee thereof to the wool specified or referred to therein.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12250"><num>32</num><heading>SECTION 32 Security may be given over wool of mortgaged sheep.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>32.</xhtml:b> The grantor of any instrument over sheep may, with the consent in writing of the grantee thereof, and so far as is authorized by that consent, but not otherwise, give to some third person a valid security on the next ensuing clip of the wool of those sheep.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12251"><num>33</num><heading>SECTION 33 Further provision as to security given over wool.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>33. </xhtml:b>(1) If under any instrument comprising sheep, whether the instrument has been executed before or after the commencement of this Act; the grantee thereof shall from time to time be entitled to require the grantor to execute and give to the grantee an instrument over the wool growing, or to grow, upon the sheep for the time being subject to the instrument, or be entitled to require the grantor to deliver to the grantee the wool shorn from those sheep in each year during the continuance of the instrument, then the grantee shall, during the subsistence of the registration of the first-mentioned instrument, be deemed, notwithstanding the provisions of section 30, to possess a lien or security over each clip in the same degree and manner as if an instrument in respect of the wool had been actually executed by the grantor and registered under this Act, and that lien or security shall have the consequences mentioned in section 31. 
<xhtml:p>(2) In every instrument comprising sheep, executed after the commencement of this Act, there shall be implied (unless that implication is expressly negatived) a covenant by the grantor to deliver to the grantee the wool shorn from those sheep in each year during the continuance of the instrument. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section></part><part id="part-803"><num>V</num><heading>PART V ENTRY OF SATISFACTION</heading><section id="section-12252"><num>34</num><heading>SECTION 34 Memorandum of satisfaction may be filed.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>34.</xhtml:b> (1) In the case of an instrument, upon the production to the Registrar of a memorandum of satisfaction in Form 5 in the First Schedule or to the same effect, signed by the grantee thereof or his attorney, discharging the chattels comprised in the instrument or any specified part thereof from the moneys secured thereby or any specified part thereof, or from the performance of the obligation thereby secured or any specified part thereof, and on production of the instrument and payment of a fee of thirty shillings, the Registrar shall file the memorandum and make an entry thereof in the register book on the page where the instrument is registered. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) The execution of the memorandum shall be attested by at least one witness, who shall add to his signature his residence and occupation, and shall be verified by the affidavit of that witness. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) The Registrar may dispense with the production of the instrument on proof by affidavit to his satisfaction that the instrument has been destroyed or cannot be found or cannot be produced. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12253"><num>35</num><heading>SECTION 35 Effect of filing memorandum.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>35.</xhtml:b> From and after the filing of a memorandum of satisfaction the debt or charge created by the instrument shall be vacated to the extent specified in the memorandum, and the interest of the grantee of the chattels expressed to be discharged shall vest in the person for the time being entitled to the equity of redemption therein, but so far only as that interest is expressed by the memorandum to be determined, and subject to any lien or equity affecting the chattels.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12254"><num>36</num><heading>SECTION 36 Public Trustee may sign memorandum in certain cases.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>36.</xhtml:b> Where the grantee of an instrument by way of security is absent from Kenya, and there is no person in Kenya authorized to discharge it on his behalf at or after the date appointed for the payment of the moneys secured by the instrument, the Public Trustee may receive those moneys in trust for the person entitled thereto, and may sign a memorandum of satisfaction in lieu of that person, and upon the filing thereof that memorandum, signed by the Public Trustee, shall be as effectual as a memorandum signed by the person entitled to those moneys.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12255"><num>37</num><heading>SECTION 37 Court may order memorandum to be filed.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>37.</xhtml:b> The High Court may, upon application made for that purpose, order a memorandum of satisfaction to be filed in respect of any instrument if it appears that the debt (if any) for which the instrument was given as security has been satisfied or discharged, or that the obligation for securing the performance of which the instrument was given has been performed; and thereupon that order may be filed by the Registrar and entered in his book as if it were a memorandum within the meaning of section 34.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section></part><part id="part-804"><num>VI</num><heading>PART VI SALE OF CHATTELS AND GRANTOR&amp;apos;S INTEREST THEREIN</heading><section id="section-12256"><num>38</num><heading>SECTION 38 Sale together with land.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>38.</xhtml:b> Chattels under this Act or any part thereof may be sold along with or separately from land (if any) mortgaged to secure payment of the same moneys as are secured by any instrument under this Act. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12257"><num>39</num><heading>SECTION 39 Grantor&amp;apos;s interest in chattels may be sold in execution of judgment against him.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>39. </xhtml:b>(1) Where legal process issues against the chattels of a judgment-debtor for the execution of a judgment of any court, and those chattels, or any of them, are comprised in an instrument under this Act. the officer charged with the execution of the process may, in lieu of seizing and selling the chattels so comprised, sell the right, title and interest of the judgment-debtor therein. 
<xhtml:p>(2) The grantee of the instrument, on receiving notice of the purchase of that right, title and interest, may take possession of the chattels comprised in the instrument. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) A grantee so taking possession shall be deemed to hold the chattels in trust for the purchaser of the right, title and interest, subject to payment of all moneys due under the instrument. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) If the chattels are afterwards sold under the power of sale expressed or implied in the instrument, and any surplus remains out of the proceeds of the sale after payment of all moneys due under the instrument, the grantee shall on demand pay over that surplus to the purchaser of the right, title and interest. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(5) If the grantee makes default herein, the purchaser may bring an action against him to recover the surplus as money received to the use of the purchaser. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12258"><num>40</num><heading>SECTION 40 Saving in respect of interpleader process.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>40.</xhtml:b> Nothing is section 39 shall be deemed to affect the right of an execution creditor to test the validity of any instrument by interpleader process. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section></part><part id="part-805"><num>VII</num><heading>PART VII IMPLIED COVENANTS, ETC</heading><section id="section-12259"><num>41</num><heading>SECTION 41 Covenants for title.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>41.</xhtml:b> There shall be implied in every instrument the covenants for title on the part of the grantor set out in the Second Schedule and those implied covenants shall have the same effect as if they were respectively set out at length in the instrument. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12260"><num>42</num><heading>SECTION 42 Covenants, etc., implied in instruments.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>42.</xhtml:b> There shall be implied in every instrument the covenants, provisos, agreements and powers set out in the Third Schedule or such of them as are applicable; and those implied covenants, provisos, agreements and powers shall, subject to any modifications thereof expressed in the instrument, have the same effect as if they were respectively set out therein at length. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12261"><num>43</num><heading>SECTION 43 Meaning of abbreviated expressions.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>43.</xhtml:b> Such of the expressions defined in section 2 or in the Fourth Schedule as are used in any instrument, or in any of the covenants, provisos, agreements or powers implied therein by this Act, shall, unless the contrary is expressed in the instrument, or unless manifestly inconsistent with the context, have the meanings given to them in section 2 or the Fourth Schedule, and those meanings shall be implied in the instrument as fully and effectually as if they were set out therein. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12262"><num>44</num><heading>SECTION 44 Covenants to be several as well as joint.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>44.</xhtml:b> Where there are two or more grantors or two or more grantees of any instrument, then any covenants, conditions, provisos, agreements and powers expressed in the instrument, or implied therein by this Act, and imposing an obligation on the grantors or grantees, or ensuring for the benefit of the grantors or grantees, shall, except in so far as a contrary intention appears, be deemed to impose that obligation, or confer that benefit, as the case may be, severally as well as jointly. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12263"><num>45</num><heading>SECTION 45 Covenants to bind executors.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>45.</xhtml:b> Except in so far as the contrary intention appears, all covenants, conditions, provisos, agreements and powers expressed in any instrument, or implied therein by this Act, shall bind the executors, administrators and assigns of the person, or the successors and assigns of a company or corporation, upon whom the covenants, conditions, provisos, agreements and powers impose an obligation, and shall operate for the benefit of the executors, administrators and assigns of the person, or the successors and assigns of the company or corporation, for whose benefit they enure. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12264"><num>46</num><heading>SECTION 46 Covenants may be negatived or varied.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>46.</xhtml:b> All or any of the covenants, provisos, conditions, agreements or powers set out in the Second, Third and Fourth Schedules may be negatived, modified or altered, or others may be added to them, by express words in the instrument.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section></part><part id="part-806"><num>VIII</num><heading>PART VIII TRANSFERS OF INSTRUMENTS</heading><section id="section-12265"><num>47</num><heading>SECTION 47 Form of transfer of instrument.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>47.</xhtml:b> An instrument may be transferred by a document in the form in the Fifth Schedule or to the same effect, and every transferee, his executors, administrators and assigns shall, in respect of the instrument transferred, have the same rights, powers and remedies, and be subject to the same obligations, as the transferor. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12266"><num>48</num><heading>SECTION 48 Registration of transfers.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>48.</xhtml:b> Transfers of instruments may be registered at any time after the execution thereof in the same manner as instruments are registered; and, in case two or more transfers of any one instrument are executed, a registered transfer shall have priority over an unregistered transfer; and, in case two or more transfers of any one instrument are registered, priority shall be given to those transfers in the order of their time of registration.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section></part><part id="part-807"><num>IX</num><heading>PART IX OFFENCES AND PENALTY</heading><section id="section-12267"><num>49</num><heading>SECTION 49 Offences and penalty.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>49.</xhtml:b> A grantor of an instrument under this Act who, by sale or delivery without the consent of the grantee of any chattels comprised in or affected by the instrument, or by any other means, defrauds or attempts to defraud the grantee of the chattels or any part thereof, and thus or by any other means directly or indirectly defeats, invalidates or impairs the grantee's security over them or attempts so to do, and every person who wilfully aids and abets any person in defrauding or attempting to defraud the grantee by defeating, invalidating or impairing the instrument or in attempting to do so, shall be guilty of an offence and liable to six months' imprisonment or to a fine not exceeding two thousand shillings or to both such fine and imprisonment. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section></part></body><outOfLines><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12219" id="w340aab1b9b1" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Short title.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12220" id="w340aab1b9b3" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Interpretation. 10 of 1969, Sch. Cap. 486. Cap. 490.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12221" id="w340aab1b9b5" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Attornment or agreement giving power of distress by way of security to be instrument within meaning of Act.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12222" id="w340aab1b9b7" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Registration of instrument to be notice.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12223" id="w340aab1b9b9" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Mode of registration.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12224" id="w340aab1b9c11" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Limitation of time for registration.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12225" id="w340aab1b9c13" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Register book and index to be kept.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12226" id="w340aab1b9c15" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Deleted by 7 of 2007.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12227" id="w340aab1b9c17" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Time for registration may be extended, and mistakes in register corrected.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12228" id="w340aab1b9c19" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Renewal of registration. 36 of 1955, s. 2. A7 0f 2007.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12229" id="w340aab1b9c21" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Register book and instruments may be searched and viewed. 7 of 1975, Sch.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12230" id="w340aab1b9c23" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Office copies may be had.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12231" id="w340aab1b9c25" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Unregistered instruments to be void in certain cases.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12232" id="w340aab1b9c27" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Instrument not registered within time limited not to affect bona fide purchaser for value without notice.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-21008" id="w340aab1b9c29" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Fee on registration. A 7 of 2007.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12233" id="w340aab1b9c31" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Instrument to be attested.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12234" id="w340aab1b9c33" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Instrument to take effect from registration.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12235" id="w340aab1b9c35" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Instrument to have inventory of chattels.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12236" id="w340aab1b9c37" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Instrument void where grantor not owner of chattels.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12237" id="w340aab1b9c39" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Instrument subject to defeasance, etc., void in certain cases.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12238" id="w340aab1b9c41" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Saving.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12239" id="w340aab1b9c43" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Saving of laws prescribing formalities as to execution of instruments or securing rights thereunder.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12240" id="w340aab1b9c45" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Form of instrument by way of security.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12241" id="w340aab1b9c47" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Where successive securities are given over same chattels.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12242" id="w340aab1b9c49" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>How stock to be described.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12243" id="w340aab1b9c51" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Stock to include increase of stock, etc.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12244" id="w340aab1b9c53" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Instrument may comprise book debts. Cap. 486.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12245" id="w340aab1b9c55" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Assignments of moneys payable to suppliers of dairy produce.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12246" id="w340aab1b9c57" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Security may be given over crops.  
<xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12247" id="w340aab1b9c59" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Saving of rights of landlord or mortgagee.  
<xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12248" id="w340aab1b9c61" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Security may be given over wool.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12249" id="w340aab1b9c63" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Wool securities not affected by sale, etc., of sheep.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12250" id="w340aab1b9c65" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Security may be given over wool of mortgaged sheep.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12251" id="w340aab1b9c67" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Further provision as to security given over wool.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12252" id="w340aab1b9c69" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Memorandum of satisfaction may be filed.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12253" id="w340aab1b9c71" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Effect of filing memorandum.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12254" id="w340aab1b9c73" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Public Trustee may sign memorandum in certain cases.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12255" id="w340aab1b9c75" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Court may order memorandum to be filed.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12256" id="w340aab1b9c77" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Sale together with land.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12257" id="w340aab1b9c79" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Grantor's interest in chattels may be sold in execution of judgment against him.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12258" id="w340aab1b9c81" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Saving in respect of interpleader process.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12259" id="w340aab1b9c83" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Covenants for title.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12260" id="w340aab1b9c85" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Covenants, etc., implied in instruments.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12261" id="w340aab1b9c87" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Meaning of abbreviated expressions.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12262" id="w340aab1b9c89" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Covenants to be several as well as joint.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12263" id="w340aab1b9c91" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Covenants to bind executors.  
<xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12264" id="w340aab1b9c93" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Covenants may be negatived or varied.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12265" id="w340aab1b9c95" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Form of transfer of instrument.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12266" id="w340aab1b9c97" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Registration of transfers.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12267" id="w340aab1b9c99" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Offences and penalty.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine></outOfLines></act></akomaNtoso>