<akomaNtoso xmlns:an="http://www.akomantoso.org/1.0"><act contains="singleVersion"><meta><identification source="#kenyalaw"><FRBRWork><FRBRthis value="/ke/act/1959-06-16/143/main"/><FRBRuri value="/ke/act/1959-06-16/143"/><FRBRdate date="1959-06-16" name="Generation"/><FRBRauthor as="#author" href="#parliament"/><components><component href="#emain" id="wmain" name="main" showAs="Main Document"/></components></FRBRWork><FRBRExpression><FRBRthis value="/ke/act/1959-06-16/143/eng@/main"/><FRBRuri value="/ke/act/1959-06-16/143/eng@"/><FRBRdate date="1959-06-16" name="Generation"/><FRBRauthor as="#author" href="#parliament"/><components><component href="#mmain" id="emain" name="main" showAs="Main Document"/></components></FRBRExpression><FRBRManifestation><FRBRthis value="/ke/act/1959-06-16/143/eng@/main.xml"/><FRBRuri value="/ke/act/1959-06-16/143/eng@/.akn"/><FRBRdate date="1959-06-16" name="Generation"/><FRBRauthor as="#author" href="#parliament"/><components><component href="#mmain" id="mmain" name="main" showAs="Main Document"/></components></FRBRManifestation></identification><publication date="1959-06-16" name="" showAs=""/><lifecycle source="#bungeni"><event date="1959-06-16" id="e1" source="#ro1" type="generation"/></lifecycle><references source="#kenyalaw"><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActTitle" id="TheActTitle" showAs="Act Title"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActLongTitle" id="TheActLongTitle" showAs="Act Description"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/AssentDate" id="AssentDate" showAs="Assent Date"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/CommencementDate" id="CommencementDate" showAs="Commencement Date"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActNumber" id="TheActNumber" showAs="Act Number"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActID" id="TheActID" showAs="Act ID"/><TLCConcept href="http://bungeni-lexmigrate.googlecode.com" id="bungeni" showAs="Lex Migrator"/><TLCConcept href="http://kenyalaw.org" id="kenyalaw" showAs="Kenya Law"/></references><proprietary xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" source="#kenyalaw"><kl:meta name="gokcatid" num="13"/><kl:meta name="gokcatname">Children</kl:meta><kl:meta name="lexyy" num="1959"/><kl:meta name="lexmm" num="6"/><kl:meta name="lexdd" num="16"/></proprietary></meta><preface><block name="preface"><docTitle id="ActTitle" refersTo="#TheActTitle">Adoption (Repealed)</docTitle><docTitle id="ActLongTitle" refersTo="#TheActLongTitle">An Act of Parliament to make provision for the making and registration of adoption orders; to provide for the registration and control of adoption societies; to regulate the making of arrangements by adoption societies and other persons in connexion with the adoption of children; to restrict the making and receipt of payments in connexion with the adoption of children; and for connected purposes</docTitle><docDate date="1959-06-16" refersTo="#CommencementDate">Jun 16, 1959</docDate><docDate date="1111-11-11" refersTo="#AssentDate">Nov 11, 1111</docDate><docNumber id="ActNumber" refersTo="#TheActNumber">143</docNumber><docNumber id="ActIdentifier" refersTo="#TheActID">100</docNumber></block></preface><preamble><p>ARRANGEMENT OF SECTIONS</p><toc><tocItem href="#section-19061" level="2"> THE ADOPTION RULES</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-19062" level="2"> THE ADOPTION REGULATIONS</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11829" level="2">1 Short title.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11830" level="2">2 Interpretation.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11831" level="2">3 Power to make adoption orders.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11832" level="2">3A Jurisdiction of a Resident Magistrate&amp;apos;s Court.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11833" level="2">4 Restrictions on making adoption orders.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11834" level="2">5 Consent to adoption.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11835" level="2">6 Evidence of consent of parent or guardian.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11836" level="2">7 Functions of court as to adoption orders</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11837" level="2">7A Appointment of provisional guardian.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11838" level="2">7B Consent to future adoption.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11839" level="2">8 Interim orders.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11840" level="2">9 Adoption order in respect of infants previously adopted</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11841" level="2">10 Custody of infant when order refused.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11842" level="2">11 Appeal.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11843" level="2">12A Appointment of guardians</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11844" level="2">13 Adopted Children Register.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11845" level="2">14 Registration of adoptions.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11846" level="2">15 Amendment of orders and rectification of registers.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11847" level="2">16 Rights and duties of parents and capacity to marry.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11848" level="2">17 Workmen&amp;apos;s compensation.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11849" level="2">18 Orders and agreements respecting illegitimate children.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11850" level="2">19 Intestacies, wills and settlements.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11851" level="2">20 Provisions supplementary to section 19.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11852" level="2">21 Effect of overseas adoption.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11853" level="2">22 Restriction on making arrangements for adoption.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11854" level="2">23 Approval of adoption societies.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11855" level="2">24 Procedure.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11856" level="2">25 Functions of adoption societies.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11857" level="2">26 Arrangements by adoption societies for adoption</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11858" level="2">27 Inspection of books, etc., of adoption societies</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11859" level="2">28 Information to be confidential.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11860" level="2">29 Prohibition of certain payments.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11861" level="2">30 Restriction upon advertisements.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11862" level="2">31 Offences under Parts V and VI</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11863" level="2">32 Service of notices.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11864" level="2">33 Powers of local authorities.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11865" level="2">34 Expenses.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11866" level="2">35 Regulations.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11867" level="2">36 Exemption.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11868" level="2">37 Adoptions under previous law.</tocItem></toc></preamble><body><section id="section-19061"><num/><heading>SECTION  THE ADOPTION RULES</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:table width="100%"><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%">
    L.N.248/1972,<xhtml:br/>L.N.232/1978. Citation. 
  </xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="85%"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>SUBSIDIARY LEGISLATION</xhtml:b></xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>Rules under section 12</xhtml:b></xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>THE ADOPTION RULES</xhtml:b></xhtml:p><xhtml:p>1. These Rules may be cited as the Adoption Rules.</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%">
    Interpretation. 
   <xhtml:p><xhtml:br/></xhtml:p></xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="85%">
    2. In these Rules, unless the context otherwise requires - 
   <xhtml:p>"applicant" includes either, as well as both, of two joint applicants;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"registrar" means the Registrar of the High Court and includes a district and deputy registrar and, in a subordinate court, the executive officer.</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%"/><xhtml:td width="85%">
    3 - (<xhtml:i>Deleted by L.N.</xhtml:i>232/1978.) 
  </xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%">
    Commencement of proceedings.<xhtml:br/></xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="85%">
    4. (1) Proceedings for an adoption order shall be commenced by originating summons in Form 1 which shall, unless otherwise ordered by the court, be served on - 
   <xhtml:p>(a) all persons whose consent to the making of the order is required by section 4 (6) of the Act; and</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) any adoption society by whom arrangements for the adoption have been made.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) An appearance to the originating summons shall be entered within ten days of service thereof.</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%">
    Confidentiality<xhtml:br/>of identity. 
   <xhtml:p/></xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="85%">
    5. If any person proposing to apply for an adoption order desires that his identity shall be kept confidential, he may, before taking out an originating summons, apply to the registrar for a serial number to be assigned to him for the purposes of the proposed application and such a number shall be assigned to him accordingly. 
  </xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%">
    Application by adoption society. 
  </xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="85%">
    6. An adoption society may apply to the registrar for a serial number to be assigned to it for the purposes of a proposed application and the adoption society need not give the name of any applicant and such a number shall be assigned to it accordingly. 
  </xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%">
    Previous<xhtml:br/>proceedings.<xhtml:br/></xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="85%">
    7. If it appears that the applicant has previously made an application for an adoption order in respect of the same infant, the application shall not be proceeded with unless the court is satisfied that there has been a substantial change in the circumstances since the previous application. 
  </xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%">
    Evidence in<xhtml:br/>support of<xhtml:br/>application.<xhtml:br/></xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="85%">
    8. There shall be filed with the originating summons the following documents - 
   <xhtml:p><xhtml:i>(a)</xhtml:i>a statement in Form 2 which shall be verified by an affidavit in Form 3;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>(b)</xhtml:i>an affidavit of fitness of the proposed guardian<xhtml:i>ad litem</xhtml:i>which shall further show that the proposed guardian has no interest adverse to those of the infant; but no such affidavit shall be required if the proposed guardian is an adoption society;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>(c)</xhtml:i>the consent to act of the guardian<xhtml:i>ad litem</xhtml:i>;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>(d)</xhtml:i>the consent of any person to the making of an adoption order in Form 4;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>(e)</xhtml:i>any other affidavit or document required by the circumstances.</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%">
    Appointment<xhtml:br/>of guardian<xhtml:br/><xhtml:i>ad litem.</xhtml:i></xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="85%">
    8A. An application for appointment of a guardian<xhtml:i>ad litem</xhtml:i>shall be made<xhtml:i>ex parte</xhtml:i>before any further step in the proceedings is taken. 
  </xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%"><xhtml:p>Duties of<xhtml:br/>guardian<xhtml:br/><xhtml:i>ad litem.</xhtml:i></xhtml:p></xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="85%">
    9. It shall be the duty of the guardian<xhtml:i>ad litem</xhtml:i>to investigate as fully as possible all circumstances relevant to the proposed adoption with a view to safeguarding the interests of the infant, and to report to the court in writing in particular on the following matters - 
   <xhtml:p><xhtml:i>(a)</xhtml:i>whether the matters alleged in the applicant's statement are true;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>(b)</xhtml:i>in the case of an application by one only of two spouses - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(i) whether the other spouse consents to the application; and</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(ii) why he or she does not join in the application;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>(c)</xhtml:i>whether the means of the applicant enable him to maintain and bring up the infant suitably including by the provision of a proper education;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>(d)</xhtml:i>whether the applicant understands that an adoption order is irrevocable and that the order will make him responsible for the maintenance and upbringing of the infant;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>(e)</xhtml:i>who are the parents of the infant;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>(f)</xhtml:i>who is liable to contribute to the support of the infant;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>(g)</xhtml:i>whether the infant has any right to or interest in property;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>(h)</xhtml:i>whether the infant (if of an age to understand the effect of an adoption order, and knowing that he is not the child of the applicant) wishes the order to be made;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(i) whether he considers it desirable that any special terms or conditions be imposed in the adoption order;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(j) what relatives (if any) the infant has, whether they have been informed of the proposed adoption and whether any of them has offered and is able to provide a suitable home for the infant; and</xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>(k)</xhtml:i>whether the proposed adoption will be in the best interests of the infant,</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>and the guardian<xhtml:i>ad litem</xhtml:i>shall attach to his report a certified copy of the infant's birth certificate, or if the infant has been previously adopted, a certified copy of the relevant entry in the Adopted Children Register.</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%">
    Confidentiality<xhtml:br/>of information. 
  </xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="85%">
    10. (1) The guardian<xhtml:i>ad litem</xhtml:i>and, where a body of persons is appointed guardian<xhtml:i>ad litem</xhtml:i>, any officer or agent of that body shall regard all information obtained in the investigation or otherwise in relation to the matter as confidential, and shall not divulge any part of it to any person save as may be necessary for the proper execution of his duty. 
   <xhtml:p>(2) The report referred to in rule 9 shall be made by the guardian<xhtml:i>ad litem</xhtml:i>or its officer or agent personally and m his own words and unless the court otherwise directs, shall not be disclosed to any person other than the applicant or his advocate or the adoption society (if any) acting on behalf of the applicant.</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%">
    Custody<xhtml:br/>pending<xhtml:br/>disposal.<xhtml:br/></xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="85%">
    10A. An application for custody of the infant pending disposal of the application for adoption under section 5 (5) of the Act shall be by summons in Form 4A and shall be supported by an affidavit in Form 4s both of which shall be served on - 
   <xhtml:p>(a) all persons whose consent to the making of the order is required by section 4 (6) of the Act and whose consent has neither been given in Form 4 or Form 7 nor been dispensed with under section 5 of the Act;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) any adoption society by whom arrangements for the adoption have been made;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) the guardian<xhtml:i>ad litem.</xhtml:i></xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%">
    Dispensing<xhtml:br/>with consent. 
  </xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="85%">
    10B. An application to dispense with the consent of any person on any of the grounds specified in section 5 of the Act shall be by summons in Form 4C served on the person whose consent it is desired to dispense with, unless such person cannot be found, and accompanied by a statement, which shall also be filed with court, of the facts upon which the applicant intends to rely in support of the application. 
  </xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%">
    Hearing<xhtml:br/>of the<xhtml:br/>application. 
  </xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="85%">
    11. Notice of the hearing of the application for adoption shall be in Form 5 and shall be served on - <xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(a) all persons referred to in paragraphs (a), (b) and (c) of rule 10A; and 
   <xhtml:p>(b) all persons who have entered an appearance to the originating summons.</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%">
    Appearance at hearing. 
  </xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="85%">
    12. On the hearing of the application any person on whom notice is required to be served under rule11 may appear before the judge to show cause why an adoption order should not be made; and an adoption society may be represented by any officer of the society duly authorized in that behalf. 
  </xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%">
    Proceedings<xhtml:br/>where identity confidential. 
  </xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="85%">
    13. Unless the court is satisfied that the applicant does not desire his identity to be kept confidential, or the court is considering an application to dispense with the consent of any person whose consent is required and is satisfied that disclosure to such person of the identity of the applicant is necessary in the interests of justice, the proceedings shall be conducted with a view to securing so far as possible that he is not seen by or made known to any person (other than the spouse of the applicant) whose consent to the order is required. 
  </xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%">
    Attendance of applicant and infant. 
  </xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="85%">
    14. Unless otherwise directed, the applicant and any infant reported on by the guardian<xhtml:i>ad litem</xhtml:i>under rule 9 (h) shall attend at the hearing of the application for adoption. 
  </xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%">
    Powers of<xhtml:br/>court on<xhtml:br/>hearing. 
  </xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="85%">
    15. On the hearing of the application for an adoption order, the court may make such order as it thinks fit, including an interim order, or it may adjourn the hearing. 
  </xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%">
    Form and<xhtml:br/>transmission<xhtml:br/>of order. 
  </xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="85%">
    16. Every adoption order shall be drawn up by the registrar in Form 6 and a certified copy shall be served on the Registrar-General within thirty days of its date. 
  </xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%">
    Interim order. 
  </xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="85%">
    17. Where the determination of an application is postponed and an interim order made, the applicant shall obtain an appointment for the further hearing of the application, on, or as soon as possible after, the expiry of the period specified in the interim order, and shall thereupon comply with rule 11. 
  </xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%">
    Amendment of adoption order. 
  </xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="85%">
    18. (1) An order under section 15 (1) of the Act for the amendment of an adoption order may be made<xhtml:i>ex parte.</xhtml:i><xhtml:p>(2) Where an order for the amendment of an adoption order is made the registrar shall send to the Registrar-General a notice specifying the date of the adoption order and the names of the adopter and of the adopted person (as described in the adoption order) and stating what amendments are to be made in the particulars specified in that order.</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%">
    Consent<xhtml:br/>to future<xhtml:br/>adoption. 
  </xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="85%">
    18A. In any case where it is desired to give consent to future adoption under section 7B of the Act. such consent shall be in Form 7.<xhtml:br/></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%">
    Keeping of<xhtml:br/>documents and<xhtml:br/>information. 
   <xhtml:p/></xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="85%">
    19. (1) All documents filed in court shall be confidential and shall be so treated by the registrar. 
   <xhtml:p>(2) No copy of any order may be given to or served on any person other than the applicant or the Registrar General, and subject to these rules no copy of any proceedings or any other document may be given to any person, unless the court otherwise directs.</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%">
    Service of<xhtml:br/>documents. 
   <xhtml:p/></xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="85%">
    20. Any document required to be served, may be served - 
   <xhtml:p>(a) on an individual, by delivering it to him personally, or by leaving it with some person for him at his last known or usual place of abode (whether in Kenya or elsewhere) or by sending it to him by registered post;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) on a Government Department, adoption society or other body of persons, by delivering it at the principal office of the Department, society or body, or by sending it by registered post.</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%">
    Attestation of documents. 
   <xhtml:p/></xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="85%">
    21. (1) For the purposes of section 6 (1) of the Act a document shall be sufficiently attested if it is attested as follows - 
   <xhtml:p>(a) if it is executed in Kenya, by a magistrate, registrar or advocate;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) if it is executed in any Commonwealth country, by any person for the time being authorized by law in that place to administer an oath for any judicial or other legal purposes; and</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) if it is executed in any country outside the Commonwealth, by any consular officer of Kenya or, if there is none, a consular officer of the United Kingdom or any other Commonwealth country.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) Any document executed in accordance with this rule shall be admissible without further proof of execution.</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%">
    Bond.<xhtml:br/></xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="85%">
    2lA. Where any person is required under section 7 (2) of the Act to enter into a bond, such bond shall be in Form 8. 
  </xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%">
    Costs. 
  </xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="85%">
    22. The court may make such orders as to costs as it thinks fit. 
  </xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%">
    Service of<xhtml:br/>notice of<xhtml:br/>appeal. 
  </xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="85%">
    23. Notice of appeal under section 11 of the Act shall be served only on the persons who attended at the hearing of the application. 
  </xhtml:td></xhtml:tr></xhtml:table><xhtml:p>&#160;</xhtml:p><xhtml:table width="100%"><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%"/><xhtml:td width="85%"><xhtml:p>SCHEDULE</xhtml:p><xhtml:table width="100%"><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="87%"><xhtml:p>FORM1</xhtml:p></xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="13%"><xhtml:p>(r. 4 )</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr></xhtml:table><xhtml:p>ORIGINATING SUMMONS ON APPLICATION FOR AN ADOPTION ORDER</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>In the .................. Court .................. at ..................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Adoption Cause No. ............ of 19......</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Let ................... of ................ within 10 days of service on him enter an appearance to this summons which is issued on the application of ............................ of .................... (or, under the serial number ............) for an order - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(1) That .................................. of ....................... be appointed guardian<xhtml:i>ad litem</xhtml:i>in this case.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) That the applicant(s) be authorized to adopt ............................... an infant (enter the forenames only of the infant in accordance with the birth certificate).</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Dated this .................. day of ................... 19......</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>.................................<xhtml:br/>Registrar</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>This summons was taken out by the applicant personally/the ........................ Adoption Society of .............................. on behalf of the applicant/ ....................... advocate for the applicant.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>Note:</xhtml:i></xhtml:p><xhtml:p>If the person served does not enter an appearance within the time above mentioned the application will be dealt with without further reference to him unless that person is - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) an adoption society which has made arrangements for the adoption; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) a person whose consent to the adoption is required but has not been given,<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>and in either of the latter cases notice of further proceedings in the application will be served in accordance with rules 10A, 10B or 11 of the Adoption Rules.</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%"/><xhtml:td width="85%"><xhtml:table width="100%"><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="82%"><xhtml:p>FORM 2</xhtml:p></xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="18%"><xhtml:p>(r. 8 (a))</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr></xhtml:table><xhtml:p>(<xhtml:i>Heading as in Form 1</xhtml:i>)</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>STATEMENT IN SUPPORT OF AN APPLICATION FOR AN ADOPTION ORDER</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>1. I/We, the undersigned, wish to adopt AB an infant of the ......................... sex born on the .................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>2. My/Our full name(s) is/are .......................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>3. My/Our occupation(s) is/are ...................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>4. My/Our date(s) of birth is/are ..................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>5. I/We reside at .........................................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>6. I/We am/are of .................................... nationality and of ................race.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>7. I/We have resided in Kenya since ...........................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>8. I/We intend to continue to reside in Kenya indefinitely/until ......................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>9. I am married/a widow/a widower/a divorcee/married to ED of ................. /We are married to each other and are the persons to whom the attached marriage certificate (or other evidence of marriage) relates. My/Our marriage is/is not polygamous or such as may lawfully become polygamous.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>10. I/We am/are of the ........................................... religion.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>11. The infant was received into my/our care and possession on ................... and has been continuously in my/our care and possession since that date.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>12. The infant is of ........................... nationality and of ....................... race.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>13. The infant is of the ................................................. religion.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>14. I/We have not received or agreed to receive, and no person has made or given or agreed to make or give to me/us, any payment or reward in consideration of the adoption.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>15. I/We have not made any previous application for an adoption order in respect of the same infant, except (give details) ...........................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>16. I/We desire that my/our identity should be kept confidential.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>17. I/We am/are related to the infant as follows: ..........................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>18. If an adoption order is made, it is proposed that the infant be known as ...................................................................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>19. No previous application has been made relating to the adoption of the infant (or as the case may be).</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%"/><xhtml:td width="85%"><xhtml:table width="100%"><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="84%"><xhtml:p>FORM 3</xhtml:p></xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="16%"><xhtml:p>(r. 8 (a))</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr></xhtml:table><xhtml:p>(<xhtml:i>Heading as in Form 1</xhtml:i>)</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>AFFIDAVIT IN SUPPORT OF APPLICATION</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>I, ..................................... of ................................. make oath and say: - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>1. I am the applicant herein.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>2. The facts stated in paragraphs ................................. of my statement herein dated the .................. day of 19....... are true.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>3. The facts stated in paragraphs ........................... of my said statement are true to the best of my knowledge, information and belief.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>SWORN at .................... this ...................... day of .................. 19......etc.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Notes:</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Throughout this Form, in the case of a joint application, substitute the plural.</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%"/><xhtml:td width="85%"><xhtml:table width="100%"><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="82%"><xhtml:p>FORM 4</xhtml:p></xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="18%"><xhtml:p>(r. 8 (d))</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr></xhtml:table><xhtml:p><xhtml:br/>CONSENT TO AN ADOPTION ORDER IN RESPECT OF AN INFANT NAMED A.B. (1)</xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:br/>Whereas an application is to be made (by CD and ED) (2) or (under the serial number .....................) (Whereas the said AB (hereinafter called the infant) is not less than six weeks old, having been born in .................. on the .................. day of ......................... 19......) (3)</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>I the undersigned .............................. of ......................... being the</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>mother of the infant/<xhtml:br/>the father of the infant/<xhtml:br/>a guardian of the infant/</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>the parent of the mother of the infant (in a case where the mother of the infant is unmarried and under the age of 18) / person liable by virtue of an order or agreement to contribute to the maintenance of the infant/the spouse of CD, hereby state as follows - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(1) I understand that the effect of an adoption order will be to deprive me permanently of the rights of a parent/guardian and in particular I understand that, if an order is made, I shall have no right to see or get in touch with the infant or have him/her returned to me;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) I understand that when the application for an adoption order is heard by the court, this document may be used as evidence of my consent to the making of the order;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) I consent to the making of an adoption order (on condition that the religious persuasion in which the infant is brought up is ...........................)(4)</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>.....................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(<xhtml:i>Signature</xhtml:i>)</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Signed at......................on the ...........................day of ..................,19......., by the said .....................................(who satisfied me that she fully understood the foregoing statement) (3)</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Before me .........................................(Signature)<xhtml:br/>of ......................................................(address) ..........................................................(description)</xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>Notes:</xhtml:i></xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(1) Insert name as known to consenting party.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) Where the name of applicant is not known to the consenting party, and serial number has been obtained for the application under rule 5, complete the entry contained in second brackets.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) Delete the words in brackets except where the consenting party is the mother of infant.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) Delete the words in brackets if no condition as to religious upbringing is to be imposed.</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%"/><xhtml:td width="85%"><xhtml:table width="100%"><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="81%">
       Form 4A 
     </xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="19%"><xhtml:p>(r.10A)</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr></xhtml:table><xhtml:p>APPLICATION FOR RETENTION OF CUSTODY OF THE INFANT PENDING FINAL DISPOSAL OF THE APPLICATION</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(<xhtml:i>Heading as form in Form 1</xhtml:i>)</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>To: ...................................<xhtml:br/>...................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>TAKE NOTICE that an application will be made to the ..................... at the ...................... court .....................on .................... the ........................ day of ...........................,19 ............ at .........................o'clock for an order that the applicant(s) may be granted custody of the infant ............................. until the disposal of the application for adoption.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>You may appear at the time and place stated above to show cause why the application for custody should not be granted.</xhtml:p><xhtml:table width="100%"><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="50%"/><xhtml:td width="50%"><xhtml:i>Applicant /</xhtml:i></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="50%"/><xhtml:td width="50%"><xhtml:i>Adoption Society acting for the Applicant /</xhtml:i></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="50%"/><xhtml:td width="50%"><xhtml:i>Advocate for the Applicant.</xhtml:i></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr></xhtml:table></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%"/><xhtml:td width="85%"><xhtml:table width="100%"><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="83%">
       FORM 4B 
     </xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="17%"><xhtml:p>(r. 10A)</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr></xhtml:table><xhtml:p>(<xhtml:i>Heading as in Form 1</xhtml:i>)</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>AFFIDAVIT IN SUPPORT OF APPLICATION FOR CUSTODY PENDING DISPOSAL</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>I. ......................................of ................................. make oath and say - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(1) I am the applicant herein.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) The infant ....................................... who is the subject of my application for adoption has been lawfully in my care since ...........................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) The circumstances in which the infant came into my care are as follows - <xhtml:br/>...................................................................................................................<xhtml:br/>...................................................................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) I therefore ask that this court grant me custody of the infant .................... until such time as my application to adopt him/her is finally disposed of.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>SWORN at ........................... this ............... day of ................. 19...... etc.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>Note.</xhtml:i> - In the case of a joint application substitute the plural.</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%"/><xhtml:td width="85%"><xhtml:table width="100%"><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="83%"><xhtml:p>FORM 4c</xhtml:p></xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="17%"><xhtml:p>(r. 10B)</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr></xhtml:table><xhtml:p>APPLICATION FOR AN ORDER DISPENSING WITH CONSENT</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(<xhtml:i>Heading as in Form 1</xhtml:i>)</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>To: ................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>TAKE NOTICE that an application will be made to the Judge in Chambers on .................. the day of ................... 19....... at .................. o'clock for an order dispensing with your consent to the adoption being made.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>The grounds on which the application will be made are that the case falls within the following provisions of section 5 of the Adoption Act, that is to say .......................................................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>A statement of the facts on which the applicant intends to rely in support of the application accompanies this summons.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>If you do not appear in answer to this summons at the time and place stated above the application will be determined in your absence.</xhtml:p><xhtml:table width="100%"><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="50%"/><xhtml:td width="50%"><xhtml:i>Applicant/</xhtml:i></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="50%"/><xhtml:td width="50%"><xhtml:i>Adoption Society acting for the<xhtml:br/>Applicant/</xhtml:i></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="50%"/><xhtml:td width="50%"><xhtml:i>Advocate for the Applicant.</xhtml:i></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr></xhtml:table></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%"/><xhtml:td width="85%"><xhtml:table width="100%"><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="86%"><xhtml:p>FORM 5</xhtml:p></xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="14%"><xhtml:p>(r.11)</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr></xhtml:table><xhtml:p>HEARING NOTICE</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(<xhtml:i>Heading as in Form 1</xhtml:i>)</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>To: ............................................................ of .......................................... Whereas an application has been made (by CD/CD and ED) (1) or (under the serial number of ..................)</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>TAKE NOTICE that the application will be heard at the .................... Court ......................... at ..................... o'clock in the forenoon on .................. the ..................... day of ................. 19....... and that you may appear to show cause why the adoption order should not be made.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Dated this .................. day of ...................... 19........</xhtml:p><xhtml:table width="100%"><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="50%"/><xhtml:td width="50%"><xhtml:i>Applicant/</xhtml:i></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="50%"/><xhtml:td width="50%"><xhtml:i>Advocate for the Applicant/<xhtml:br/>Adoption Society acting for the Applicant</xhtml:i></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr></xhtml:table><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>Note:</xhtml:i></xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(1) The name of the applicant must not be given when the notice is addressed to an individual and a serial number has been obtained under rule 5 or rule 6.</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%"/><xhtml:td width="85%"><xhtml:table width="100%"><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="83%">
       FORM 6 
     </xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="17%"><xhtml:p>(r. 16)</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr></xhtml:table><xhtml:p>ADOPTION ORDER</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(<xhtml:i>Heading as in Form 1</xhtml:i>)</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Application having been made by CD by occupation a .................. resident at .................. and ED his wife (hereinafter called the applicant/applicants) for an order under the Adoption Act authorizing him/her/them to adopt AB an infant, the child/adopted child of FB/FB and GB.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>And the said AB (hereinafter called the infant) being of the .................... sex and never having been married;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>And the applicant/one of the applicants having attained the age of twenty-five years and being at least twenty-one years older than the infant;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Having attained the age of twenty-one years and being a relative of the infant within the meaning of the Act;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Being the mother/father of the infant;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(And the names by which the infant is to be known being FD) (1);</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(And it having been proved to the satisfaction of the judge that the infant is identical with AB, to whom an entry numbered .................. and made on the .................... 19 ....... in the district of............. ................... relates) (2) And the (probable) (3) date and place of birth of the infant appearing to be the ............................19....... at ..............................;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>And the infant having been previously the subject of an adoption order dated the ........................ 19 ....... of which particulars are entered in the Adopted Children Register) (4)</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>IT IS ORDERED that the applicant/applicants be authorized to adopt the infant;<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>And it is directed that the Registrar-General shall make in the Adopted Children Register an entry recording the adoption in accordance with the particulars set out in the Schedule to this Order;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(And it is further directed that the Registrar-General shall cause the said entry in the Register of Births to be marked with the word "Adopted") (2);</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(And it is further directed that the Registrar-General shall notify the Registrar-General of (Tanzania or Uganda) that an adoption order has been made by the Court in respect of the infant) (5);</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(And it is further directed that the Registrar-General shall cause the previous entry in the Adopted Children Register relating to the infant to be marked with the word "readopted");</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(And it is further directed that the applicant shall comply with the following terms and conditions referred to in section 7 (2) of the Adoption Act, that is to say ...................................................).</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>SCHEDULE</xhtml:p><xhtml:table width="100%"><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="20%">
       Date and place of birth of child (6) 
     </xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="20%">
       Name of child (7) 
     </xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="20%">
       Sex of child 
     </xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="20%">
       Name and surname Address and occupation of adopter or adopters 
     </xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="20%">
       Date of adoption order and court by which made 
     </xhtml:td></xhtml:tr></xhtml:table><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>Notes:</xhtml:i></xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(1) Delete where there is no change of name.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) Delete this entry - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Where the infant is identified with a person whose birth is registered in the Register of Births of Kenya, Tanzania or Uganda;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) if the infant has been previously adopted.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Where the infant is identified with a person whose birth is registered in any such registry other than that of Kenya, modify the entry.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) Delete "probable" where the precise date of the infant's birth is proved.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) Delete except where the infant has been previously adopted.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(5) Where the infant is identified with a person whose birth is registered in the Register of Births of Tanzania or Uganda, substitute this direction for the previous one.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(6) Where a probable date and place of birth are specified in the body of the order, enter that date and place without qualification.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(7) Enter only the names by which the infant is to be known.</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%"/><xhtml:td width="85%"><xhtml:table width="100%"><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="82%">
       FORM 7 
     </xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="18%"><xhtml:p>(r.18A)</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr></xhtml:table><xhtml:p>CONSENT TO FUTURE ADOPTION OF AN INFANT NAMED (1)</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>WHEREAS AB an infant born on the ...........................19 ......... has been placed in the care and protection of an adoption society known as ............... of .....................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>I, the undersigned, being the mother of the infant/father of the infant/guardian of the infant/parent of the mother of the infant (in a case where the mother of the infant is unmarried and under the age of 18) / person liable by virtue of an order or agreement to contribute to the maintenance of the infant, hereby state as follows - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(1) I consent to the future adoption of the infant by any adopter approved by the society within a year of the last consent being given by all those persons whose consent is required to be given under section 4 (6) of the Adoption Act.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) I understand that the effect of an adoption order is to deprive me permanently of the rights of a parent/guardian and m particular I understand that if an order is made I shall have no right to see or get in touch with the infant or have him/her returned to me.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) I understand that when an application for an adoption order is heard by the court, this document may be used as evidence of my consent to the making of the order.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) I understand that in the event of the adoption society being unable to find a suitable adopter within the time specified in paragraph (1) I may be requested by that society to remove the infant from its care and possession, and that failure to do so may result in an order being made to commit him/her to the care of a fit person under section 25 of the Children and Young Persons Act (Cap. 141).</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(5) My consent is subject to the condition that the infant is brought up in the ....................... religion (2).</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>...................................<xhtml:br/>(<xhtml:i>Signature</xhtml:i>)</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Signed at ............... on the .............. day of .................. 19....... by the said .............................. (who satisfied me that she fully understood the nature of the foregoing statement) 3).</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Before me ..................................... (Signature)</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>of ................................................. (address)</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>..................................................... (description)</xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>Notes:</xhtml:i></xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(1) Insert the name as known to the consenting party.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) Delete paragraph (5) if inapplicable.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) Delete the words in brackets except where the consenting party is the mother of the infant.</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%"/><xhtml:td width="85%"><xhtml:table width="100%"><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="86%">
       FORM 8 
     </xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="14%"><xhtml:p>(r. 2lA)</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr></xhtml:table><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>(Heading as in Form 1)</xhtml:i></xhtml:p><xhtml:p>BOND</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>BY THIS BOND, I/We ........................................ the person(s) in whose favour an adoption order relating to the infant ..................................... was made by the .................................... Court on the ........................ day<xhtml:br/>of ........................ 19....... acknowledge myself/ourselves to be firmly bound to do the several things set out hereunder in pursuance of the direction of the Court made under section 7 (2) of the Adoption Act.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(set out the conditions)<xhtml:br/>..................................................................................................................<xhtml:br/>..................................................................................................................<xhtml:br/>..................................................................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>And I/We understand that should I/We fail to undertake any of the obligations of this bond such failure will constitute contempt of court and be punishable as such.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Dated this .................. day of ................... 19......</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Signed, sealed and delivered<xhtml:br/>by the above named<xhtml:br/>............................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>in the presence of<xhtml:br/>...........................................</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%"/><xhtml:td width="85%"/></xhtml:tr></xhtml:table></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-19062"><num/><heading>SECTION  THE ADOPTION REGULATIONS</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:table width="100%"><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%">
    L.N.252/1959, L.N.279/1979, L.N.90/1997.<xhtml:br/>Cap. 531. 
  </xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="85%"><xhtml:b>Regulations under section 35</xhtml:b><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>THE ADOPTION REGULATIONS</xhtml:b></xhtml:p><xhtml:p>PART I - PRELIMINARY</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>1. These Regulations may be cited as the Adoption Regulations.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>2. In these Regulations, except where the context otherwise requires - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"adopter" means any person making application to an adoption society with a view to adopting an infant;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"case committee" has the meaning assigned to it in paragraph (b) of regulation 5.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>PART II - ADOPTION SOCIETIES</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>3. Every application for the approval of an adoption society under the Act shall be made in the form, and shall give the particulars, set out in the First Schedule.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>4. Where the parent or guardian of an infant proposes to place an infant at the disposition of a registered adoption society with a view to the infant being adopted, the society - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) shall furnish the parent or guardian with an explanatory memorandum in the form set out in the Second Schedule; and</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) shall not accept the infant unless the parent or guardian has signed and delivered to the society a certificate of acknowledgement (which the society shall retain) in the form set out in the Second Schedule that he has read and understood the memorandum.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>5. In the case of every infant proposed to be delivered by or on behalf of a registered adoption society into the care and possession of an adopter - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) the society shall make inquiries and obtain reports on the matters set out in the Third Schedule, and the reports obtained on the health of the infant and the adopters shall be signed by a medical practitioner, and reports obtained under this paragraph shall be retained by the adoption society until the infant's age of majority;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) the case shall be considered by a committee (called a case committee) appointed by the society for the purpose and consisting of not less than three and not more than five persons, one of whom shall wherever possible 'be a trained social worker.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>6. No infant shall be delivered into the care and possession of an adopter by or on behalf of an adoption society until - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) the adopter has been interviewed by the case committee or by some person on their behalf;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) a representative of the case committee has inspected any premises in Kenya in which the adopter intends that the infant should reside permanently; and</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) the case committee has considered the reports required by regulation 5.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>7. (1) Every adoption society shall, within twelve months after the date of its approval by the Minister and thereafter at least once in every period of twelve months, furnish to the Minister - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) duly audited accounts and a balance sheet; and</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) a report in the form set out in the Fourth Schedule to these Regulations.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) For the purpose of subparagraph (a) of paragraph (1), the auditor shall be an independent person who is the holder of a practising certificate issued pursuant to section 21 of the Accountants Act, or is on other grounds accepted by the Minister as competent for the purpose; and no person shall be deemed to be independent if he is related to or associated in business with any member of a committee, i or with any officer, of the society.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>8. (1) Every adoption society shall make adequate arrangements for the care and supervision of infants who have been placed by their parents or guardians in the care of the society.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) Every such infant who is not living under the direct control of the society shall, unless and until the infant has been adopted in pursuance of a adoption order, or he Minister otherwise directs, be visited in the first month and at least once in every three months thereafter by a representative of the society, who shall report upon the case to the case committee; and, if the case committee so recommend, the society shall immediately remove the infant.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>PART III MISCELLANEOUS</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>9. Every prospective adopter shall, forthwith upon an infant being placed with him by any party other than an adoption society, notify the Chief Inspector of Children of such placement and of the date thereof.<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>9A. (1) Where an infant has been delivered into the care and possession of a prospective adopter, visits shall fee made to the infant at least once in every month - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) in the case of an infant so delivered by an adoption society, by a representative of that society; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) in any other case, by the Chief Inspector of Children or his authorized representative and for that purpose the prospective adopter shall allow access by such person to the infant at any reasonable time.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) The representative of the adoption society or inspector of children shall report on such visits to the guardian<xhtml:i>ad litem</xhtml:i>, unless he is himself the guardian<xhtml:i>ad litem</xhtml:i>of the infant.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) The provisions of this regulation are additional to and not in substitution for the provisions of regulation 8.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>9B. Where the court makes an adoption order conditional on the adopter accepting supervision and advice from an adoption society, a representative of such society shall visit the infant at least once in every month during the continuance in force of the condition and for that purpose the adopter shall allow access by such person to the infant at any reasonable time.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>10. The fees payable under subsection (3) of section 13 of the Act shall be - <xhtml:br/></xhtml:p><xhtml:table width="100%"><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="90%"/><xhtml:td width="10%"><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>Sh.</xhtml:i></xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="90%">
       (a) to search the index of the Adopted Children Register 
     </xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="10%"><xhtml:p>100</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="90%">
       (b) for a certified copy of an entry in that register 
     </xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="10%"><xhtml:p>100</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr></xhtml:table></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr></xhtml:table><xhtml:p>&#160;</xhtml:p><xhtml:table width="100%"><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%"/><xhtml:td width="85%"><xhtml:table width="100%"><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="89%"><xhtml:p>FIRST SCHEDULE</xhtml:p></xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="11%"><xhtml:p>(r. 3)</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr></xhtml:table><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>Form of Application for Registration of an Adoption Society</xhtml:i></xhtml:p><xhtml:p>To: The Minister for Health,<xhtml:br/>Nairobi.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>I/We the undersigned being (a person) (persons) duly authorized on behalf of the adoption society called .......................... hereby apply to have the said society registered under the Adoption Regulations.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>The following are particulars of the society - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>1. Date of establishment.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>2. Full postal address of the society's administrative centre.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>3. (a) For what object(s) does the society exist - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) Does it exist only for the above object(s) - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) Does it apply the whole of its profits, if any, and other income in promoting the above objects - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>[A copy of the instrument governing the society's activities should be attached]</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>*4. Full names, addresses and occupations or descriptions of all members of the committee controlling the activities of the society.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>*5. Full names, addresses, occupations or descriptions and qualifications of members of the case committee.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>6. Has any person taking part in the management or control of the society or any member of the society been convicted of an offence under the Adoption Act, or of a breach of any regulations made thereunder - (If so, give particulars.)</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>*7. Full names, addresses and qualifications of all persons employed by the society, whether voluntary or paid, for the purpose of making any arrangement for the adoption of children.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>8. Cases dealt with by the society during the year ended - .......</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) Number of applications from persons wishing to adopt a child.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) Number of children offered to the society with a view to adoption.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) Number of children taken into hostels under the direct control of the society pending adoption.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(d) Number of children placed by the society pending adoption in foster homes or hostels not under the direct control of the society.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(e) Number of children placed with a view to adoption.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(f) Number of adoption orders made in respect of children placed by the society.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>9. (a) Number of children placed for adoption by the society and awaiting adoption orders at the end of the year.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) Number of children in hostels under the direct control of the society at the end of the year</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) Number of children at the end of the year in foster homes or in hostels in which they had been placed by the society but which are not under the society's direct control.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>10. Copies should be attached of the society's latest annual report and audited statement of accounts.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>I/We hereby declare that the above particulars are correct in every respect.<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>Signature:</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Office held under the society:</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Address:</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Signature:</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Office held under the society:</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Address:</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Date :</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>*Attach separate list if necessary.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> - Insert date on which last financial year ended.</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr></xhtml:table><xhtml:p>&#160;</xhtml:p><xhtml:table width="100%"><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%"/><xhtml:td width="85%"><xhtml:table width="100%"><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="87%"><xhtml:p>SECOND SCHEDULE</xhtml:p></xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="13%"><xhtml:p>(r. 4)</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr></xhtml:table><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>Adoption of Children - Explanatory Memorandum</xhtml:i></xhtml:p><xhtml:p>1. If the court makes an adoption order, all your rights and duties with regard to the child will be transferred permanently to the adopters and in law the child will no longer be yours.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>2. The court cannot make an adoption order without the consent of each parent or guardian of the child, unless that parent or guardian has abandoned, persistently failed to maintain or persistently ill-treated or neglected the child, or cannot be found, or is incapable of giving consent (for instance, by reason of being insane), or is unreasonably withholding consent. Therefore, unless one of these things applies to you, an order cannot be made without your consent.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>3. Your consent may be given in writing, but if you are the child's mother your consent must be given in writing and signed in the presence of a witness and cannot be given until the child is six weeks old.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>4. You may either consent to adoption by specific applicants, or to adoption by any persons whom the adoption society finds to be suitable within twelve months from the giving of your consent.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>5. You may if you wish stipulate that your consent is given on condition that the child is brought up in a particular religious persuasion.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>6. Where specific applicants have applied to adopt, either these names must appear on the form or, if they have stated that they do not want you to know who they are (as they are entitled to do), the form must refer to them by a number identifying them in the records of the adoption society or the Chief Inspector of Children, as the case may be.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>7. Where the applicants are referred to by a number you are not allowed to be told who they are, but you are entitled to be given information as to what sort of people they are.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>8. If you have given your consent but change your mind and want to get the child back, you will have to apply to the court for leave to remove the child from the care of the would-be adopters; but you are not allowed to change your mind and withdraw your consent merely on the ground that you do not know the identity of the would-be adopters.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>9. You are not allowed to change your mind and withdraw your consent once a final adoption order has been made by the court.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>10. You are not allowed to receive or pay any money for the adoption unless the court agrees. This does not apply to a weekly payment to an adoption society for the maintenance of your child before the child goes to the adopters.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>11. If you have taken out an insurance policy against funeral expenses for your child, the insurer will be able to tell you whether. after the adoption order is made. the policy can be transferred to the adopters should they wish to continue it.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>Form of Certificate of Acknowledgement</xhtml:i></xhtml:p><xhtml:p>To (insert name and address of adoption society):</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>I HEREBY CERTIFY that I have received from you a memorandum headed "Adoption of Children - Explanatory Memorandum", from which I have detached this certificate of acknowledgement; and I further certify that I have read the memorandum and understand it.<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>Signature: ............................................. Address: ...........................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Date: ..........................................</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr></xhtml:table><xhtml:p>&#160;</xhtml:p><xhtml:table width="100%"><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%"/><xhtml:td width="85%"><xhtml:table width="100%"><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="86%"><xhtml:p>THIRD SCHEDULE</xhtml:p></xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="14%"><xhtml:p>(r. 5)</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr></xhtml:table><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>Matters on which inquiries are to be made and reports obtained</xhtml:i></xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>Part A - Particulars relating to the infant</xhtml:i></xhtml:p><xhtml:p>1. Name.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>2. Address.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>3. Date and place of birth.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>4. Infant's nationality.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>5. If baptized state place of baptism and denomination.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>6. Full name, address and age of the child's parents. If dead, state date of death.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>7. Parents' religion(s).</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>8. Is there any history of insanity, tuberculosis or other disease in the family of either parent - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>9. Has either parent any other children - If so, state their age and sex.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>10. Why is the child offered for adoption - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>11. Has the child any right or interest in property - If so, give full particulars.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>12. Has any insurance been effected in respect of the child - </xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%"/><xhtml:td width="85%"><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>Part B - Particulars relating to the child's parents or guardians</xhtml:i></xhtml:p><xhtml:p>1. If the mother is alive, does she consent to the adoption - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>2. If the father is alive - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) is he married to the mother or otherwise contributing or liable to contribute to the child's maintenance - If so, give particulars. (If the parents are separated, state whether there is a separation order in force.)</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) does he consent to the adoption - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>3. If the child has a guardian, state - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) their names and addresses;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) how and by whom they were appointed;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) whether they consent to adoption.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>4. (a) Arc any other persons liable to contribute to the support of the child - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) If so, do they agreed to adoption - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>5. If the answer to questions 1, 2 (b), 3 (c) or 4 (b) is in the negative, the reasons should be stated.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>6. (a) Has the child any grandparents, brothers, sisters, uncles, or aunts - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) If so have they been informed of the proposed adoption - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) Has any of them offered to provide a home for the child - </xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%"/><xhtml:td width="85%"><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>Part C - Particulars relating to the adopter(s)</xhtml:i></xhtml:p><xhtml:p>1. Name(s).</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>2. Address(es).</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>3. Country of domicile.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>4. Date(s) of birth.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>5. Religion(s).</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>6. Nationality and race.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>7. Length of previous residence in Kenya.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>8. Intended length of future residence in Kenya.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>9. Marital status of joint applicants and whether polygamous.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>10. Occupation(s).</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>11. Immigration status.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>12. Is it intended to apply for an adoption order - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>13. Is the adopter married or are the adopters a married couple - If so, give date and place of marriage, and say whether it is intended to make a point application for an adoption order.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>14. Is there any child of the adopter(s) living at home - If so, give age and sex.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>15. Has any child been adopted by the adopter(s) before - If so, give particulars.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>16. What is the accommodation and condition of the home - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>17. What are the means of the adopter(s) - How far are the earning of children living at home included - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>18. What are the wishes of the adopter(s) as to the age and sex of the child they wish to adopt - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>19. Would the adopter(s) welcome periodical visits by a representative of an adoption society for a limited period after the adoption order is made - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>20. Is there any evidence of insanity, tuberculosis or other disease in the adopter(s) - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>21. Give the names and addresses of two responsible persons who can vouch for the character and means of the adopter(s).</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%"/><xhtml:td width="85%"><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>Part D - Verification of application</xhtml:i></xhtml:p><xhtml:p>1.(a) Have the particulars given under Parts A, B and C above been verified so far as possible - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) Have the particulars of the birth of the child, and of the death, marriage or separation of the parents, and of the marriage of the adopter(s) been confirmed by inspection of certificates of birth, death or marriage or the separation order - <xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>2. Has a representative of the case committee interviewed the adopter(s) - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>3. Has the home of the adopter(s) been inspected by a representative of the case committee - Was it found satisfactory - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>4. Are the adopter(s) and the members of their household persons of good character - Have their references been taken up - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>5. (a) Are the adopter(s) and the members of their household in good health - <xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(b) Is this supported by medical evidence - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>6. Has the child been seen by the adopter(s) - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>7. Has the child been accepted by the adopter(s) with a view to adoption - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>8. Has the desirability of maintaining contact with an adoption society and seeking its guidance been fully explained to the adopter(s) - </xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%"/><xhtml:td width="85%"><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>Part E - Medical Particulars of Infant</xhtml:i></xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(The medical report must be signed by a medical practitioner.)</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>1. (a) Date of birth.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) Weight at birth (state if premature).</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) Present weight.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(d) Was the mother's confinement normal or instrumental - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>2. State of nutrition (good, fair, poor).</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>3. (a) When did the child begin to walk - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) When did the child begin to talk - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>4. Has the child any affection of bones, muscles or joints - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>5. Are there any evidences of paralysis - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>6. Are there any evidences of syphilis - State result of serological test.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>7. Is there any evidence of tuberculosis - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>8. Has the child had fits - If so, state nature.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>9. Is there, or has there been, any affection of the skin - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>10. Is there, or has there been, any affection of the eyes - Is the sight normal - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>11. Has the child had any discharge from the ears, or any serious ear trouble, and can it hear well - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>12. Are the nose and throat in healthy condition - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>13. Is there any evidence of disease of heart, lungs, kidneys or liver - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>14. Has the child normal control of bowels and bladder for its age - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>15. Has the child had measles, chicken pox, whooping cough, mumps or poliomyelitis - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>16. Has the child received the following immunizations</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>B.C.G. (against tuberculosis) ..................................................................<xhtml:br/>Triple Vaccination (against whooping cough, diptheria and tetanus) ...............................................................................................................<xhtml:br/>Tetanus toxoid ........................................................................................<xhtml:br/>Small pox ...............................................................................................<xhtml:br/>Measles .................................................................................................<xhtml:br/>Other (state which) ................................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>17. Is the child's mental and physical development normal for its age - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>18. Are behaviour, speech and articulation normal for its age - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>19. If the child has been neglected or improperly fed, do you consider its constitution such that good nursing and proper care would make it suitable for adoption - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>20. Give particulars of any condition not mentioned above about which you consider an adopter should be informed.</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%"/><xhtml:td width="85%"><xhtml:table width="100%"><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="100%"><xhtml:i>Part F - Medical Particulars of Prospective Adapter</xhtml:i><xhtml:p>(The medical report must be signed 'by a medical practitioner)<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>1. (a) Name of prospective adopter;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) Date of birth;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) Sex;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(d) Address.<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>2. How long has the adopter been known to the medical practitioner - <xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>3. Is the prospective adopter in good health - <xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>4. Is the prospective adopter able to have natural children of his/her own and if not is the reason why he/she is unable to have such children known - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>5. If any fertility tests have been made to the prospective adopter what were the results of such - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>6. Has the prospective adopter suffered from any of the following - - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) tuberculosis;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) chronic bronchitis or recurrent chest illness;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) cardiovascular disease;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(d) any form of rheumatism;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(e) any form or neurosis or mental disorder;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(f) epilepsy;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(g) gentito-urinary disease;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(h) diabetes;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(i) any neurological disorder;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(j) leprosy;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(k) any illness which might shorten the expection of life or cause recurrent disability.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>7. Has the prospective adopter undergone any major surgical procedure - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>8. Is there any relevant family history of mental or physical disease - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>9. Is there any detectable abnormality in the following - - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) cardiovascular system (blood pressure should be stated);</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) respiratory system (if a chest X-ray is taken state date and result of such);</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) urogential system (state quantity of albumin and sugar in urine);</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(d) abdomen and alimentary system;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(e) central nervous system;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(f) eyes and vision;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(g) ears and hearing;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(h) skin.<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>10. Is there normal use of limbs - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>11. Does the prospective adopter appear mentally balanced and emotionally secure - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>12. Are there any other facts, medical or otherwise, about the prospective adopter which should be known - </xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr></xhtml:table></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr></xhtml:table><xhtml:p>&#160;</xhtml:p><xhtml:table width="100%"><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%"/><xhtml:td width="85%"><xhtml:table width="100%"><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="86%"><xhtml:p>FOURTH SCHEDULE</xhtml:p></xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="14%"><xhtml:p>(r. 7)</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr></xhtml:table><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>Form of Annual Report</xhtml:i></xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Report to the Minister of Health,</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>from the adoption society called ................................. for the financial year ended *............</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>1. Full postal address of the society's administrative centre.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>2. Has there been any change in the objects for which the society exists - Does it still apply the whole of its profits, if any, and other income in promoting those objects - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p> - 3. Full names, addresses and occupations or descriptions of all members of the committee controlling the activities of the society.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> - 4. Full names, addresses, occupations or descriptions and qualifications of members of the case committee.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>5. Has any person taking part in the management or control of the society or any member of the society been convicted of an offence under the Adoption Act, or of a breach of any regulations made thereunder - (If so, give particulars.)</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> - 6. Full names, addresses and qualifications of all persons employed by the society whether voluntary or paid, for the purpose of making any arrangements for the adoption of children.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>7. Cases dealt with by the society during the year ended *......</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) Number of applications from persons wishing to adopt a child.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) Number of children offered to the society with a view to adoption.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) "Number of children taken into hostels under the direct control of the society pending adoption.<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(d) Number of children placed by the society pending adoption in foster homes or hostels not under the direct control of the society.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(e) Number of children placed with a view to adoption.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(f) Number of adoption orders made in respect of children placed by the society.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>8. (a) Number of children placed for adoption by the society and awaiting adoption orders at the end of the year.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) Number of children in hostels under the direct control of the society at the end of the year.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) Number of children at the end of the year in foster homes or in hostels in which they had been placed by the society but which are not under the society's direct control.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>9. A copy of the society's latest annual report is attached. We hereby declare that the above particulars are correct in every respect.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Signature:</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Office held under the society:</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Address:</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Signature:</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Office held under the society:</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Address:</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Date:</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>* Insert date on which last financial year ended.<xhtml:br/> - Attach separate list if necessary.</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr></xhtml:table></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11829"><num>1</num><heading>SECTION 1 Short title.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>1.</xhtml:b>This Act may be cited as the Adoption Act.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11830"><num>2</num><heading>SECTION 2 Interpretation.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>2.</xhtml:b>(1) In this Act, unless the text otherwise requires - 
<xhtml:p>"adoption order" has the meaning assigned to it by section 3;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"adoption society" means a society approved by the Minister under section 23, and a local authority which has been approved by the Minister as an adoption society under that section;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"body of persons" means any body of persons, whether incorporate or unincorporate;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"charitable association" means a body of persons which exists only for the purpose of promoting a charitable, benevolent or philanthropic object, whether or not the object is charitable within the meaning of any rule of law, and which applies the whole of its profits (if any) or other income in promoting the object for which it exists:</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"the court" means the High Court or a Resident Magistrates Court acting in the exercise of the jurisdiction conferred on it by section 3A;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"East African Territories" means Kenya, Uganda and Tanzania;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"father", in relation to an illegitimate infant, means the natural father;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"guardian", in relation to an infant, means a person appointed by deed or will, in accordance with the provisions of any written law relating to the guardianship of infants for the time being in force in Kenya, or by a court of competent jurisdiction, to be the guardian of the infant;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"infant" means a person under eighteen years of age, but does not include a person who is or has been married;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"interim order" means an order under section 8;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"parent" does not include the natural father of an illegitimate infant;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"relative", in relation to an infant, means a grandparent, brother, sister, uncle or aunt, whether of the full blood, of the half-blood or by affinity, and - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) where an adoption order has been made in respect of the infant or any other person under this Act or any other law relating to adoption for the time being in force in any of the East African Territories or the United Kingdom, any person who would be a relative of the infant within the meaning of this definition if the adopted person were the child of the adopter born in lawful wedlock;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) where the infant is illegitimate and the father has acknowledged paternity and is contributing towards the maintenance of the infant, the father of the infant and any person who would be a relative of the infant within the meaning of this definition if the infant were a legitimate child of his mother and father;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"spouse", in relation to a wife of a polygamous marriage, means the wife applying for an adoption order either as sole applicant or jointly with her husband or the wife into whose care a husband applying for an adoption order proposes to give the infant.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) For the purposes of this Act, a person shall be deemed to make arrangements for the adoption of an infant if, not being a parent or guardian of the infant, he enters into or makes any agreement or arrangement for, or for facilitating, the adoption of the infant by any other person, whether the adoption is effected, or is intended to be effected, is pursuance of an adoption order or otherwise, or if he initiates or takes part in any negotiations of which the purpose or effect is the conclusion of any agreement or the making of any arrangement therefor, or if he causes another to do so.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11831"><num>3</num><heading>SECTION 3 Power to make adoption orders.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>3.</xhtml:b>(1) Subject to this Act, the court may, upon an application made in the prescribed manner, make an order (in this Act referred to as an adoption order) authorizing the applicant to adopt an infant.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) An adoption order may be made on the application of two spouses authorizing them jointly to adopt an infant.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) An adoption order may be made authorizing the adoption of an infant by the mother or father of the infant, either alone or jointly with her or his spouse.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) All proceedings under this Act shall be heard and determined in chambers.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(5) Any officer of an adoption society may draw or prepare any document relating to any proceedings under this Act and may carry on any such proceedings on behalf of an applicant for an adoption order:</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Provided that no fee, gain or reward other than a voluntary contribution to the adoption society may be accepted or received directly or indirectly therefor.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11832"><num>3A</num><heading>SECTION 3A Jurisdiction of a Resident Magistrate&amp;apos;s Court.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>3A.</xhtml:b>(1) A Resident Magistrate's Court shall have jurisdiction to hear and determine applications for adoption orders in cases where all consents required by subsection (6) of section 4 have been signified in the manner prescribed by section 6, and where the making of an order does not require justification as an exceptional measure under subsection (3) of section 4. 
<xhtml:p>(2) If in the course of an application for an adoption order in a Resident Magistrate's Court any consent is withdrawn or it appears to the court that the applicant is a person to whom subsection (3) of section 4 apply or that for any other reason it is desirable so to do, the court shall adjourn the application and transfer it to the High Court which shall proceed from the point at which the application was transferred.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11833"><num>4</num><heading>SECTION 4 Restrictions on making adoption orders.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>4.</xhtml:b>(1) An adoption order shall not be made in respect of an infant unless the applicant or, in the case of a joint application, one of the applicants - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) has attained the age of twenty-five years and is at least twenty-one years older than the infant; or<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(b) has attained the age of twenty-one years and is a relative of the infant; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) is the mother or father of the infant.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) Except as provided by subsection (2) of section 3 an adoption order shall not be made authorizing more than one person to adopt an infant.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) Unless the court is satisfied that there arc special circumstances which justify as an exceptional measure the making of an adoption order, an adoption order shall not be made in favour of - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) a sole applicant who is a male;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) a spouse or spouses of a polygamous marriage;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) an applicant who is of a different race from the infant.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) An adoption order shall not be made unless the applicant and the infant reside in Kenya.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(5) An adoption order shall not be made in respect of any infant unless the infant has been continuously in the care and possession of the applicant for at least three consecutive months immediately preceding the date of the presentation to the court of the application for the order.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(6) Subject to section 5 an adoption order shall not be made - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) in any case, except with the consent of every person or body who is a parent or guardian of the infant or who is liable by virtue of any order or agreement to contribute to the maintenance of the infant;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) in the case of an illegitimate infant whose paternity has been acknowledged and to whose maintenance contributions are being made by the father of the infant, except with the consent of the father;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) in the case of an illegitimate infant whose mother has not yet attained the age of eighteen years, except with the consent of the parents of the mother;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(d) on the application of one of two spouses, except with the consent of the other spouse.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11834"><num>5</num><heading>SECTION 5 Consent to adoption.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>5.</xhtml:b>(1) The Court may dispense with any consent required by paragraph (a), (b) or (c) of subsection (6) of section 4 if it is satisfied - 
<xhtml:p>(a) in the case of a parent or guardian of the infant, that he has abandoned, neglected, persistently failed to maintain or persistently ill-treated the infant, or that he has failed to exercise the normal duty and care of parenthood in respect of the infant: </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Provided that - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(i) abandonment may be presumed if the infant appears to have been abandoned at birth or if the person or body having care and possession of the infant has neither seen nor heard from a parent or guardian of the infant for a period of at least six consecutive months; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(ii) persistent failure to maintain may be presumed where, despite demands made, no parent or guardian has contributed to the maintenance of the infant for a period of at least six consecutive months and such failure is not due to poverty; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) in the case of a person liable by virtue of an order of agreement to contribute to the maintenance of the infant, that he has persistently neglected or refused so to contribute; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) in any case, that the person whose consent is required cannot be found or is incapable of giving his consent or that his consent is unreasonably withheld; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(d) in any case, that a provisional adoption order has been made in respect of the infant under section 53 of the Adoption Act, 1958, of the United Kingdom or under the corresponding provision of any former or subsequent Act of the United Kingdom or under the corresponding provision of any Act or Ordinance of any country in the Commonwealth. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) The court may dispense with the consent of the spouse of an applicant for an adoption order if satisfied that the person whose consent is to be dispensed with cannot be found or is incapable of giving the consent or that the spouses have separated and are living apart and that the separation is likely to be permanent. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) The consent of any person to the making of an adoption order in pursuance of an application may be given (either unconditionally or subject to conditions with respect to the religious persuasion in which the infant is to be brought up) without knowing the identity of the applicant for the order; and where the consent so given by any person is subsequently withdrawn on the ground only that he does not know the identity of the applicant, his consent shall be deemed for me purposes of this section to be unreasonably withheld. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) While an application for an adoption order in respect of an infant is pending in any court, any parent or guardian of the infant who has signified his consent to the making of an adoption order in pursuance of the application shall not be entitled, except with the leave of the court, to remove the infant from the care and possession of the applicant. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(5) An applicant for an adoption order may at the time of filing his application or at any time thereafter while such application is pending apply to the court for the custody of the infant pending the decision of the court on the application for an adoption order. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(6) In considering whether or not to dispense with the consent of any person to the making of an adoption order or whether to grant or refuse leave or custody under the provisions of subsection (4) or (5) the court shall regard the interests of the infant as paramount and subject thereto shall consider firstly the interests of the parents and relatives of the infant and secondly the interests of applicants. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(7) Any consent to the making of an adoption order may be withdrawn without leave of the court at any time prior to the making of an order. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11835"><num>6</num><heading>SECTION 6 Evidence of consent of parent or guardian.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>6.</xhtml:b>(1) Where any person whose consent to the making of an adoption order is required by paragraph (a), (b) or (c) of subsection (6) of section 4 does not attend in the proceedings for the purpose of giving it, then, subject to the provisions of subsection (3) of this section, a document, in the prescribed form and attested by a person of any such class as may be prescribed, signifying his consent to the making of such an order shall, if the person in whose favour the order is to be made is named in the document or (where the identity of that person is not known to the consenting party) is distinguished therein in the prescribed manner, be admissible as evidence of that consent, whether the document is executed before or after the commencement of the proceedings. 
<xhtml:p>(2) Any such document, whether executed in or outside Kenya, shall be admissible without further proof of the signature of the person by whom it was executed; and, for the purposes of this subsection, a document purporting to be attested as aforesaid shall be deemed to be so attested, and to be executed and attested on the date and at the place specified therein, unless the contrary is proved.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) A document signifying the consent of the mother of an infant shall not be admissible under this section unless - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) the infant is at least six weeks old on the date of the execution of the document; and<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(b) the document is attested on that date by a person of a class prescribed for the purposes of subsection (1).</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11836"><num>7</num><heading>SECTION 7 Functions of court as to adoption orders</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>7.</xhtml:b>(1) The court before making an adoption order shall be satisfied - 
<xhtml:p>(a) that every person whose consent is necessary under this Act, and whose consent is not dispensed with, has consented to and understands the nature<xhtml:br/>and effect of the adoption order for which application is made, and in particular, in the case of any parent, understands that the effect of the adoption order will be permanently to deprive him or her of his or her parental rights;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) that the order if made will be in the best interests of the infant, due consideration being for this purpose given to the wishes of the infant, having regard to the age and understanding of the infant, and to the ability of the applicant to maintain and educate him;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) that the applicant has not received or agreed to receive, and that no person has made or given or agreed to make or give to the applicant, any payment or other reward in consideration of the adoption contrary to section 29;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(d) that any person whose consent is dispensed with on the grounds of incapacity is still incapable of giving his consent at the date of making the order; and</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(e) where the applicant is not himself a relative of the infant, that reasonable steps have been taken to inform the relatives of the infant of the proposed adoption and that no relative able to accept the care of the infant has expressed willingness to do so.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) The court in an adoption order may impose such terms and conditions as it may think fit and in particular and without prejudice to the generality of the foregoing, the court may - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) require the adapter by bond or otherwise to make for the infant such provision as in the opinion of the court is just and expedient;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) order that the infant shall not be removed from the jurisdiction of the court without the consent of the court for such period not exceeding two years as it may specify;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) require the adopter to accept supervision by and advice from an adoption society specified by the court for such period not exceeding two years as the court may specify;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(d) where consent to the making of an adoption order is conditional upon the infant being brought up in a particular religious persuasion, require the infant to be brought up in that religious persuasion;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(e) require the adopter to furnish such security by bond or otherwise as the court may think fit for the due performance of any condition the court may impose.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11837"><num>7A</num><heading>SECTION 7A Appointment of provisional guardian.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>7A.</xhtml:b>(1) The court may, on the application of the adopter or of its own motion, at the time of making an adoption order appoint any person approved by the adopter and whose prior consent thereto has been given in writing to be guardian of the infant in the event of the adopter or both adopters where two spouses have applied for the adoption order, dying before the infant is of full age. 
<xhtml:p>(2) The court may, at any time before the infant is of full age on the application of the adopter, or of a guardian appointed under subsection (1), or of the infant, revoke any such appointment and appoint any other person to be guardian of the infant.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11838"><num>7B</num><heading>SECTION 7B Consent to future adoption.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>7B.</xhtml:b>(1) Where an infant is in the care and possession of an adoption society, consent to the future adoption of the infant by an adopter approved by such society may be given by those persons where consent to the making of an adoption order is required by the provisions of paragraph (a), (b) or (c) of subsection (6) of section 4. 
<xhtml:p>(2) Any such consent shall be signified in the manner provided in section 6 and the provisions of that section shall apply to any document signifying consent notwithstanding the omission therefrom of the name of the person in whose favour the adoption order is to be made or any other reference to an applicant for an adoption order.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) In the event of the adoption society being unable to find a suitable adopter within twelve months of the date of the last consent given under the provisions of this section, the society shall notify the persons whose consent has been given as aforesaid of such failure and may request them to remove the infant from the care and possession of the society.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) If within one month of any such request the infant has not been removed from the care and possession of the society, the infant shall be deemed to be in need of protection or discipline and on the application of the adoption society a court of competent jurisdiction may commit the infant to the care of a fit person under section 25 of the Children and Young Persons Act.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11839"><num>8</num><heading>SECTION 8 Interim orders.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>8.</xhtml:b>(1) Subject to this section, the court may, upon any application for an adoption order, postpone the determination of the application and make an interim order giving the custody of the infant to the applicant for a period not exceeding two years by way of a probationary period upon such terms as regards provision for the maintenance and education and supervision of that welfare of the infant and otherwise as the count may think fit. 
<xhtml:p>(2) All such consents as are required to an adoption order shall be necessary to an interim order but subject to a like power on the part of the court to dispense with any such consent.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) An interim order shall not be made in any case where the making of an adoption order would be unlawful by virtue of section 4.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) An interim order shall not be deemed to be an adoption order within the meaning of this Act.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11840"><num>9</num><heading>SECTION 9 Adoption order in respect of infants previously adopted</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>9.</xhtml:b>(1) An adoption order or an interim order may be made in respect of an infant who has already been the subject of an adoption order under this Act or under any Act or Ordinance for the time being in force in any country in the Commonwealth. 
<xhtml:p>(2) In relation to an application for an adoption order in respect of such an infant, the adopter or adopters under the previous or last previous adoption order shall be deemed to be the parent or parents of the infant for all the purposes of this Act.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11841"><num>10</num><heading>SECTION 10 Custody of infant when order refused.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>10.</xhtml:b>If the court refuses to make an adoption order or an interim order, the court may make such order for the custody of the infant as the court may think fit.<xhtml:br/></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11842"><num>11</num><heading>SECTION 11 Appeal.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>12.</xhtml:b>The Rules Committee may make rules of court in regard to any matter to be prescribed under this Part and providing generally for all matters of procedure and for carrying this Part into effect.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11843"><num>12A</num><heading>SECTION 12A Appointment of guardians</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>12A.</xhtml:b>(1) For the purpose of any application for an adoption order, the court shall, subject to any rules of court made by virtue of section 12, appoint an independent person or body to act as guardian<xhtml:i>ad litem</xhtml:i>of the infant upon the hearing of the application, with the duty of safeguarding the interests of the infant before the court and having for that purpose such powers and duties as may be prescribed by such rules. 
<xhtml:p>(2) Where arrangements for the adoption of any infant have been made by an adoption society neither that society nor any member thereof shall be appointed guardian<xhtml:i>ad litem</xhtml:i>of that infant for the purposes of its adoption.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) For the assistance of the court, and without prejudice to the discretion in the power of appointment given to the court by subsection (1), the Minister may, by notice in the Gazette, nominate a panel of persons whom he considers suitable for appointment as guardians<xhtml:i>ad litem</xhtml:i>and may from time to time add or remove names to or from the panel.<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(4) The Minister may by order published in the Gazette provide that in all cases where arrangements for an adoption have not been made by an adoption society the guardian<xhtml:i>ad litem</xhtml:i>appointed shall be an adoption society or a member of any such society.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(5) Where the body so appointed is a local authority the court may authorize the authority to incur any necessary expenditure; but nothing in this section shall be deemed to authorize the court to appoint a local authority to act as guardian<xhtml:i>ad litem</xhtml:i>except with the consent of that authority.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11844"><num>13</num><heading>SECTION 13 Adopted Children Register.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>13.</xhtml:b>(1) The Registrar-General shall maintain a register, to be called the Adopted Children Register, in which shall be made such entries as may be directed to be made therein by adoption orders, but no other entries.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) A certified copy of any entry in the Adopted Children Register, if purporting to be sealed or stamped with the seal of the Registrar-General's Office, shall, without any further or other proof of that entry, be received as evidence of the adoption to which it relates, and, where the entry contains a record of the date of the birth or the country of the birth of the adopted person, shall also be received as aforesaid as evidence of that date or country in all respects as if the copy were a certified copy of an entry in the Register of Births.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) The Registrar-General shall cause an index of the Adopted Children Register to be made; and every person shall be entitled to search that index and to have a certified copy of any entry in the Adopted Children Register upon payment of such fee as may be prescribed.<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(4) The Registrar-General shall, in addition to the Adopted Children Register and the index thereof, keep such other registers and books, and make such entries therein, as may be necessary to record and make traceable the connexion between any entry in the Register of Births which has been marked "Adopted" pursuant to section 14 of this Act or section 14 of the Adoption of Children Ordinance (now repealed) and any corresponding entry in the Adopted Children Register; but the registers and books kept under this subsection shall not be, nor shall any index thereof be, open to public inspection or search, nor, except under an order of a court of competent jurisdiction, shall the Registrar-General furnish any person, other than an adopted person of full age who has proved his identity to the satisfaction of the Registrar-General and who requests information with respect to his own adoption, with any information contained in or with any copy or extract from any such registers or books.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11845"><num>14</num><heading>SECTION 14 Registration of adoptions.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>14.</xhtml:b>(1) Every adoption order made by the court shall contain a direction to the Registrar-General to make in the Adopted Children Register an entry in the form set out in the First Schedule and (subject to subsection (2)) shall specify the particulars to be entered under the headings in columns 2 to 6 of that Schedule. 
<xhtml:p>(2) For the purposes of compliance with the requirements of subsection (1) - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) where the precise date of the infant's birth is not proved to the satisfaction of the court, the court shall determine the probable date of his birth and the date so determined shall be specified in the order as the date of his birth;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) (<xhtml:i>Deleted by</xhtml:i>4<xhtml:i>of</xhtml:i>1978,<xhtml:i>s.</xhtml:i>12.)</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) where the country of birth of the infant is not proved to the satisfaction of the court, the particulars of that country may, notwithstanding anything in that subsection, be omitted from the order and from the entry in the Adopted Children Register.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) Where upon any application to the court for an adoption order in respect of an infant (not being an infant who has previously been the subject of an adoption order made by the court under this Act or the Adoption of Children Ordinance (now repealed), there is proved to the satisfaction of the court the identity of the infant with a child to whom an entry in the Register of Births relates, any adoption order made in pursuance of the application shall contain a direction to the Registrar-General to cause the entry in the Register of Births to be marked with the word "Adopted".</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) Where an adoption order is made by the court in respect of an infant who has previously been the subject of an adoption order made by such court under this Act or the Adoption of Children Ordinance (now repealed), the order shall contain a direction to the Registrar-General to cause the previous entry in the Adopted Children Register to be marked with the word "Re-adopted".</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(5) Where an adoption order is made by the court, the court shall cause the order to be communicated in the prescribed manner to the Registrar-General, and upon receipt of such communication the Registrar-General shall cause compliance to be made with the directions contained in the order both in regard to marking any entry in the Register of Births with the word "Adopted" and in regard to making the appropriate entry in the Adopted Children Register.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11846"><num>15</num><heading>SECTION 15 Amendment of orders and rectification of registers.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>15.</xhtml:b>(1) The court by which an adoption order has been made under this Act or the Adoption of Children Ordinance (now repealed) may, on the application of the adopter or of the adopted person, amend the order by the correction of any error in the particulars contained therein; and, where an adoption order is so amended, the court shall cause the amendment to be communicated in the prescribed manner to the Registrar-General, and any necessary correction of or addition to the Adopted Children Register shall be made accordingly. 
<xhtml:p>(2) Where the adoption order was made before the commencement of this Act, the power of the court under subsection (1) shall include power to amend the order - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) by the insertion of the country of the adopted person's birth;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) (where the order does not specify a precise date as the date of the adopted person's birth) by the insertion of the date which appears to the court to be the date or probable date of his birth; and the provisions of that subsection shall have effect accordingly.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) Where an adoption order is quashed or an appeal against an adoption order allowed, the court which made the order shall give directions to the Registrar-General to cancel any marking of an entry in the Register of Births and any entry in the Adopted Children Register which was effected in pursuance of the order.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) Where the Registrar-General is notified by the Registrar-General or Administrator-General of any of the East African Territories that an adoption order has been made by a court in such territory under the law with regard to the adoption of children in force in such territory in respect of an infant to whom an entry in the Register of Births or the Adopted Children Register relates, the Registrar-General shall cause the entry to be marked "Adopted (Tanzania)" or "Adopted (Uganda)", as the case may be, or, as the case may be, "Re-adopted (Tanzania)" or "Re-adopted (Uganda)", and, where, after an entry has been marked in pursuance of this subsection, the Registrar-General is notified as aforesaid that the adoption order has been quashed or that an appeal against an adoption order has been allowed, he shall cause the marking to be cancelled.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(5) A copy or extract of an entry in any register, being an entry the marking of which is cancelled under this section, shall be deemed to be an accurate copy if, and only if, both the marking and the cancellation are omitted therefrom.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11847"><num>16</num><heading>SECTION 16 Rights and duties of parents and capacity to marry.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>16.</xhtml:b>(1) Upon an adoption order being made, all rights, duties, obligations and liabilities of the parents or guardians of the infant in relation to the future custody, maintenance and education of the infant, including all rights to appoint a guardian and to consent or give notice of dissent to marriage, shall be extinguished, and all such rights, duties, obligations and liabilities shall vest in and be exercisable by and enforceable against the adopter as if the infant were a child born to the adopter in lawful wedlock; and in respect of the matters aforesaid the infant shall stand to the adopter exclusively in the position of a child born to the adopter in lawful wedlock.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) In any case where two spouses are the adopters, the spouses shall in respect of the matters aforesaid, and for the purpose of the jurisdiction of any court to make orders as to the custody and maintenance of and right of access to children, stand to each other and to the infant in the same relation as they would have stood if they had been the lawful father and mother of the infant and the infant shall stand to them respectively in the same relation as to a lawful father and mother respectively.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) For the purpose of any written law relating to marriage for the time being in force in Kenya, an adopter and the person whom he has been authorized to adopt under an adoption order shall be deemed to be within the prohibited degrees of consanguinity; and the provisions of this subsection shall continue to have effect notwithstanding that some person other than the adopter is authorized by a subsequent order to adopt the same infant.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11848"><num>17</num><heading>SECTION 17 Workmen&amp;apos;s compensation.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>17.</xhtml:b>For the purposes of the Workmen's Compensation Act, an infant whom a deceased workman has been authorized to adopt under an adoption order shall be deemed to be a member of the family of such workman and an adopter shall be deemed to be the parent of a deceased workman whom he has been so authorized to adopt.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11849"><num>18</num><heading>SECTION 18 Orders and agreements respecting illegitimate children.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>18.</xhtml:b>(1) Where an adoption order is made in respect of an infant who is illegitimate, then subject to this section, any order, decree or agreement whereby the father of the infant is required or has undertaken to make payments specifically for the benefit of the infant shall cease to have effect, but without prejudice to the recovery of any arrears which are due under the decree, order or agreement at the date of the adoption order. 
<xhtml:p>(2) Where an infant to whom any such order, decree or agreement as aforesaid relates is adopted by his mother, and the mother is a single woman, the order, decree or agreement shall not cease to have effect by virtue of the foregoing subsection upon the making of the adoption order, but shall cease to have effect if she subsequently marries.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) Where an adoption order is made in respect of an infant committed to the care of a fit person, an approved society or an appointed local authority by an order in force under the Children and Young Persons Act, the last mentioned order shall cease to have effect; and in any such case any contribution order made in respect of the infant shall cease to have effect, but without prejudice to the recovery of any arrears which are due under that order at the date of the adoption order.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11850"><num>19</num><heading>SECTION 19 Intestacies, wills and settlements.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>19.</xhtml:b>(1) Where, at any time after the making of an adoption order, the adopter or the adopted person or any other person dies intestate in respect of any movable or immovable property (other than property subject to an entailed interest under a disposition made before the date of the adoption order), that property shall devolve in all respects as if the adopted person were the child of the adopter born in lawful wedlock and were not the child of any other person. 
<xhtml:p>(2) In any disposition of movable or immovable property made, whether by instrument<xhtml:i>inter vivos</xhtml:i>or by will (including codicil), after the date of an adoption order - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) any reference (whether express or implied) to the child or children of the adopter shall, unless the contrary intention appears, be construed as, or as including, a reference to the adopted person;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) any reference (whether express or implied) to the child or children of the adopted person's natural parents or either of them shall, unless the contrary intention appears, be construed as not being, or as not including, a reference to the adopted person; and</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) any reference (whether express or implied) to a person related to the adopted person in any degree shall, unless the contrary intention appears, be construed as a reference to the person who would be related to him in that degree if he were the child of the adopter born in lawful wedlock and were not the child of any other person.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) Where under any disposition any movable or immovable property or any interest in such property is limited (whether subject to any preceding limitation or charge or not) in such a way that it would, apart from this section, devolve (as nearly as the law permits) along with a dignity or title of honour, then whether or not the disposition contains an express reference to the dignity or title of honour, and whether or not the property or some interest in the property may in some event become severed therefrom, nothing in this section shall operate to sever the property or any interest therein from the dignity, but the property or interest shall devolve in all respects as if this section had not been enacted.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11851"><num>20</num><heading>SECTION 20 Provisions supplementary to section 19.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>20.</xhtml:b>(1) For the purposes of the application of any written law for the time being in force in Kenya to the devolution of any property in accordance with section 19, and for the purposes of the construction of any such disposition as is mentioned in that section, an adopted person shall be deemed to be related to any other person being the child or adopted child of the adopter or (in the case of a joint adoption) of either of the adopters - 
<xhtml:p>(a) where he or she was adopted by two spouses jointly, and that other person is the child or adopted child of both of them, as brother or sister of the whole blood:</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) in any other case, as brother or sister of the half-blood.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) Notwithstanding any rule of law, a disposition made by will or codicil executed before the date of an adoption order shall not be treated for the purposes of section 19 as made after that date by reason only that the will or codicil is confirmed by a codicil executed after that date.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) Notwithstanding anything in section 19, trustees or personal representatives may convey or distribute any movable or immovable property to or among the persons entitled thereto without having ascertained that no adoption order has been made by virtue of which any person is or may be entitled to any interest therein, and shall not be liable to any such person of whose claim they have not had notice at the time of the conveyance or distribution; but nothing in this subsection shall prejudice the right of any such person to follow the property, or any property representing it, into the hands of any person, other than a purchaser for value without notice, who may have received it.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) Where an adoption order is made in respect of a person who has been previously adopted, the previous adoption shall be disregarded for the purposes of section 19 in relation to the devolution of any property on the death of a person dying intestate after the date of the subsequent adoption order and in relation to any disposition of property made after that date.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11852"><num>21</num><heading>SECTION 21 Effect of overseas adoption.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>21.</xhtml:b>(1) Where a person has been adopted (whether Effect of before or after the commencement of this Act) in any place outside Kenya according to the law of that place, and the adoption is one to which this section applies, for the purposes of this Act and all other written laws, the adoption shall have the same effect as an adoption order validly made under this Act, and shall have no other effect. 
<xhtml:p>(2) Subsection (1) shall apply to an adoption in any place outside Kenya, if - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) the adoption order was made by an order of any court of law in any country in the Commonwealth; and</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) in consequence of the adoption, the adopter had, or would have had, immediately following the adoption, according to the law of that place, a right superior to that of any natural parent of the adopted person in respect of the custody of the person; and</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) in consequence of the adoption, the adopter had, immediately following the adoption, according to the law of that place, a right superior to or equal with that of any natural parent in respect of any property of the adopted person which was capable of passing to the parents or any parent of the person in the event of the person dying intestate without other next of kin and domiciled in the place where the adoption was made and a national of the country which had jurisdiction in respect of that place,</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>but not otherwise.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11853"><num>22</num><heading>SECTION 22 Restriction on making arrangements for adoption.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>22.</xhtml:b>(1) No local authority or body of persons shall make any arrangements for the adoption of an infant under the provisions of this Act unless that local authority or body is approved as an adoption society under this Part. 
<xhtml:p>(2) The Minister may by order published in the Gazette prohibit the making of arrangements for the adoption of an infant under the provisions of this Act by any individual persons other than the parents or guardian of an infant, or such other persons or classes of persons as may be prescribed, and any person who contravenes the provisions of such order shall be guilty of an offence and liable to imprisonment for a term not exceeding six months or to a fine not exceeding six thousand shillings or to both.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) Any local authority or other corporate body of persons, or any person who takes part in the management or control of an unincorporated body of persons, which makes arrangements for the adoption of an infant in contravention of subsection (1) shall be guilty of an offence.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) Any local authority or other corporate body guilty of an offence under this section shall be liable to a fine not exceeding twelve thousand shillings.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(5) Any person who takes part in the management or control of an unincorporated body of persons which is guilty of an offence under this section, or any person to whom section 31 applies in relation to an offence under this section, shall be liable to imprisonment for a term not exceeding six months or to a fine not exceeding six thousand shillings or to both.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(6) In any proceedings under this section, proof of things done or of words written, spoken or published (whether or not in the presence of any party to the proceedings) by any person taking part in the management or control of a body of persons, or in making arrangements for the adoption of infants on behalf of the body, shall be admissible as evidence of the purpose for which that body exists.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11854"><num>23</num><heading>SECTION 23 Approval of adoption societies.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>23.</xhtml:b>(1) A local authority, or the managing committee or Approval of governing body of any body of persons which exists wholly or in part for the purpose of making arrangements for the adoption of infants, may apply to the Minister for that local authority or body to be approved by him as an adoption society, and the Minister may after making such inquiries as he thinks fit, approve that local authority or body for that purpose and issue a certificate of approval accordingly. 
<xhtml:p>(2) The Minister shall not approve an adoption society under this Part, unless the society is a local authority, or unless he is satisfied, by such evidence as he may reasonably require, that the society is a charitable association.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) The Minister may refuse to approve an adoption society, other than a local authority, under this Part if it appears to him - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) that the activities of the society are not controlled by a committee of members of the society who are responsible to the members of the society;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) that any person proposed to be employed or employed by the society for the purpose of making any arrangements for the adoption of children on behalf of the society is not a fit and proper person to be so employed;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) that the number of competent persons proposed to be employed, or employed, by the society for the purpose aforesaid is insufficient having regard to the extent of the activities of the society in connexion with that purpose;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(d) that any person taking part in the management or control of the society or any member of the society has been convicted of an offence under this Act, or of a breach of any regulations made under this Act; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(e) that it would not be in the public interest to approve the same having regard to the number of adoption societies already approved and functioning in the particular locality.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) The Minister may at any time cancel the certificate of approval of an adoption society, other than a local authority, on any ground, except that mentioned in paragraph (e) of subsection (3), which would entitle him to refuse an application for the approval of the society, or on the ground that the society is no longer a charitable association; and the Minister may at any time cancel the certificate of approval of any adoption society if he is satisfied that it is failing or has failed to discharge properly its functions under this Act.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(5) A local authority which has been approved as an adoption society, or the managing committee or governing body of any adoption society, may, on giving three months' notice to the Minister of their intention to do so, surrender the certificate of approval of the society, and at the expiration of three months from the date of the notice (unless the notice is previously withdrawn) the surrender of the certificate shall take effect, and the local authority or the society shall cease to be an adoption society.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(6) The Minister shall, within one month from the date thereof, cause any grant of a certificate of approval and any notice of the withdrawal of, or intention to surrender, the certificate to be published in the Gazette.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11855"><num>24</num><heading>SECTION 24 Procedure.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>24.</xhtml:b>(1) Where the Minister proposes to refuse an application for a certificate of approval made to him by or on behalf of a local authority or any body of persons or to cancel the certificate of approval of an adoption society, he shall give to it not less than fourteen days' notice in writing of his intention so to do. 
<xhtml:p>(2) Every such notice shall state the grounds on which the Minister intends to refuse the application or to cancel the certificate of approval, as the case may be, and shall contain an intimation that, if within fourteen days after the receipt of the notice the local authority, the body of persons or the adoption society, as the case may be. inform him in writing that it desires so to do, the Minister will, before refusing the application or cancelling the certificate of approval, as the case may be, afford an opportunity of causing representation to be made to him by or on its behalf.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) If the Minister, after giving to the local authority the body of persons or the adoption society, as the case may be, an opportunity of causing such representations as aforesaid to be made, decides to refuse the application for a certificate of approval or to cancel the certificate of approval, as the case may be, he shall give to the same notice in writing of his decision.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) The decision of the Minister shall be final.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11856"><num>25</num><heading>SECTION 25 Functions of adoption societies.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>25.</xhtml:b>The functions of an adoption society shall be - 
<xhtml:p><xhtml:i>(a)</xhtml:i>whenever required by an applicant or a prospective applicant for an adoption order, or by the court or the Minister, to conduct negotiations with any person who, having the care and possession of an infant, is desirous of causing the infant to be adopted, and, in particular, to secure that the parent or guardian of the infant understands the effect, in relation to his rights as a parent or guardian, of the making of an adoption order in respect of the infant;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>(b)</xhtml:i>subject to its having the facilities to do so, to take care and possession of any infant whose parent or guardian is desirous of causing the infant to be adopted, pending arrangements for such adoption;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>(c)</xhtml:i>in the case of every such infant as aforesaid, to make such inquiries and cause such reports to be obtained as the society may think fit, or as the court may direct, for the purpose of ensuring, so far as may be, the suitability of the infant and the person proposing to adopt him respectively and. in particular, to obtain a report on the health of the infant signed by a medical practitioner;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>(d)</xhtml:i>to nominate a member or officer of the society to act as guardian<xhtml:i>ad litem</xhtml:i>to any such infant as aforesaid for the purpose of any adoption proceedings relating to such infant, but without prejudice to the power of the court to appoint any other person to act as guardian<xhtml:i>ad litem</xhtml:i>to the infant in such proceedings;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>(e)</xhtml:i>in so far as the funds at its disposal permit, to make provision for the care and supervision of infants who have been placed by their parents or guardians at the disposition of the society;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>(f)</xhtml:i>to perform such other duties as may be prescribed.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11857"><num>26</num><heading>SECTION 26 Arrangements by adoption societies for adoption</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>26.</xhtml:b>(1) It shall not be lawful for an adoption society by whom arrangements are made for the adoption of an infant to place the infant in the care and person resident in Kenya who proposes to adopt him, whether in pursuance of an adoption order or otherwise if an adoption order in respect of the infant could not lawfully be made in favour of that person. 
<xhtml:p>(2) At any time within three months from the date on which an infant is delivered into the care and possession of a person resident in Kenya in pursuance of arrangements made by an adoption society for the adoption of the infant by that person - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) that person may give notice in writing to the society of his intention not to adopt the infant; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) the society may cause notice in writing to be given to that person of their intention not to allow the infant to remain in his care and possession.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) If at the expiration of the period of three months mentioned in subsection (2) no such notice as is mentioned in that subsection has been given, the person into whose care and possession the infant was delivered shall, within six months after the expiration of that period, either - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) apply to the court for an adoption order in respect of the infant; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) give notice in writing to the society of his intention not to apply for such an order.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) Where any notice is given to an adoption society by any person, or by such a society to any person under subsection (2) or subsection (3), or where an application for an adoption order made by any person pursuant to subsection (3) is refused by the court, that person shall, within seven days after the date on which the notice was given or the application refused, as the case may be cause the infant to be returned to the society, and the society shall receive the infant accordingly:</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Provided that it shall be sufficient compliance with the requirements of this subsection if the infant is delivered by the said person to, and is received by a suitable person nominated for the purpose by the society.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(5) Any person who contravenes the provisions of this section shall be guilty of an offence and liable to imprisonment for a term not exceeding six months or to a fine not exceeding one thousand shillings or to both; and the court by which the offender is convicted may order any infant in respect of whom the offence is committed to be returned to his parents or guardian or to the adoption society.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11858"><num>27</num><heading>SECTION 27 Inspection of books, etc., of adoption societies</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>27.</xhtml:b>(1) The Minister may at any time give notice in writing to any adoption society, or to any officer of such a society, requiring that society or officer to produce to him such books, accounts and other documents relating to the performance by the society of the function of making arrangements for the adoption of infants as he may consider necessary for the exercise of the powers conferred on him by subsection (4) of section 23. 
<xhtml:p>(2) Any such notice may contain a requirement that any information to be furnished in accordance with the notice shall be verified by statutory declaration.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) Any person who fails to comply with the requirements of a notice under this section shall be guilty of an offence and liable to imprisonment for a term not exceeding three months or to a fine not exceeding one thousand shillings or to both.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11859"><num>28</num><heading>SECTION 28 Information to be confidential.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>28.</xhtml:b>(1) Every member or officer of an adoption society and every person having any official duty under or being employed in the administration of this Act, shall regard and deal with all documents and information relating to the adoption or proposed adoption of any infant, or to any such infant, or to the parent or guardian of any such infant or to the proposed adopter of any such infant as secret and confidential. 
<xhtml:p>(2) Every person having possession or control over any such documents or information who at any time communicates any such information or anything contained in any such document to any person - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) other than the court, the Minister, the Registrar-General or any other member or officer of the society; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) otherwise than for the purposes of this Act,</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>shall be guilty of an offence and liable to imprisonment for a term not exceeding six months or to a fine not exceeding two thousand shillings or to both:</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Provided that nothing herein contained shall apply to the communication of any document or information made in good faith in the interest or intended interest of any such infant as aforesaid or of the parent or guardian of, or proposed adopter of, any such infant.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) No officer or member of an adoption society, and no person having any official duty under or being employed in the administration of this Act, shall be required to produce in any court any such document as aforesaid, or to divulge or to communicate to any court any such information as aforesaid, except as may be necessary for the purpose of carrying into effect the provisions of this Act, or in order to bring or assist in the course of a prosecution for any offence under this Act.<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(4) The Minister may by order exempt any person, by name or office, from the provisions of this section</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11860"><num>29</num><heading>SECTION 29 Prohibition of certain payments.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>29.</xhtml:b>(1) Subject to subsection (2) - 
<xhtml:p>(a) any adopter or any parent or guardian to an infant who receives any payment or other reward in consideration of the adoption of an infant under this Act; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) any person who makes or gives or agrees to make or give to any adopter or any parent or guardian of an infant any payment or other reward in consideration of the adoption of any infant under this Act; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) any person who makes arrangements for the adoption of an infant and receives or makes or gives or agrees to receive or make or give any payment or other reward in connexion with the making of the arrangements,</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>shall be guilty of an offence and liable to imprisonment for a term not exceeding six months or to a fine not exceeding four thousand shillings or to both.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) Subsection (1) shall not apply - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) to any payments the making or receipt of which is sanctioned by the court to which an application for an adoption order in respect of an infant is made;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) to any payments made by or on behalf of an adoption society in respect of the maintenance of an infant who has been placed at the disposition of the society;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) to any payments made to an adoption society by the parent or guardian of an infant or by any other person in respect of the maintenance of the infant, so long as the infant is not in the care and possession of a person who has adopted or proposes to adopt him, whether under an adoption order or otherwise, being payments made weekly and at a rate not exceeding such rate as may be prescribed;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(d) to any payments made to an advocate who acts for any party in or in connexion with an application for an adoption order, being payments made in respect of such application; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) to any voluntary contribution made by an adopter or any parent or guardian to an adoption society.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11861"><num>30</num><heading>SECTION 30 Restriction upon advertisements.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>30.</xhtml:b>(1) It shall not be lawful for any advertisement to be published indicating - 
<xhtml:p><xhtml:i>(a)</xhtml:i>that the parent or guardian of an infant desires to cause the infant to be adopted; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>(b)</xhtml:i>that a person desires to adopt an infant; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>(c)</xhtml:i>that any person (not being an adoption society) is willing to make arrangements for the adoption of an infant.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) Any person who causes to be published or knowingly publishes an advertisement in contravention of this section shall be guilty of an offence and liable to a fine not exceeding one thousand shillings.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11862"><num>31</num><heading>SECTION 31 Offences under Parts V and VI</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>31.</xhtml:b>Where any offence under Part V or Part VI or any regulations made thereunder committed by a body corporate is proved to have been committed with the consent or connivance of, or to be attributable to any neglect on the part of, any director, manager, member of the committee, secretary or other officer of the body. he, as well as the body, shall be deemed to be guilty of that offence and shall be liable to be proceeded against and punished accordingly.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11863"><num>32</num><heading>SECTION 32 Service of notices.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>32.</xhtml:b>Any notice under this Act may be served by post.<xhtml:br/></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11864"><num>33</num><heading>SECTION 33 Powers of local authorities.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>33.</xhtml:b>Every local authority shall have power, in connexion with their functions under any written law, to make and participate in arrangements for the adoption of children, but such power shall only be exercised in accordance with the provisions of this Act.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11865"><num>34</num><heading>SECTION 34 Expenses.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>34.</xhtml:b>There shall be defrayed out of moneys provided by Parliament any administrative expenses incurred by the Minister or by any other Minister under this Act.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11866"><num>35</num><heading>SECTION 35 Regulations.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>35.</xhtml:b>The Minister may make regulations for the better carrying out of the provisions and purposes of this Act, and, without prejudice to the generality of the foregoing, for either of the following purposes - 
<xhtml:p>(a) for regulating and maintaining supervision over the activities of adoption societies and persons or bodies of persons purporting to assist in or make arrangements for the adoption of children; and</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) for prescribing any matter authorized or required to be prescribed under this Act, save the matters to be prescribed by rules made under section 12.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11867"><num>36</num><heading>SECTION 36 Exemption.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>36.</xhtml:b>The Minister shall have power, from time to time, by order, either retrospectively, from the passing of this Act or prospectively to exclude from the operation of all or any of the provisions of this Act the members of any race, tribe or sect, in Kenya, or any part of such race, tribe or sect to whom he may consider it impossible or inexpedient to apply such provisions, and may also from time to time revoke any such order, but not so that the revocation shall have any retrospective effect.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11868"><num>37</num><heading>SECTION 37 Adoptions under previous law.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>37.</xhtml:b>Without prejudice to the generality of the application of subsection (3) of section 23 of the Interpretation and General Provisions Act, the provisions of the Second Schedule to this Act shall have effect in relation to the Adoption of Children Ordinance (now repealed).<xhtml:br/></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section></body><outOfLines><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-19061" id="w1096aab1b9b1" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"/></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-19062" id="w1096aab1b9b3" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"/></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11829" id="w1096aab1b9b5" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Short title.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11830" id="w1096aab1b9b7" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Interpretation. 9 of 1967, Sch., 4 of 1978, s. 2.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11831" id="w1096aab1b9b9" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Power to make adoption orders. 4 of 1978, s. 3.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11832" id="w1096aab1b9c11" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Jurisdiction of a Resident Magistrate's Court. 4 of 1978, s. 4.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11833" id="w1096aab1b9c13" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Restrictions on making adoption orders. 4 of 1978. s. 5.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11834" id="w1096aab1b9c15" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Consent to adoption. 4 of 1978, s. 6.  
<xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11835" id="w1096aab1b9c17" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Evidence of consent of parent or guardian. 4 of 1978, s. 7.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11836" id="w1096aab1b9c19" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Functions of court as to adoption orders. 4 of 1978, s. 8.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11837" id="w1096aab1b9c21" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Appointment of provisional guardian. 4 of 1978, s. 9.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11838" id="w1096aab1b9c23" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Consent to future adoption. 4 of 1978, s. 9.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11839" id="w1096aab1b9c25" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Interim orders.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11840" id="w1096aab1b9c27" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Adoption order in respect of infants previously adopted.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11841" id="w1096aab1b9c29" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Custody of infant when order refused.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11842" id="w1096aab1b9c31" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Power to make rules of procedure. 4 of 1978, s. 10.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11843" id="w1096aab1b9c33" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Appointment of guardians  <xhtml:i>ad litem </xhtml:i>4 of 1978, s. 10, 13 of 1980, Sch.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11844" id="w1096aab1b9c35" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Adopted Children Register. 4 of 1978, s. 11. Cap. 21 (1948).</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11845" id="w1096aab1b9c37" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Registration of adoptions. 4 of 1978, s. 12.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11846" id="w1096aab1b9c39" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Amendment of orders and rectification of registers. Cap. 21 (1948).</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11847" id="w1096aab1b9c41" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Rights and duties of parents and capacity to marry.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11848" id="w1096aab1b9c43" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Workmen's compensation. Cap. 236.  
<xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11849" id="w1096aab1b9c45" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Orders and agreements respecting illegitimate children. 4 of 1978, s. 13. Cap. 141.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11850" id="w1096aab1b9c47" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Intestacies, wills and settlements.  
<xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11851" id="w1096aab1b9c49" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Service of documents.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11852" id="w1096aab1b9c51" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Effect of overseas adoption.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11853" id="w1096aab1b9c53" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Restriction on making arrangements for adoption. 4 of 1978, s. 14.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11854" id="w1096aab1b9c55" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Approval of adoption societies.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11855" id="w1096aab1b9c57" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Procedure.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11856" id="w1096aab1b9c59" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Functions of adoption societies.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11857" id="w1096aab1b9c61" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Arrangements by adoption societies for adoption.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11858" id="w1096aab1b9c63" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Inspection of books, etc., of adoption societies.  
<xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11859" id="w1096aab1b9c65" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Information to be confidential. 4 of 1978, s. 15.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11860" id="w1096aab1b9c67" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Prohibition of certain payments. 4 of 1978, s. 17.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11861" id="w1096aab1b9c69" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Restriction upon advertisements.  
<xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p> </xhtml:p><xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11862" id="w1096aab1b9c71" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Offences under Parts V and VI. 4 of 1978, s. 18.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11863" id="w1096aab1b9c73" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Service of notices.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11864" id="w1096aab1b9c75" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Powers of local authorities.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11865" id="w1096aab1b9c77" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Expenses.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11866" id="w1096aab1b9c79" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Regulations.  
<xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11867" id="w1096aab1b9c81" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Exemption.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11868" id="w1096aab1b9c83" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Adoptions under previous law. Cap.2. Cap. 21 (1948).</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine></outOfLines></act></akomaNtoso>