<akomaNtoso xmlns:an="http://www.akomantoso.org/1.0"><act contains="singleVersion"><meta><identification source="#kenyalaw"><FRBRWork><FRBRthis value="/ke/act/1111-11-11/15/main"/><FRBRuri value="/ke/act/1111-11-11/15"/><FRBRdate date="1111-11-11" name="Generation"/><FRBRauthor as="#author" href="#parliament"/><components><component href="#emain" id="wmain" name="main" showAs="Main Document"/></components></FRBRWork><FRBRExpression><FRBRthis value="/ke/act/1111-11-11/15/eng@/main"/><FRBRuri value="/ke/act/1111-11-11/15/eng@"/><FRBRdate date="1111-11-11" name="Generation"/><FRBRauthor as="#author" href="#parliament"/><components><component href="#mmain" id="emain" name="main" showAs="Main Document"/></components></FRBRExpression><FRBRManifestation><FRBRthis value="/ke/act/1111-11-11/15/eng@/main.xml"/><FRBRuri value="/ke/act/1111-11-11/15/eng@/.akn"/><FRBRdate date="1111-11-11" name="Generation"/><FRBRauthor as="#author" href="#parliament"/><components><component href="#mmain" id="mmain" name="main" showAs="Main Document"/></components></FRBRManifestation></identification><publication date="1111-11-11" name="" showAs=""/><lifecycle source="#bungeni"><event date="1111-11-11" id="e1" source="#ro1" type="generation"/></lifecycle><references source="#kenyalaw"><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActTitle" id="TheActTitle" showAs="Act Title"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActLongTitle" id="TheActLongTitle" showAs="Act Description"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/AssentDate" id="AssentDate" showAs="Assent Date"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/CommencementDate" id="CommencementDate" showAs="Commencement Date"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActNumber" id="TheActNumber" showAs="Act Number"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActID" id="TheActID" showAs="Act ID"/><TLCConcept href="http://bungeni-lexmigrate.googlecode.com" id="bungeni" showAs="Lex Migrator"/><TLCConcept href="http://kenyalaw.org" id="kenyalaw" showAs="Kenya Law"/></references><proprietary xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" source="#kenyalaw"><kl:meta name="gokcatid" num="3"/><kl:meta name="gokcatname">Courts and Officers of the Court</kl:meta><kl:meta name="lexyy" num="1111"/><kl:meta name="lexmm" num="11"/><kl:meta name="lexdd" num="11"/></proprietary></meta><preface><block name="preface"><docTitle id="ActTitle" refersTo="#TheActTitle">Oaths and Statutory Declarations</docTitle><docTitle id="ActLongTitle" refersTo="#TheActLongTitle">An Act of Parliament to provide for the appointment of commissioners for oaths, and to make provision in regard to the administering of oaths and the taking of statutory declarations</docTitle><docDate date="1111-11-11" refersTo="#CommencementDate">Nov 11, 1111</docDate><docDate date="1111-11-11" refersTo="#AssentDate">Nov 11, 1111</docDate><docNumber id="ActNumber" refersTo="#TheActNumber">15</docNumber><docNumber id="ActIdentifier" refersTo="#TheActID">16</docNumber></block></preface><preamble><p>ARRANGEMENT OF SECTIONS</p><toc><tocItem href="#part-613" level="0">I PRELIMINARY</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10211" level="2">1 Short title.</tocItem><tocItem href="#part-614" level="0">II COMMISSIONERS FOR OATHS</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10212" level="2">2 Appointment of commissioners for oaths.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10213" level="2">3 Commissioner for oaths to sign roll.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10214" level="2">4 Powers of commissioner for oaths.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10215" level="2">5 Particulars to be stated in jurat or attestation clause.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10216" level="2">6 Rules of court under Part.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10217" level="2">7 Penalty for unlawfully acting as commissioner for oaths.</tocItem><tocItem href="#part-615" level="0">III STATUTORY DECLARATIONS</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10218" level="2">8 Power to take declarations.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10219" level="2">9 Fees payable on declarations.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10220" level="2">10 Mode of referring to declaration.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10221" level="2">11 Penalty for false declaration.</tocItem><tocItem href="#part-616" level="0">IV POWERS OF MAGISTRATES AND CERTAIN COURT OFFICERS</tocItem><tocItem href="#part-617" level="0">V OATHS BY AFRICANS</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10222" level="2">12 Powers of magistrates and certain court officers to administer oaths.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10223" level="2">13 Oaths by Africans.</tocItem><tocItem href="#part-618" level="0">VI OATHS AND AFFIRMATIONS</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10224" level="2">14 Authority to administer oaths and affirmations.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10225" level="2">15 When affirmation may be made instead of oath.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10226" level="2">16 Form of affirmation.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10227" level="2">17 Persons by whom oaths and affirmations to be made.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10228" level="2">18 Forms of oath.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10229" level="2">19 Evidence of children of tender years.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10230" level="2">20 Power of court to tender certain oaths.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10231" level="2">21 Validity of oath not affected by absence of religious belief.</tocItem></toc></preamble><body><part id="part-613"><num>I</num><heading>PART I PRELIMINARY</heading><section id="section-10211"><num>1</num><heading>SECTION 1 Short title.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>PART I-PRELIMINARY</xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>1. </xhtml:b>This Act may be cited as the Oaths and Statutory Declarations Act. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section></part><part id="part-614"><num>II</num><heading>PART II COMMISSIONERS FOR OATHS</heading><section id="section-10212"><num>2</num><heading>SECTION 2 Appointment of commissioners for oaths.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>PART II-COMMISSIONERS FOR OATHS</xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>2.&#160; </xhtml:b>(1) The Chief Justice may, by commission signed by him, appoint persons being practising advocates to be commissioners for oaths, and may revoke any such appointment. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) Each commission by which any commissioner for oaths is appointed shall bear a stamp of the value of thirty shillings, to be paid for by the commissioner for oaths therein named; but no other charge or fee shall be made or be payable in respect of the appointment or in respect of anything required to be done to perfect it. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) After the commission has been signed and stamped the appointment of the person therein named as a commissioner for oaths shall be forthwith published in the Gazette. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-10213"><num>3</num><heading>SECTION 3 Commissioner for oaths to sign roll.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>3. </xhtml:b>Every advocate appointed a commissioner for oaths shall, on appointment, sign a roll, which shall be kept by the Registrar of the High Court.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-10214"><num>4</num><heading>SECTION 4 Powers of commissioner for oaths.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>4. </xhtml:b>(1) A commissioner for oaths may, by virtue of his commission, in any part of Kenya, administer any oath or take any affidavit for the purpose of any court or matter in Kenya, including matters ecclesiastical and matters relating to the registration of any instrument, whether under an Act or otherwise, and take any bail or recognizance in or for the purpose of any civil proceeding in the High Court or any subordinate court: 
<xhtml:p>Provided that a commissioner for oaths shall not exercise any of the powers given by this section in any proceeding or matter in which he is the advocate for any of the parties to the proceeding or concerned in the matter, or clerk to any such advocate, or in which he is interested. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) A commissioner for oaths shall, in the exercise of any of the powers mentioned in subsection (1), be entitled to charge and be paid such fees as may be authorized by any rules of court for the time being. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-10215"><num>5</num><heading>SECTION 5 Particulars to be stated in jurat or attestation clause.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>5. </xhtml:b>Every commissioner for oaths before whom any oath or affidavit is taken or made under this Act shall state truly in the jurat or attestation at what place and on what date the oath or affidavit is taken or made.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-10216"><num>6</num><heading>SECTION 6 Rules of court under Part.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>6. </xhtml:b>The Chief Justice may make rules of court for the better carrying into effect of this Part and for fixing the amount of the fees payable to commissioners for oaths.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-10217"><num>7</num><heading>SECTION 7 Penalty for unlawfully acting as commissioner for oaths.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>7. </xhtml:b>Any person who holds himself out as a commissioner for oaths or receives any fee or reward as a commissioner for oaths shall, unless he has been appointed as such under this Act, be guilty of an offence and, in addition to any other penalty or punishment to which he may be liable by any law in force, be liable to a fine not exceeding six hundred shillings, and for a second offence, in addition to any other penalty or punishment, shall be liable to a fine of two thousand shillings or imprisonment for a term not exceeding six months or to both such fine and imprisonment.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section></part><part id="part-615"><num>III</num><heading>PART III STATUTORY DECLARATIONS</heading><section id="section-10218"><num>8</num><heading>SECTION 8 Power to take declarations.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>8. </xhtml:b>A magistrate or commissioner for oaths may take the declaration of any person voluntarily making and subscribing it before him in the form in the Schedule.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-10219"><num>9</num><heading>SECTION 9 Fees payable on declarations.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>9. </xhtml:b>Whenever any declaration is made and subscribed by any person under this Act, the same fees or fee shall be payable as would have been payable on the taking or making of any legal oath, solemn affirmation or affidavit.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-10220"><num>10</num><heading>SECTION 10 Mode of referring to declaration.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>10.&#160; </xhtml:b>A declaration made under this Act may be referred to in any Act or other legal document as a statutory declaration.<xhtml:br/></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-10221"><num>11</num><heading>SECTION 11 Penalty for false declaration.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>11. </xhtml:b>If any person knowingly and wilfully makes any statement which is false in a material particular in a statutory declaration he shall be guilty of an offence and liable to imprisonment for a term not exceeding two years or to a fine not exceeding two thousand shillings, or to both such imprisonment and fine.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section></part><part id="part-616"><num>IV</num><heading>PART IV POWERS OF MAGISTRATES AND CERTAIN COURT OFFICERS</heading></part><part id="part-617"><num>V</num><heading>PART V OATHS BY AFRICANS</heading><section id="section-10222"><num>12</num><heading>SECTION 12 Powers of magistrates and certain court officers to administer oaths.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>PART IV-POWERS OF MAGISTRATES AND CERTAIN COURT OFFICERS</xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>12. </xhtml:b>A magistrate, the Registrar of the High Court, a deputy registrar and a district registrar may administer any oath or affirmation or take any affidavit or statutory declaration (voluntarily made and subscribed in accordance with the provisions of Part III) which might lawfully be administered or taken by a commissioner for oaths appointed under Part II. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-10223"><num>13</num><heading>SECTION 13 Oaths by Africans.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>PART V-OATHS BY AFRICANS</xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>13.&#160; </xhtml:b>Any African, not being a Christian or a Mohammedan, required by law to take an oath shall take the oath in the form common among and held binding by the members of the tribe to which such African belongs, and when such African belongs to a tribe the members of which hold no form of oath binding upon them he shall be required to make solemn affirmation in the form now in use. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section></part><part id="part-618"><num>VI</num><heading>PART VI OATHS AND AFFIRMATIONS</heading><section id="section-10224"><num>14</num><heading>SECTION 14 Authority to administer oaths and affirmations.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>PART VI-OATHS AND AFFIRMATIONS</xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>14. </xhtml:b>All courts and persons having by law or consent of the parties authority to receive evidence are authorized to administer, by themselves or by an officer empowered by them in that behalf, oaths and affirmations in discharge of the duties or in exercise of the powers imposed or conferred upon them by law.<xhtml:br/></xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-10225"><num>15</num><heading>SECTION 15 When affirmation may be made instead of oath.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>15. </xhtml:b>Every person upon objecting to being sworn, and stating, as the ground of such objection, either that he has no religious belief or that the taking of an oath is contrary to his religious belief, shall be permitted to make his solemn affirmation instead of taking an oath in all places and for all purposes where an oath is required by law, which affirmation shall be of the same effect as if he had taken the oath.<xhtml:br/></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-10226"><num>16</num><heading>SECTION 16 Form of affirmation.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>16.&#160; </xhtml:b>Every affirmation shall be as follows: "I,<xhtml:em> A.B</xhtml:em>., do solemnly, sincerely and truly declare and affirm," and then proceed with the words of the oath prescribed by law, omitting any words of imprecation or calling to witness.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-10227"><num>17</num><heading>SECTION 17 Persons by whom oaths and affirmations to be made.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>17. </xhtml:b>Subject to the provisions of section 19, oaths or affirmations shall be made by - 
<xhtml:p>(<xhtml:i>a</xhtml:i>) all persons who may lawfully be examined, or give, or be required to give, evidence by or before any court or person having by law or consent of parties authority to examine such persons or to receive evidence; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(<xhtml:i>b</xhtml:i>) interpreters of questions put to, and evidence given by, witnesses. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-10228"><num>18</num><heading>SECTION 18 Forms of oath.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>18.&#160; </xhtml:b>All oaths made under section 17 of this Act or section 151 of the Criminal Procedure Code shall be administered according to such forms as the Chief Justice may by rules of court prescribe, and until any such forms are so prescribed such oaths shall be administered according to the forms now in use.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-10229"><num>19</num><heading>SECTION 19 Evidence of children of tender years.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>19.&#160; </xhtml:b>(1) Where, in any proceedings before any court or person having by law or consent of parties authority to receive evidence, any child of tender years called as a witness does not, in the opinion of the court or such person, understand the nature of an oath, his evidence may be received, though not given upon oath, if, in the opinion of the court or such person, he is possessed of sufficient intelligence lo justify the reception of the evidence, and understands the duty of speaking the truth; and his evidence in any proceedings against any person for any offence, though not given on oath, but otherwise taken and reduced into writing in accordance with section 233 of the Criminal Procedure Code, shall be deemed to be a deposition within the meaning of that section. 
<xhtml:p>(2) If any child whose evidence is received under subsection (1) wilfully gives false evidence in such circumstances that he would, if the evidence had been given on oath, have been guilty of perjury, he shall be guilty of an offence and liable to be dealt with as if he had been guilty of an offence punishable in the case of an adult with imprisonment. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-10230"><num>20</num><heading>SECTION 20 Power of court to tender certain oaths.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>20. </xhtml:b>If any party to, or witness in, any judicial proceedings offers to give evidence on oath or affirmation in any form common amongst, or held binding by, persons of the race or persuasion to which he belongs and not repugnant to justice or decency, and not purporting to affect any third person, the court may, if it thinks fit, notwithstanding anything hereinbefore contained, tender such oath or affirmation to him.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-10231"><num>21</num><heading>SECTION 21 Validity of oath not affected by absence of religious belief.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>21. </xhtml:b>Where an oath has been duly administered and taken, the fact that the person to whom it was administered had, at the time of taking the oath, no religious belief shall not for any purpose affect the validity of the oath.<xhtml:br/></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section></part></body><outOfLines><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10211" id="w172aab1b9b1" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Short title.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10212" id="w172aab1b9b3" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Appointment of commissioners for oaths.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10213" id="w172aab1b9b5" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Commissioner for oaths to sign roll.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10214" id="w172aab1b9b7" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Powers of commissioner for oaths.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10215" id="w172aab1b9b9" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Particulars to be stated in jurat or attestation clause.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10216" id="w172aab1b9c11" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Rules of court under Part.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10217" id="w172aab1b9c13" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Penalty for unlawfully acting as commissioner for oaths.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10218" id="w172aab1b9c15" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Power to take declarations.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10219" id="w172aab1b9c17" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Fees payable on declarations.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10220" id="w172aab1b9c19" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Mode of referring to declaration.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10221" id="w172aab1b9c21" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Penalty for false declaration.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10222" id="w172aab1b9c23" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Powers of magistrates and certain court officers to administer oaths. 20 of 1956, s.2.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10223" id="w172aab1b9c25" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Oaths by Africans.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10224" id="w172aab1b9c27" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Authority to administer oaths and affirmations. 42 of l954, s.2.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10225" id="w172aab1b9c29" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>When affirmation may be made instead of oath. 42of l954, s.2.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10226" id="w172aab1b9c31" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Form of affirmation. 42 of 1954, s.2.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10227" id="w172aab1b9c33" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Persons by whom oaths and affirmations to be made. 42 of 1954, s.2.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10228" id="w172aab1b9c35" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Forms of oath. 42 of 1954, s.2, 27 of 1961, Sch. Cap.75.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10229" id="w172aab1b9c37" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Evidence of children of tender years.42 of 1954, s.2, 46 of 1963, 2nd Sch. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10230" id="w172aab1b9c39" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Power of court to tender certain oaths. 42 of 1954, s.2.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10231" id="w172aab1b9c41" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Validity of oaths not affected by absence of religious belief. 42 of 1954, s.2.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine></outOfLines></act></akomaNtoso>