<akomaNtoso xmlns:an="http://www.akomantoso.org/1.0"><act contains="singleVersion"><meta><identification source="#kenyalaw"><FRBRWork><FRBRthis value="/ke/act/1981-05-08/20/main"/><FRBRuri value="/ke/act/1981-05-08/20"/><FRBRdate date="1981-05-08" name="Generation"/><FRBRauthor as="#author" href="#parliament"/><components><component href="#emain" id="wmain" name="main" showAs="Main Document"/></components></FRBRWork><FRBRExpression><FRBRthis value="/ke/act/1981-05-08/20/eng@/main"/><FRBRuri value="/ke/act/1981-05-08/20/eng@"/><FRBRdate date="1981-05-08" name="Generation"/><FRBRauthor as="#author" href="#parliament"/><components><component href="#mmain" id="emain" name="main" showAs="Main Document"/></components></FRBRExpression><FRBRManifestation><FRBRthis value="/ke/act/1981-05-08/20/eng@/main.xml"/><FRBRuri value="/ke/act/1981-05-08/20/eng@/.akn"/><FRBRdate date="1981-05-08" name="Generation"/><FRBRauthor as="#author" href="#parliament"/><components><component href="#mmain" id="mmain" name="main" showAs="Main Document"/></components></FRBRManifestation></identification><publication date="1981-05-08" name="" showAs=""/><lifecycle source="#bungeni"><event date="1981-05-08" id="e1" source="#ro1" type="generation"/></lifecycle><references source="#kenyalaw"><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActTitle" id="TheActTitle" showAs="Act Title"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActLongTitle" id="TheActLongTitle" showAs="Act Description"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/AssentDate" id="AssentDate" showAs="Assent Date"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/CommencementDate" id="CommencementDate" showAs="Commencement Date"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActNumber" id="TheActNumber" showAs="Act Number"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActID" id="TheActID" showAs="Act ID"/><TLCConcept href="http://bungeni-lexmigrate.googlecode.com" id="bungeni" showAs="Lex Migrator"/><TLCConcept href="http://kenyalaw.org" id="kenyalaw" showAs="Kenya Law"/></references><proprietary xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" source="#kenyalaw"><kl:meta name="gokcatid" num="3"/><kl:meta name="gokcatname">Courts and Officers of the Court</kl:meta><kl:meta name="lexyy" num="1981"/><kl:meta name="lexmm" num="5"/><kl:meta name="lexdd" num="8"/></proprietary></meta><preface><block name="preface"><docTitle id="ActTitle" refersTo="#TheActTitle">Court Brokers (Repealed)</docTitle><docTitle id="ActLongTitle" refersTo="#TheActLongTitle">An Act of Parliament to provide for the control of court brokers and for purposes incidental thereto and connected therewith</docTitle><docDate date="1981-05-08" refersTo="#CommencementDate">May 8, 1981</docDate><docDate date="1111-11-11" refersTo="#AssentDate">Nov 11, 1111</docDate><docNumber id="ActNumber" refersTo="#TheActNumber">20</docNumber><docNumber id="ActIdentifier" refersTo="#TheActID">22</docNumber></block></preface><preamble><p>ARRANGEMENT OF SECTIONS</p><toc><tocItem href="#section-19137" level="2"> THE COURT BROKERS RULES</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10031" level="2">1 Short title.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10032" level="2">2 Interpretation.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10033" level="2">3 Prohibition against unlicensed court brokers.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10034" level="2">4 Court Brokers Licensing Board.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10035" level="2">5 Meetings of the Board.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10036" level="2">6 Functions of the Board.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10037" level="2">7 Revenue.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10038" level="2">8 Eligibility for licence.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10039" level="2">9 Application for grant of licence.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10040" level="2">10 Conditions applicable to grant of licence.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10041" level="2">11 Refusal to grant licence.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10042" level="2">12 Form of licence.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10043" level="2">13 Duplicate licence.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10044" level="2">14 Renewal of licence.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10045" level="2">15 Fee.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10046" level="2">16 Duration of licence.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10047" level="2">17 Revocation of licence.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10048" level="2">18 Suspension of licence.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10049" level="2">19 Application to set aside suspension.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10050" level="2">20 Licence not transferable.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10051" level="2">21 Amendment of licence.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10052" level="2">22 Register of licences.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10053" level="2">23 Penalty.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10054" level="2">24 Power to make rules.</tocItem></toc></preamble><body><section id="section-19137"><num/><heading>SECTION  THE COURT BROKERS RULES</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Rules under section 24 THE COURT BROKERS RULES PART I - PRELIMINARY L.N.70/1981, L.N.185/1981, L.N.118/1983, L.N. 98/1984. Citation. 1. These Rules may be cited as the Court Brokers Rules. Interpretation. Cap. 531. 2. In these Rules, unless the context otherwise requires - "accountant" means the holder of a practising certificate under section 21 of the Accountants Act; "judgment creditor" includes a person in whose favour a decree has been passed or an order of a court capable of execution has been made; "Judgment debtor" includes a person against whom a decree has been passed or an order of a court capable of execution has been made. Application for licence. Cap. 526. 3. (1) An application for a licence made under section 9 of the Act shall be in a form approved by the Board and shall be accompanied by - (a) a fee of one hundred shillings; (b) a letter of recommendation from a chief magistrate, senior resident magistrate or resident magistrate and a letter of recommendation from an advocate of not less than five years standing; (c) a cash deposit of Sh. 20,000 or a guarantee from a bank or insurance company acceptable to the Board in the same sum; (d) evidence that the applicant is literate in both English and Swahili; (e) an unlimited licence issued under section 7 of the Auctioneers Act; (f) evidence that the applicant has available to him secure premises sufficient to store and auction goods seized in execution; and (g) evidence that the applicant has a working knowledge of the rules of court applicable to the attachment and sale of property. (2) Each letter of recommendation required under paragraph (1) (b) shall state the period of time that the referee has known the applicant and those letters of recommendation may be used to supply the evidence required by paragraph (1) (d), (f) and (g). Fees for renewal and amendment of licences. 4. (1) An application for the renewal or amendment of a licence, or for the issue of a duplicate licence, shall be accompanied by the fee prescribed in the First Schedule. (2) Except as otherwise provided in the Act, a person who inspects the register of licences shall pay the fee prescribed in the First Schedule. PART II - ACCOUNTS Judgment creditors' account. 5. (1) Subject to this rule, a court broker shall maintain a judgment creditors' account or accounts into which he shall without delay pay all judgment creditors' money held or received by him. (2) There may be paid into a judgment creditors' account - (a) money belonging to the court broker necessary to maintain the account; (b) money to replace any sum drawn from the account in contravention of these Rules; and (c) a cheque or draft received by the court broker which under rule 6 he is entitled to split but does not split. (3) A court broker need not pay into a judgment creditors' account judgment creditors' money held or received by him which - (a) is received by him in the form of cash and is without delay paid in cash in the ordinary course of business to a court; or (b) is received by him in the form of a cheque or draft and is, without delay, endorsed over and delivered in the ordinary course of business to a court and is not cashed or passed through a bank account by the court broker. (4) A court broker shall only pay into a judgment creditors' account money which he is by these Rules permitted or required to pay in. (5) A court broker who fails to maintain a judgment creditors' account shall be guilty of an offence. Splitting cheque and drafts. 6. (1) Where a court broker holds or receives a cheque or draft which includes judgment creditors' money - (a) he may where practicable split the cheque or draft and, if he does so, he shall deal with each part thereof as if he had received a separate cheque or draft in respect of that part; or (b) if he does not split the cheque or draft, he shall pay it into a judgment creditors' account. (2) Money which is not judgment creditors' money but which is paid into a judgment creditors account, other than under rule 5 (2) (b), shall be paid out as soon as reasonably possible. Withdrawals from judgment creditors' account 7. (1) Subject to rule 8, a court broker may withdraw from a judgment creditors' account - (a) money properly required for payment to a court; (b) money properly required for a payment authorized by court; (c) money properly required for or towards payment of the court broker's charges where details thereof have been delivered to the court in accordance with rule 22; (d) money paid into the account in contravention of these Rules; (e) money paid into the account under rule 5 (2) (a); and (f) money not being judgment creditors' money paid into the account under rule 6 (1) (b). (2) A cheque drawn upon a judgment creditors' account shall bear on its face the words "judgment creditors' account". (3) A court broker shall not withdraw from a judgment creditors' account any sum in excess of the amount held for the time being in the account for the credit of the judgment creditor in respect of whom the drawing is proposed to be made. (4) No money shall be withdrawn from a judgment creditors' account under any of sub-paragraphs (c), (d), (e) and (f) of paragraph (1) except by a cheque drawn in favour of the court broker. (5) No money shall be withdrawn from a judgment creditors, account other than in accordance with this rule. (6) A court broker who, without reasonable excuse, fails to comply with this rule shall be guilty of an offence. Books of account. 8. (1) A court broker shall keep properly maintained books of account showing - (a) every receipt by him of judgment creditors' money, in respect of each judgment creditor; (b) every payment or application by him of or from judgment creditors' money, in respect of each judgment creditor; (c) the amount held by him for the time being in a judgment creditors' account, in respect of each judgment creditor; and (d) the moneys expended by him for and the costs charged by him to, each judgment creditor. (2) The books of account referred to in paragraph (1) shall include - (a) a cash book and a ledger each of which shall record - (i) every transaction involving judgment creditors money, or other money dealt with by the court broker through a judgment creditors' account: and (ii) every transaction involving the court broker's own money and relating to his activities as a court broker; (b) a record, showing particulars of all charges levied by the court broker. (3) A cash book or ledger kept under this rule may be a loose leaf book or may consist of cards or other permanent records necessary for the operation of a mechanical system of book-keeping. (4) The details required under paragraph (2) (a) (i) and (2) (a) (ii) shall be recorded separately, either - (a) in separate volumes of the cash book and ledger; or (b) in one cash book and one ledger, each of which is ruled with two principal money columns on each side. (5) A court broker who, without reasonable excuse, fails to comply with this rule shall be guilty of an offence. Preservation of records. 9. (1) A court broker shall preserve for a least six years from the date of the last entry therein all books of account required to be kept by him under rule 11. (2) A court broker who, without reasonable excuse, fails to comply with this rule shall be guilty of an offence and liable to a fine not exceeding five thousand shillings. Reporting of records lost or destroyed. 10. A court broker shall take reasonable precautions to ensure the safety of all books of account which he is required by rule 8 to keep and in the event of any books being lost, destroyed or materially damaged, shall forthwith give notice thereof to the Board, together with a written report on the circumstances. Accountant's certificate; 11. Subject to these Rules a court broker shall every year deliver to the Board a certificate in a form approved by the Board signed by an accountant and complying with these Rules. Who may not give an accountant's certificate. Cap. 531. 12. (1) An accountant is not qualified to give an accountant's certificate if - (a) he has at any time during the accounting period, or subsequently but before giving the certificate, been a partner, clerk or servant of the court broker; or (b) he is subject to a notice of disqualification under paragraph (2). (2) Where the Board is satisfied that (a) the accountant has been found guilty by the Disciplinary Committee appointed under section 29 of the Accountants Act of professional misconduct; (b) the accountant has deliberately or negligently failed to comply with this Part, it may notify the accountant concerned in writing and on receipt of that notice the accountant shall not be qualified to give a certificate. Procedure on examination of accounts. 13. (1) Before signing a certificate an accountant shall - (a) make a general test examination of the books of account of the court broker; (b) ascertain whether a judgment creditors' account is kept; (c) make a general test examination of the bank pass books and statements kept in relation to the business of the court broker; and (d) make a comparison, as at no fewer than two dates selected by the accountant, between - (i) the liabilities of the court broker to judgment creditors as shown by his books of account; and (ii) the balance standing to the credit of the judgment creditors' account. Dispensing with the requirements of rule 11. 14. The Board may dispense with the requirements of rule 11 if it is satisfied that a court broker has not held or received judgment creditors' money since the delivery by him of his last certificate or since he was licensed, whichever is the later. Duration of an accounting period. 15. Subject to rule 16, the accounting period specified in an accountants' certificate shall - (a) begin at the expiry of the last proceeding accounting period for which an accountant's certificate has been delivered; (b) cover not less than twelve months; (c) terminate not more than three months before the date of delivery of the certificate to the Board; and (d) where possible, correspond to a period or consecutive periods for which the accounts of the court broker are ordinarily prepared. Commencement of an accounting period. 16. (1) An accounting period shall begin on - (a) the date when a licence is granted to a court broker who has not previously held a licence; (b) the date of commencement of an authorization to a court broker to act without a licence under section 27 of the Act; or (c) the date when an exemption from delivering a certificate, given to a court broker under rule 14, expires. (2) An accounting period shall, where a court broker retires from his business and is obliged to deliver a final accountant's certificate, end on the date when he last held judgment creditors' money and may last less than twelve months. Separate accounting periods. 17. A court broker who has two or more places of business may adopt separate accounting periods in respect of each place of business. Application of Part II. 18. This Part shall not apply to a person executing an order of a court issued to him under section 3 (2) of the Act. PART III - ATTACHMENT AND SALE OF PROPERTY Application of Part III. Cap. 536. 19. (1) This Part shall apply to the attachment and sale of movable and immovable property under warrants and orders issued by the civil courts of Kenya, but shall not apply to sales in suits on mortgages. (2) This Part doss not affect and is not affected by any rules made under the Auctioneers Act. Fees. 20. (1) Fees for the execution of warrant and orders of attachment shall be chargeable in accordance with the Second Schedule. (2) Where in proceedings before the High Court a dispute arises as to the amount of fees payable to a court broker, a registrar, as defined in the Civil Procedure Act, may on the application of a party or of the court broker, assess the fees payable. (3) Where in proceedings before subordinate court a dispute arises as to the amount of fees payable to a court broker, a magistrate may, on the application of a party or of the court broker, assess the fees payable. (4) An appeal shall lie from a decision of a registrar or a magistrate under sub-rules (2) or (3), to a judge in chambers. (5) The memorandum of appeal, setting out the grounds of the appeal, shall be filed within seven days of the decision of the registrar or magistrate. Preparation of inventory. 21. (1) Where a court broker attaches property, he shall, if the judgment debtor or his agent is present, request him to sign an inventory of the items attached. (2) If the judgment debtor or his agent refuses to sign the inventory, the court broker shall sign a certificate to that effect, which he shall forward to the court that passed the warrant to him, together with a copy of the inventory. Register of licences. 22. (1) The Registrar shall keep a register, in a form that he determines, of licences granted and shall record therein in respect of each licence - (a) the particulars required by section 12; (b) particulars of any amendment of the licence made under section 21; (c) particulars of any revocation or suspension of the licence under section 17 or 18; (d) the district or districts to which the licence applies; (e) other particulars the Board may require to be recorded. (2) A person may, during reasonable office hours, and on payment of the prescribed fee. inspect the register of licences. (3) A person who is - (a) a member of the police force, or a public officer, acting in the course of his duty; and (b) a person authorized in writing by the Registrar, may inspect the register without payment. Independent valuation of goods attached. 23. A judgment debtor may, at any time before the property attached is sold, apply to a court for an order that the property be valued by an independent valuer. Register of warrants. 24. (1) A court broker shall keep a register of all warrants and orders passed to him and shall record therein - (a) the number of the case under which the warrant was issued and the name of the court that issued it; (b) the date he received each warrant; (c) the amount he is required by the warrant to recover; (d) the date of return endorsed upon the warrant; (f) the details required by rule 22; (g) the amount realized in respect of each item sold: (h) the date the warrant was returned to the court; (i) the date the proceeds of any sale were forwarded to the court; and (j) the charges levied by the court broker. (2) A court broker who fails to keep a register containing the details required by this rule shall be guilty of an offence. Payment of charges. 25. The judgment debtor shall pay the charges of the court broker, but if the judgment debtor cannot be traced or has no goods upon which execution can be levied, then the judgment creditor shall pay those charges. Insurance. 26. Subject to these Rules, the court broker executing the attachment shall be responsible for the safe custody and insurance of any movable property attached by him until it has been sold or the attachment withdrawn. Procedure when specially authorized. 27. (1) A person issued with an order of the court under section 3 (2) of the Act shall, in addition to complying with rules 21, 22 and 26, forward a list of the property attached together with details of his charges to the Registrar. (2) A person who, without reasonable excuse, fails to comply with this rule shall be guilty of an offence. Payment over of money recovered. 28. (1) A court broker shall pay judgment creditor's money recovered by him under an order of a court to the court that passed the order to him within ten days of the receipt by him of that money. (2) A court broker who fails, without reasonable excuse, to comply with this rule shall be guilty of an offence and liable to a fine not exceeding five thousand shillings. PART IV - DISCIPLINARY HEARINGS When disciplinary action may be taken. 29. The Board may take disciplinary action under this Part against a court broker who - (a) acts unlawfully; (b) acts oppressively or in a manner incompatible with his status as an officer of the court. Form of complaint. 30. A complaint to the Board against a court broker may be made in a form approved by the Board. Procedure on complaint. 31. (1) Upon receipt of a complaint, the Board shall furnish the court broker against whom the complaint is made with a copy of the complaint and any supporting documents. (2) The Board shall fix a day for the hearing of the complaint and shall give twenty-one days notice in writing thereof to each party. Powers of the Board on determination of a complaint. 32. Upon determination of a complaint, the Board may - (a) revoke or suspend a licence; (b) alter the terms of a licence; (c) dismiss the complaint, and may order any party to pay the reasonable costs of the other. PART V - PENALTY Penalty. 33. A person who commits an offence under these Rules for which no other penalty is prescribed shall be liable to a fine not exceeding twenty thousand shillings or to imprisonment not exceeding one year. FIRST SCHEDULE FEES Sh. 1. Upon application for the renewal of a licence...... 100 2. Upon application for the amendment of a licence, or the issue of a duplicate licence ......... 50 3. To inspect the register of licences ............. 20 SECOND SCHEDULE FEES UPON EXECUTION Sh. 1. Upon receipt of a warrant in respect of movable or immovable property .............................................. 100 2. Where there is no property found to attach, or where property to the value of Sh. 1,000 or less is found .................... 200 3. Upon attachment of movable property the following charges may be levied based upon the value placed on the items attached as per itemized inventory (in accordance with rule 22 (1) (a)) or upon the decretal amount, which- ever is less - Per cent Sh. 1,001 to 10,000 ... ... ... ... .... 5 Sh, 10,001 to 50,000 ... ... ... ... ... 3 Sh. 50,001 and over .... ... ... ... ... 1.5 4. In the event of the amount of attachment being tendered to the court broker before any property is attached he shall be entitled to a fee of Sh. 200 and his out-of-pocket expenses, if any. 5. In the event of an attachment of movable property being raised or money tendered any time before sale by the court broker, he shall be entitled to attaching charges in addition to his reasonable out-of-pocket expenses. 6. Upon sale of movable property the following charges may be levied, based upon the amount realized at the sale - Sh. 0 to 50,000 ... ... ... ... ... ... 5 Sh. 50,000 and over ... ... ... ... ... 3 Sh. 7. For storing movable property the court broker may claim one quarter per centum per day of the value placed by him upon the property commencing on the sixteenth day after attachment with a maximum of Sh. 100 per day; but in special cases the Court may increase or decrease the charges. 8. Upon taking possession of immovable property ... ... 200 9. Upon sale of immovable property, the following charges may be levied, based upon the amount realized at the sale - Per cent Sh. 0 to 50,000 ... ... ... ... ... . 5 Sh. 50,001 to 100,000 ... ... ... ... ,,. 2.5 Sh. 100,001 and over ... ... ... .,. ... 1 10. If immovable property is withdrawn from sale after the sale has been advertised, then the court broker shall he entitled to one quarter of the commission to which be would have been entitled had the property been sold for an amount equal to the decretal amount. 11. For taking an inventory of, or transporting movable property and for advertising and insuring movable or immovable property, the court broker shall be awarded such sum as the Court may consider reasonable. 12. Travelling expenses by car may be allowed upon the scale for the time being applicable to Government officers. 13. (1) The Court may increase the fees allowed to a court broker under this Schedule. (2) In exercising its discretion under this paragraph the Court shall have regard to all relevant circumstances of the case, including - (a) the complexity and difficulty or otherwise of the work required to be done; and (b) the skill, specialized knowledge and responsibility required of, and the time and labour expended by, the Court Broker.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-10031"><num>1</num><heading>SECTION 1 Short title.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>1.</xhtml:b>This Act may be cited as the Court Brokers Act.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-10032"><num>2</num><heading>SECTION 2 Interpretation.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>2.</xhtml:b>In this Act, unless the context otherwise requires - 
<xhtml:p>"Board" means the Court Brokers Licensing Board established under section 4; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"court broker" means a person who carries out, or who purports to carry out. the functions of attachment and sale of property under an order of a court, but does not include a bailiff certified under the Distress for Rent Act; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"licence" means a licence in force under this Act; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"place of business" means each separate building and each separate part of a building at which the business of a court broker is carried on; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"Registrar" means the Registrar of the High Court. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-10033"><num>3</num><heading>SECTION 3 Prohibition against unlicensed court brokers.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>3.</xhtml:b>(1) Subject to subsection (2), a person who acts as, or who holds himself out as acting as, a court broker without being licensed under this Act shall be guilty of an offence and liable to a fine not exceeding ten thousand shillings or to imprisonment for a term not exceeding twelve months. 
<xhtml:p>(2) A court may, for exceptional reasons to be recorded by it in writing, issue a warrant of attachment and sale to a person other than a corporate body who is not a licensee but who it is satisfied is able properly to execute the warrant. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-10034"><num>4</num><heading>SECTION 4 Court Brokers Licensing Board.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>4.</xhtml:b>(1) There is hereby constituted the Court Brokers Licensing Board. 
<xhtml:p>(2) The Board shall consist of the following persons appointed by the Chief Justice - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:br/>(a) ................ principal magistrate or chief magistrate, who shall be the chairman; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) two advocates of the High Court of nor less than five years standing one of whom shall, in the absence of the chairman, act as chairman; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) a person who has acted as a court broker for a period of five years immediately preceding his appointment; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(d) five other members. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) A member of the Board shall be appointed for three years but may resign his office by written notice to the Chief Justice. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-10035"><num>5</num><heading>SECTION 5 Meetings of the Board.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>5.</xhtml:b>(1) Meetings of the Board shall be held at least once in each quarter and at any other times appointed by the chairman. 
<xhtml:p>(2) A quorum of the Board shall be five. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) The chairman shall have a deliberative and a casting vote. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) Subject to this section the Board may regulate its own procedure. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-10036"><num>6</num><heading>SECTION 6 Functions of the Board.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>6.</xhtml:b>The functions of the Board shall be - 
<xhtml:p>(a) to consider applications for licences and applications to renew or amend licences; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) to monitor the activities of court brokers; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) to receive and investigate complaints against court brokers; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(d) conduct disciplinary proceedings against court brokers; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(e) to grant, renew, revoke and suspend licences. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-10037"><num>7</num><heading>SECTION 7 Revenue.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>7</xhtml:b>. All moneys received by the Board pursuant to this Act shall be paid into the Consolidated Fund.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-10038"><num>8</num><heading>SECTION 8 Eligibility for licence.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>8.</xhtml:b>(1) A person who has attained the age of twenty-one years and is a Kenya citizen shall be eligible to hold a licence under this Act. 
<xhtml:p>(2) Notwithstanding subsection (1), a person shall not be eligible to hold a licence under this Act if - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) (i) he has been convicted in the ten years preceding his application of an offence involving fraud, dishonesty or immorality and sentenced therefore<xhtml:br/>to a term of imprisonment; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(ii) he has at any time been convicted of an offence under this Act. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) he is a judge or magistrate or is employed in any capacity as an executive or subordinate officer of a court; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) he is a practising advocate. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) A person who obtains a licence knowing that he is not eligible to hold one shall be guilty of an offence and liable to a fine not exceeding ten thousand shillings. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-10039"><num>9</num><heading>SECTION 9 Application for grant of licence.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>9.</xhtml:b>(1) Application for a licence shall be made to the Board and shall identify the place of business in respect of which the licence is requested. 
<xhtml:p>(2) A person who knowingly makes a false statement in connexion with an application for the grant, renewal or amendment of a licence shall be guilty of an offence. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-10040"><num>10</num><heading>SECTION 10 Conditions applicable to grant of licence.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>10.</xhtml:b>(1) The Board shall not grant a licence unless it is satisfied that the applicant is eligible to hold a licence and that he is a fit and proper person. 
<xhtml:p>(2) For the purpose of satisfying itself as to the eligibility and suitability of an applicant, the Board may make any necessary inquiries and in pursuance thereof may serve a notice in writing on the applicant requiring him to furnish to the Board within a period specified in the notice any information that the Board may reasonably require. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-10041"><num>11</num><heading>SECTION 11 Refusal to grant licence.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>11.</xhtml:b>Where the Board refuses to grant a licence it shall serve a notice of refusal, indicating the reasons therefore, on the applicant by registered post or by delivering it to the applicant personally.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-10042"><num>12</num><heading>SECTION 12 Form of licence.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>12.</xhtml:b>(1) A licence shall be in the form to be determined by the Board and shall include - 
<xhtml:p>(a) the full names and identity card number of the person to whom the licence is granted; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) the place of business in respect of which the licence is granted; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) the district or districts to which the licence applies; and </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(d) the date of its expiry. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) The licence shall be displayed in a conspicuous position within the place of business in respect of which it is granted </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-10043"><num>13</num><heading>SECTION 13 Duplicate licence.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>13.</xhtml:b>If the Board is satisfied that a licence has been lost, destroyed or mutilated, it may, on payment of the prescribed fee. issue a duplicate licence.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-10044"><num>14</num><heading>SECTION 14 Renewal of licence.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>14.</xhtml:b>(1) A licensee may, not earlier than three months, nor later than one month, before the date of expiry of his licence, apply to the Board for a renewal thereof. 
<xhtml:p>(2) Where an application for the renewal of a licence is made, the licence shall remain in force until the application is dealt with unless the licence is suspended or revoked under the provisions of this Act. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) The Board may refuse to renew a licence upon any of the grounds upon which it may refuse to grant a licence or revoke a licence under section 10 or 17 and the provisions of subsection (4) of section 17 shall apply to any refusal to renew. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-10045"><num>15</num><heading>SECTION 15 Fee.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>15.</xhtml:b>Where the Board is satisfied as to the eligibility and suitability of an applicant it shall grant or renew a licence on payment of the prescribed fee.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-10046"><num>16</num><heading>SECTION 16 Duration of licence.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>16.</xhtml:b>Subject to this Act - 
<xhtml:p>(a) a licence shall be valid for a period of two years from the date of issue; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) where the licence is renewed it shall be valid for a period of two years from the date of expiry of the previous licence; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) where a licence is suspended by the Board under this Act and the suspension is set aside, the licence shall continue to be valid for the period remaining unexpired thereon at the time the suspension took effect. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-10047"><num>17</num><heading>SECTION 17 Revocation of licence.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>17.</xhtml:b>(1) The Board may revoke a licence upon the determination of a complaint made under the rules or if it is satisfied that the licensee made a statement in or in connection with his application for the grant, amendment or renewal of that licence which he knew to be false or misleading in any material particular or which he did not believe to be true. 
<xhtml:p>(2) The Board shall revoke a licence upon the happening of any event which renders the licensee ineligible to hold a licence. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) The provisions of section 9 of the Probation of Offenders Act shall not apply to this section. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) Where the Board has power to revoke a licence it shall give the licensee sufficient opportunity to show cause why the licence should not be revoked. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(5) Where the Board revokes a licence, it shall serve a notice of revocation, indicating the reasons therefore, on the licensee personally or by registered post and shall publish the notice in the Gazette. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(6) The revocation of the licence shall have effect from the date of service of the notice of revocation which shall be- </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) where the notice is sent by registered post, a date four days after the date of posting; or </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) where the notice is delivered to the holder of the licence personally, the date of delivery. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(7) Where a licence is revoked, the licensee shall forthwith deliver the licence to the Board and a licensee who, without reasonable excuse, the burden of proving which shall lie on him. fails to do so shall be guilty of an offence and liable to a fine not exceeding ten thousand shillings. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-10048"><num>18</num><heading>SECTION 18 Suspension of licence.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>18.</xhtml:b>(1) The Board may suspend a licence for a period not exceeding one year - 
<xhtml:p>(a) if the licensee is charged with an offence involving fraud, dishonesty or immorality; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) if, having received a complaint against the licensee concerning his activities as a court broker, the Board considers it appropriate to suspend the licence pending further investigation of the complaint; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) if the licensee has acted in a manner incompatible with his status as an officer of the court. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(1A) The chairman, if satisfied of the necessity for acting without delay, may for any of the reasons set out in subsection (1) suspend a licence until the next meeting of the Board but such suspension shall not remain in force for a period exceeding six weeks and the chairman shall forthwith serve a notice<xhtml:br/>of the suspension indicating the reasons therefore upon the licensee personally or by registered post. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) Where the Board suspends a licence it shall serve a notice of suspension, indicating the reasons therefore, upon the licensee personally or by registered post and shall publish the notice in the Gazette. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) The suspension shall take effect on the day following the date of service of the notice of suspension which shall be - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) where the notice is sent by registered post, a date four days after the date of posting; or </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) where the notice is delivered to the licensee personally the date of delivery. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-10049"><num>19</num><heading>SECTION 19 Application to set aside suspension.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>19.</xhtml:b>(1) A licensee whose licence is suspended may, within twenty-one days after the date of service of the notice of suspension, apply to the Board to set aside the suspension. 
<xhtml:p>(2) The application shall be in writing and shall state the grounds relied upon. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) After considering the application the Board may set aside, or reduce the period of the suspension or dismiss the application. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) Notice of the decision of the Board, indicating the reasons therefore, shall be served upon the licensee in the same manner as a notice of suspension and the notice shall be published in the Gazette. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(5) The period of suspension shall expire on whichever is the earlier of - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) the date upon which the suspension is set aside; or </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) the date upon which revocation of the licence has effect; or </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) the date fixed by the Board under section 18 or subsection (3) of this section; or </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(d) the date that the licence ceases to be valid by virtue of the provisions of section 16. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-10050"><num>20</num><heading>SECTION 20 Licence not transferable.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>20.</xhtml:b>(1) A licence shall not be transferable. 
<xhtml:p>(2) Upon the death, bankruptcy or other incapacity of a licensee, his personal representative, trustee in bankruptcy or other person acting on his behalf shall return his licence to the Board and shall also return all warrants, whether executed or unexecuted, to the court which sent them to the licensee. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-10051"><num>21</num><heading>SECTION 21 Amendment of licence.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>21.</xhtml:b>A licence may be amended, on application to the Board and after payment of the prescribed fee or on the Board's own motion - 
<xhtml:p>(a) by substituting one place of business for another; or </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) by adding or deleting in the licence a district in which the holder is licensed to act; or </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) in any other manner that the Board may think fit. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-10052"><num>22</num><heading>SECTION 22 Register of licences.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>22.</xhtml:b>(1) The Registrar shall keep a register, in a form that he determines, of licences granted and shall record therein in respect of each licence - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) the particulars required by section 12; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) particulars of any amendment of the licence made under section 21; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) particulars of any revocation or suspension of the licence under section 17 or 18; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(d) the district or districts to which the licence applies; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(e) other particulars the Board may require to be recorded. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) A person may, during reasonable office hours, and on payment of the prescribed fee. inspect the register of licences. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) A person who is - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) a member of the police force, or a public officer, acting in the course of his duty; and </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) a person authorized in writing by the Registrar, may inspect the register without payment. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-10053"><num>23</num><heading>SECTION 23 Penalty.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>23.</xhtml:b>(1) A person who commits an offence under this Act or any rules made thereunder for which no penalty is expressly provided shall be liable to a fine not exceeding twenty thousand shillings or to imprisonment for a term not exceeding one year. 
<xhtml:p>(2) A court broker may be liable, notwithstanding the fact that he has been acquitted of an offence, to disciplinary proceedings under this Act. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-10054"><num>24</num><heading>SECTION 24 Power to make rules.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>24.</xhtml:b>The Chief Justice may make rules for the better implementation of the purposes of this Act and in particular providing for - 
<xhtml:p>(a) the manner of issue, revocation and suspension of licences for court brokers; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) the duties of court brokers when attaching, storing and selling property in execution of a decree; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) the fees payable to court brokers; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(d) the keeping by court brokers of accounts. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section></body><outOfLines><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-19137" id="w242aab1b9b1" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"/></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10031" id="w242aab1b9b3" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Short title.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10032" id="w242aab1b9b5" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Interpretation. Cap. 293.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10033" id="w242aab1b9b7" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Prohibition against unlicensed court brokers.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10034" id="w242aab1b9b9" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Court Brokers Licensing Board. 8 of 1986, s. 2, 18 of 1986, Sch.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10035" id="w242aab1b9c11" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Meetings of the Board.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10036" id="w242aab1b9c13" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Functions of the Board.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10037" id="w242aab1b9c15" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Revenue.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10038" id="w242aab1b9c17" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Eligibility for licence.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10039" id="w242aab1b9c19" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Application for licence.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10040" id="w242aab1b9c21" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Conditions applicable to grant of licence.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10041" id="w242aab1b9c23" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Refusal to grant licence.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10042" id="w242aab1b9c25" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Form of licence.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10043" id="w242aab1b9c27" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Duplicate licence.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10044" id="w242aab1b9c29" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Renewal of licence.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10045" id="w242aab1b9c31" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Fee.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10046" id="w242aab1b9c33" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Duration of licence.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10047" id="w242aab1b9c35" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Revocation of licence. 8 of 1986, s. 3. Cap. 64.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10048" id="w242aab1b9c37" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Suspension of licence.8 of 1986, s. 4.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10049" id="w242aab1b9c39" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Application to set aside suspension.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10050" id="w242aab1b9c41" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Licences not transferable.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10051" id="w242aab1b9c43" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Amendment of licence. 8 of 1986, s. 5.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10052" id="w242aab1b9c45" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Register of licences.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10053" id="w242aab1b9c47" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Penalty.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10054" id="w242aab1b9c49" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Power to make rules.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine></outOfLines></act></akomaNtoso>