<akomaNtoso xmlns:an="http://www.akomantoso.org/1.0"><act contains="singleVersion"><meta><identification source="#kenyalaw"><FRBRWork><FRBRthis value="/ke/act/1950-12-11/113/main"/><FRBRuri value="/ke/act/1950-12-11/113"/><FRBRdate date="1950-12-11" name="Generation"/><FRBRauthor as="#author" href="#parliament"/><components><component href="#emain" id="wmain" name="main" showAs="Main Document"/></components></FRBRWork><FRBRExpression><FRBRthis value="/ke/act/1950-12-11/113/eng@/main"/><FRBRuri value="/ke/act/1950-12-11/113/eng@"/><FRBRdate date="1950-12-11" name="Generation"/><FRBRauthor as="#author" href="#parliament"/><components><component href="#mmain" id="emain" name="main" showAs="Main Document"/></components></FRBRExpression><FRBRManifestation><FRBRthis value="/ke/act/1950-12-11/113/eng@/main.xml"/><FRBRuri value="/ke/act/1950-12-11/113/eng@/.akn"/><FRBRdate date="1950-12-11" name="Generation"/><FRBRauthor as="#author" href="#parliament"/><components><component href="#mmain" id="mmain" name="main" showAs="Main Document"/></components></FRBRManifestation></identification><publication date="1950-12-11" name="" showAs=""/><lifecycle source="#bungeni"><event date="1950-12-11" id="e1" source="#ro1" type="generation"/></lifecycle><references source="#kenyalaw"><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActTitle" id="TheActTitle" showAs="Act Title"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActLongTitle" id="TheActLongTitle" showAs="Act Description"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/AssentDate" id="AssentDate" showAs="Assent Date"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/CommencementDate" id="CommencementDate" showAs="Commencement Date"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActNumber" id="TheActNumber" showAs="Act Number"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActID" id="TheActID" showAs="Act ID"/><TLCConcept href="http://bungeni-lexmigrate.googlecode.com" id="bungeni" showAs="Lex Migrator"/><TLCConcept href="http://kenyalaw.org" id="kenyalaw" showAs="Kenya Law"/></references><proprietary xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" source="#kenyalaw"><kl:meta name="gokcatid" num="12"/><kl:meta name="gokcatname">General Administration</kl:meta><kl:meta name="lexyy" num="1950"/><kl:meta name="lexmm" num="12"/><kl:meta name="lexdd" num="11"/></proprietary></meta><preface><block name="preface"><docTitle id="ActTitle" refersTo="#TheActTitle">Exchange Control (Repealed)</docTitle><docTitle id="ActLongTitle" refersTo="#TheActLongTitle">An Act of Parliament to confer powers, and impose duties and restrictions, in relation to gold, currency, payments, securities, debts and the import, export, transfer and settlement of property, and for purposes connected therewith</docTitle><docDate date="1950-12-11" refersTo="#CommencementDate">Dec 11, 1950</docDate><docDate date="1111-11-11" refersTo="#AssentDate">Nov 11, 1111</docDate><docNumber id="ActNumber" refersTo="#TheActNumber">113</docNumber><docNumber id="ActIdentifier" refersTo="#TheActID">84</docNumber></block></preface><preamble><p>ARRANGEMENT OF SECTIONS</p><toc><tocItem href="#section-18818" level="2"> THE EXCHANGE CONTROL (DECLARATIONS AND EVIDENCE) ORDER</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-18819" level="2"> (FEES) RULES</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-18820" level="2"> (BRANCHES AND RESIDENCE) DIRECTIONS</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7646" level="2">1 Short title.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7647" level="2">2 Interpretation.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7648" level="2">3 Dealings in gold and foreign currency.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7649" level="2">4 Surrender of gold and foreign currency.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7650" level="2">5 Bailees of gold and foreign currency.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7651" level="2">6 Travelers&amp;apos; cheques, etc.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7652" level="2">7 Payments in Kenya.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7653" level="2">8 Payments outside Kenya.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7654" level="2">9 Compensation deals.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7655" level="2">10 Issue of securities.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7656" level="2">11 Transfer of securities and coupons.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7657" level="2">12 Substitution of securities and certificates outside Kenya.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7658" level="2">13 Substitution of securities and certificates outside Kenya.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7659" level="2">14 Payment of capital money outside Kenya.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7660" level="2">15 Duties of person keeping registers.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7661" level="2">16 Additional provisions as to nominee holdings.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7662" level="2">17 Deposit of certificates of title.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7663" level="2">18 Additional provisions as to deposited certificates.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7664" level="2">19 Special provisions as to dealings in certain securities.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7665" level="2">20 Validation of certain transfers.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7666" level="2">21 Application of Part to secondary securities.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7667" level="2">22 Interpretation of Part.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7668" level="2">23 Restrictions on import.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7669" level="2">23A Payment for imports</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7670" level="2">24 General restrictions on export.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7671" level="2">25 Payment for exports</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7672" level="2">25A Withholding e.t.c. of payment for export prohibited.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7673" level="2">25B Provisions relating to export documents.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7674" level="2">25C Payment for services.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7675" level="2">26 Duty to collect certain debts.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7676" level="2">27 Duty not to delay sale or importation of goods.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7677" level="2">28 Property obtained by infringement of Act.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7678" level="2">29 Provisions supplemental to preceding provisions of Part.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7679" level="2">30 Transfer of annuities, policies, etc.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7680" level="2">31 settlements.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7681" level="2">32 Companies.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7682" level="2">33 Exemptions.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7683" level="2">34 Blocked accounts.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7684" level="2">35 Contracts, legal proceedings, etc.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7685" level="2">36 Enforcement and admission.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7686" level="2">37 Application Government.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7687" level="2">38 Treasury orders.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7688" level="2">39 Other powers.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7689" level="2">39A Rules.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7690" level="2">40 Financial provisions.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7691" level="2">41 Branches.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7692" level="2">42 Persons leaving the scheduled territories.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7693" level="2">43 Determination of residence.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7694" level="2">44 Acquisition by Minister of certain securities.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7695" level="2">45 Power of Minister to direct sale of certain securities.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7696" level="2">46 Custody and disposition of documents of title to securities.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7697" level="2">47 Power of Minister to prohibit action on certain orders as to gold, etc.</tocItem></toc></preamble><body><section id="section-18818"><num/><heading>SECTION  THE EXCHANGE CONTROL (DECLARATIONS AND EVIDENCE) ORDER</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:table width="100%"><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%">
    L.N.213/1959. 
  </xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="85%"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>SUBSIDIARY LEGISLATION</xhtml:b></xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>Order under sections 2,10,11,15,17 and 18</xhtml:b></xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>THE EXCHANGE CONTROL (DECLARATIONS AND<xhtml:br/>EVIDENCE) ORDER</xhtml:b></xhtml:p><xhtml:p>1. This Order may be cited as the Exchange Control (Declarations and Evidence) Order.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>2. (1) The prescribed evidence for the purpose of section 10 (1) (b) of the Act, to be produced to the person issuing the security, is evidence that the person to whom the security is to be issued is not resident outside the scheduled territories and from facts known to the person giving the evidence or from inquiries made by that person is not, to the best of his belief, acquiring the security as the nominee of any person resident outside the scheduled territories,</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) The evidence shall be given by a declaration in writing signed by or on behalf of the person to whom the security is to be issued.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>3. The prescribed declaration for the purposes of section 11 (1) (b) of the Act, to be delivered to the transferee at or before the time of the transfer, is a declaration in the form set out in the First Schedule or in a form to the like effect, made by an authorized depositary.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>4. The prescribed evidence for the purposes of section 15 (a) of the Act, to be produced to a person concerned with the keeping of a register in Kenya, is - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) in the case of the issue of securities, the evidence prescribed by paragraph 2;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) in the case of transfer of securities, the declaration prescribed by paragraph 3 and evidence given by a declaration in writing signed by an authorized depositary that the transferee as not resident outside the scheduled territories and, from facts known to the person giving the evidence or from inquiries made by that person, is not, to the best of his belief, acquiring the security as the nominee of any person resident outside the scheduled territories; and</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) in the case of registration of securities transferable by means of bearer certificates, the evidence prescribed by paragraph 2 given by the declaration in writing signed by an authorized depositary.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>5. The prescribed evidence for the purposes of section 17 (5) of the Act, to be produced to an authorized depositary, is the evidence prescribed in the case of the transfer of securities by paragraph 4 (b).</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>6. The prescribed declaration for the purposes of section 18 (1) (a) of the Act, to be delivered to an authorized depositary, is a declaration in the form set out in the Second Schedule, or in a form to the like effect, made by an authorized depositary.</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr></xhtml:table><xhtml:p>&#160;</xhtml:p><xhtml:table width="100%"><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%"><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/></xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="85%"><xhtml:p>FIRST SCHEDULE (para. 3)</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>The holder of the above-mentioned security is not resident outside the scheduled territories and. from facts known to us or from inquiries we have made, is not to the best of our belief holding the security as the nominee of a person resident outside those territories.</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr></xhtml:table><xhtml:p>&#160;</xhtml:p><xhtml:table width="100%"><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%"><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/></xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="85%"><xhtml:p>SECOND SCHEDULE (para. 6)</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>From facts known to us or from inquiries made, we declare to the best of our belief that each of the securities listed on the attached schedule - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) is owned by a resident of Kenya; and</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) has not been acquired by the present owner in contravention of any exchange control legislation in force in Kenya since 2nd September 1939 and has not been imported into Kenya in contravention of that legislation.</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr></xhtml:table><xhtml:p>&#160;</xhtml:p><xhtml:table width="100%"><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%"><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/></xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="85%"><xhtml:p>SCHEDULE</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>All branches in Kenya of - <xhtml:br/>Algemene Bank. Nederland N.V.<xhtml:br/>Bank of Baroda<xhtml:br/>Bank of Credit &amp; Commerce International (Overseas) Limited<xhtml:br/>Bank of India<xhtml:br/>Bank of Oman Limited<xhtml:br/>Banque d<xhtml:br/>e l'Indochine et de Suez<xhtml:br/>Barclays Bank of Kenya Limited<xhtml:br/>Biashara Bank of Kenya Limited<xhtml:br/>Citibank N.A.<xhtml:br/>Commercial Bank of Africa Limited<xhtml:br/>Continental Bank of Kenya Limited<xhtml:br/>Co-operative Bank of Kenya Limited<xhtml:br/>First American Bank of Kenya Limited<xhtml:br/>First National Bank of Chicago<xhtml:br/>Grindlays Bank International (Kenya) Limited<xhtml:br/>Habib Barik A..G, Zurich<xhtml:br/>Habib Bank Limited<xhtml:br/>Industrial Development Bank Limited<xhtml:br/>Kenya Commercial Bank Limited<xhtml:br/>Middle East Bank (Kenya) Limited<xhtml:br/>National Bank of Kenya Limited<xhtml:br/>Pan African 'Bank Limited<xhtml:br/>Standard Bank Limited<xhtml:br/>Trade Bank Limited<xhtml:br/>Trans-National Bank Limited<xhtml:br/>Union Bank of Kenya-Limited</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr></xhtml:table></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-18819"><num/><heading>SECTION  (FEES) RULES</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:table width="100%"><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%"><xhtml:p>L.N.164/1978,<xhtml:br/>L.N. 47/1979.</xhtml:p></xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="85%"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>THE EXCHANGE CONTROL (FEES) RULES</xhtml:b></xhtml:p><xhtml:p>1. These Rules may be cited as the Exchange Control (Fees) Rules.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>2. In these Rules - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"accept foreign currency" means to accept foreign currency in payment for goods and services supplied to foreign, tourists in Kenya, but does not include exchange for cash;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"emigration treatment" means any concession granted to and restriction imposed upon persons resident in Kenya under section 42 of the Act on their leaving permanently;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"inter-company account" means an account, in the books of a local trading company, by means of which settlement may be effected of payments due to and from non-residents;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"overdraft" means a borrowing by a foreign controlled company or non-resident from a local bank or other institution or any person in Kenya;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"registration of shares" means the entering of the non-resident's name and address in the local register in respect of securities purchased in accordance with exchange control regulations;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"specific authority" means permission for a transaction not covered by general authority granted to banks or any exemption order, whether that permission is specific or general.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>3. The fees prescribed in the Schedule shall be payable for the specific authority mentioned therein by any person granted the authority.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>4. The Central Bank of Kenya may waive the payment of fees payable under the Rule in cases where it considers that no fee should be paid, and in the case of payments to charities and for religious purposes.</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr></xhtml:table></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-18820"><num/><heading>SECTION  (BRANCHES AND RESIDENCE) DIRECTIONS</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:table width="100%"><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%"><xhtml:p>L.N.241/1961.</xhtml:p></xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="85%"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>Directions under sections 41 and 43</xhtml:b></xhtml:p><xhtml:p>THE EXCHANGE CONTROL (BRANCHES AND RESIDENCE)<xhtml:br/>DIRECTIONS</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>1. These Directions may be cited as the Exchange Control (Branches and Residence) Directions.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>2. For the purposes of the Act, any transaction with or by a branch of any business, whether carried on by a body corporate or otherwise, shall be treated in alt respects as if the branch were a body corporate resident where the branch is situated.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>3. A person or body of persons carrying on in Kenya a branch of any business shall, as respects such business as is carried on by that branch, be treated for all the purposes of the Act as resident in Kenya.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>4. References in these Directions to a branch of a business shall be deemed to include a reference to the head office of that business.</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr></xhtml:table></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7646"><num>1</num><heading>SECTION 1 Short title.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>1.</xhtml:b>This Act may be cited as the Exchange Control Act.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7647"><num>2</num><heading>SECTION 2 Interpretation.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>2.</xhtml:b>(1) In this Act, unless the context otherwise requires - <xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>"this Act" includes any orders made and directions given thereunder;<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>"authorized dealer" means, in relation to gold or any foreign currency, a person for the time being authorized by an order of the Minister to act for the purposes of this Act as an authorized dealer in relation to gold or, as the case may be, that foreign currency;<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>"authorized depositary" means a person for the time being authorized by an order of the Minister to act as an authorized depositary for the purposes of Part IV;<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>"bank" means a person, body corporate or other body of persons carrying on, whether on his or their own behalf or as agent for another, a banking business as defined in section 2 of the Banking Act, whether in Kenya or elsewhere;<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>"banking document" includes a banker's book as defined in section 3 (1) of the Evidence Act, an entry in a banker's book and any other document evidencing the payment of money into and the withdrawal of money from a bank account; 
<xhtml:p>"bearer certificate" means a certificate of title to securities by the delivery of which (with or without endorsement) the title to the securities is transferable;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"certificate of title to securities" means a document of title whereby a person recognizes the title of another to securities issued or to be issued by the first-mentioned person, and in the case of any such document with coupons (whether attached or on separate coupon sheets) includes any coupons which have not been detached;<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>"coupon" means a coupon representing dividends or interest on a security;<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>"foreign currency" has the meaning ascribed to it by section 3;<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>"gold" means gold coin or gold bullion;<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>"owner", in relation to property, means a person who is or who holds himself out to be the owner, importer, exporter or consignee of the property, or his agent, or the person in possession of, or beneficially interested in, or having control of, or having power of disposition over. the property;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"policy of assurance" means a policy securing the payment of a capital sum or annuity on the occurrence of a specified event which is certain to happen, and includes - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) a policy by which the payment of money is assured on death (except death by accident only) or the happening of any contingency dependent on human life; and</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) a policy securing the payment of an immediate annuity,</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>and the reference in this definition to the occurrence of a specified event which is certain to happen includes the occurrence, which is certain to happen, of one of specified events none of which by itself is certain to happen;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"prescribed" means prescribed, for the purposes of the purposes of me provision in question, by order of the competent authority;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"scheduled territories" has the meaning ascribed to it by section 3;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"secondary securities" has the meaning ascribed to it by section 21;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"securities" means shares, stock, bonds, notes (other than promissory notes), debentures, debenture stock, units under a unit trust scheme and shares in an oil royalty;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"specified currency" has the meaning ascribed to it by section 4. as extended by section 6;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"unit" means, in relation to a unit trust scheme, a right or interest (whether described as a unit, a sub-unit or otherwise) which may be acquired under the scheme;<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>"unit trust scheme" means arrangements made for the purpose, or having the effect, of providing for persons having funds available for investment facilities for the participation by them, as beneficiaries under a trust, in profits or income arising from the acquisition, holding, management or disposal of any property whatsoever.<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(2) Any provision of this Act (however worded), the effect of which is to prohibit the doing of any act where a person to or by whom the act is to be done or who stands in a specified relation to any property possesses any specified attribute as to residence or otherwise, shall, where the act is done to or by two or more persons or, as the case may be, where two or more persons stand jointly in that relation to the property, operate to prohibit the doing of that act if any of those persons possess that attribute; and any provision of this Act imposing an obligation on any person to do an act if he possesses any specified attribute as to residence or otherwise shall, in relation to any act which can only be done by two or more persons jointly - <xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(a) where all those persons possess that attribute, operate to impose a joint obligation on all of them to do the act; and<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(b) where some only of them possess that attribute, operate to impose a separate obligation on each one of them who possesses that attribute to do all he can to secure the doing of the act.<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(3) Any power conferred by this Act to prescribe the declarations which are to be furnished on any occasion shall include a power to require that the declarations shall be made by specified persons and shall be verified in a specified manner.<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(4) Nothing in this Act shall be construed as requiring the Minister to pay any sum otherwise than in Kenya shillings or otherwise than in Kenya, and any provision of this Act requiring the Minister to pay any sum to any person shall. where that sum is m a specified currency, be construed as a provision that the Minister shall pay to that person the amount in Kenya shillings which he would have received for the specified currency it he had sold it to an authorized dealer in pursuance of an offer made under section 4 at the time when the sum is paid.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(5) The obligations and prohibitions imposed by this Act shall, subject to the express limitations contained therein, apply to all persons, notwithstanding that they are not in Kenya and are not citizens of Kenya.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7648"><num>3</num><heading>SECTION 3 Dealings in gold and foreign currency.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>3.</xhtml:b>* (1) Except with the permission of the Minister no person, other than an authorized dealer, shall, in Kenya, and no person resident in Kenya, other than an authorized dealer, shall, outside Kenya, buy or borrow any gold or foreign currency from, or sell or lend any gold or foreign currency to, any person other than an authorized dealer.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) Where a person buys or borrows any gold or foreign currency in Kenya or. being a person resident in Kenya, buys or borrows gold or foreign currency outside Kenya, he shall comply with such conditions as 10 the use to which it may be put or the period for which it may be retained as may from time to time be notified to him by the Minister.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) In this Act - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) "foreign currency" does not include any currency or notes issued by the Government or under the law of any part of the scheduled territories, but save as aforesaid, includes any currency other than Kenya shillings and any notes of a class which are or have at any .time been legal tender in any territory outside Kenya, and any reference to foreign currency. except so far as the context otherwise requires, includes a reference to any right to receive foreign currency in respect of any credit or balance at a bank; and</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(6) "the scheduled territories" means the territories specified in the First Schedule:</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Provided that the Minister may at any time by order amend that Schedule, either by the addition or by the exclusion of territories or otherwise, and the expression shall be construed according.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>________________________________________________________<xhtml:br/>*The exercise of. the powers and the performance of .the duties conferred on the Minister by the provisions so marked has been delegated to the Central Bank of Kenya by L.N.18/1968.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7649"><num>4</num><heading>SECTION 4 Surrender of gold and foreign currency.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>4.</xhtml:b>(1)* Any person in or resident in Kenya Who is entitled to sell, or to procure the sale of. any gold, or any foreign currency to which this section applies, and is not an authorized dealer, shall offer it, or cause it to be offered, for sale to an authorized dealer, unless the Minister consents to his retention and use thereof or he disposes thereof to any other person with the permission of the Minister; and the foreign currency to which this section applies is such foreign currency (in this Act referred to as specified currency) as may from time to time be specified by order of the Minister. 
<xhtml:p>(2) If a person who has obtained the consent of the Minister to his retention and use of any gold or specified currency, and has stated in an application for the consent that he requires it for a particular purpose, no longer requires the gold or currency for that purpose, subsection (1) shall thereupon apply to him in relation to that gold or currency as if the Minister had revoked his consent to his retention and use thereof.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) A person who acquires any gold or specified currency from an authorized dealer shall be treated for the purposes of this section as if the Minister had consented to the retention and use by him of that gold or currency (subject to any conditions notified to him in accordance with section 3) and as if any statement made by him in an application for that gold or currency as to the purpose for which he requires it had been made by him in an application for the Minister's consent to his retention and use thereof.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) Where a person has become bound under this section to offer or cause to be offered any gold or specified currency for sale to an authorized dealer, he shall not be deemed to comply with that obligation by any offer made or caused to be made by him. if the offer is an offer to sell at a price exceeding that authorized by the Minister, or without payment of any usual and proper charges of the authorized dealer, or otherwise on any unusual terms.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(5) Where a person has become bound under this section to offer or cause to be offered any gold or specified currency for sale to an authorized dealer and has not complied with that obligation, the Minister may direct that that gold or currency shall vest in him, and it shall vest in the Minister accordingly free from any mortgage, pledge or charge, and the Minister may deal with it as he thinks fit, but he shall pay to the person who would but for the direction be entitled to the gold or currency such sum as he would have received therefore if he had sold it to an authorized dealer in pursuance of an offer made under this section at the time when the vesting occurred.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(6) In any proceedings in respect of a failure to comply with the provisions of this section, it shall be presumed, until his retention and use thereof or he disposes thereof to any other person with the permission of the Minister; and the foreign currency to which this section applies is such foreign currency (in this Act referred to as specified currency) as may from time to time be specified by order of the Minister.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) If a person who has obtained the consent of the Minister to his retention and use of any gold or specified currency, and has stated in an application for the consent that he requires it for a particular purpose, no longer requires the gold or currency for that purpose, subsection (1) shall thereupon apply to him in relation to that gold or currency as if the Minister had revoked his consent to his retention and use thereof.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) A person who acquires any gold or specified currency from an authorized dealer shall be treated for the purposes of this section as if the Minister had consented to the retention and use by him of that gold or currency (subject to any conditions notified to him in accordance with section 3) and as if any statement made by him in an application for that gold or currency as to the purpose for which he requires it had been made by him in an application for the Minister's consent to his retention and use thereof.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) Where a person has become bound under this section to offer or cause to be offered any gold or specified currency for sale to an authorized dealer, he shall not be deemed to comply with that obligation by any offer made or caused to be made by him. if the offer is an offer to sell at a price exceeding that authorized by the Minister, or without payment of any usual and proper charges of the authorized dealer, or otherwise on any unusual terms.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(5) Where a person has become bound under this section to offer or cause to be offered any gold or specified currency for sale to an authorized dealer and has not complied with that obligation, the Minister may direct that that gold or currency shall vest in him, and it shall vest in the Minister accordingly free from any mortgage, pledge or charge, and the Minister may deal with it as he thinks fit, but he shall pay to the person who would but for the direction be entitled to the gold or currency such sum as he would have received therefore if he had sold it to an authorized dealer in pursuance of an offer made under this section at the time when the vesting occurred.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(6) In any proceedings in respect of a failure to comply with the provisions of this section, it shall be presumed, until</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7650"><num>5</num><heading>SECTION 5 Bailees of gold and foreign currency.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>5.</xhtml:b>* (1) Every person in Kenya by whom or to whose order (whether directly or indirectly) any gold or any specified currency in the form of notes is held in Kenya but who is not entitled to sell it or procure its sale shall notify the Minister in writing that he so holds that gold or currency. 
<xhtml:p>(2) The Minister may direct any person in Kenya by whom or to whose order (whether directly or indirectly) any gold or any specified currency in the form of notes is held in Kenya, whether or not he is entitled to sell it or procure its sale, to cause that gold or currency to be kept at all times in the custody of such banker as may be specified in the direction.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7651"><num>6</num><heading>SECTION 6 Travelers&amp;apos; cheques, etc.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>6</xhtml:b>. (1) This section applies to any document of a kind intended to enable the person to whom the document is issued to obtain foreign currency from some other person on the credit of the person issuing it. and in particular to any traveler's cheque or other draft or letter of credit so intended. 
<xhtml:p>(2) For the purposes of this Act, the person issuing a document to which this section applies, and the person to whom it is issued, shall be deemed respectively to sell and buy foreign currency and where foreign currency is obtained by means of the document to sell and buy. that foreign currency.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) Any such document not expressed in terms of Kenya shillings shall, if it is of a kind intended to enable the person to whom it is issued to obtain any specified currency, be treated also for the purposes of this Act as itself being specified currency.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4)* Every person in or resident m Kenya who holds or to whose order there is held any document to which this section applies, being a document expressed in terms of Kenya shillings, shall encash it or cause it to be encashed in the scheduled territories with the person issuing it or with a banker, unless the Minister consents to his retention and use thereof and, where in his application for that consent he has stated that he requires it for a particular purpose, unless also he still requires it for that purpose.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(5) A person who acquires any document to which subsection (4) applies from an authorized dealer shall be treated for the purposes of that subsection as if the Minister had consented to the retention and use by him of that document (subject to any conditions notified to him in accordance with section 3 (2), and as if any statement made by him in an application for that document as to the purpose for which he requires it had been made by him in an application for the Minister's consent to his retention and use thereof.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7652"><num>7</num><heading>SECTION 7 Payments in Kenya.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>7.</xhtml:b>* Except with the permission of the Minister, no person shall do any of the following things in Kenya - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) make any payment to or for the credit of a person resident outside the scheduled territories; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) make any payment to or for the credit of a person resident in the scheduled territories by order or on behalf of a person resident outside the scheduled territories; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) place any sum to the credit of any person resident outside the scheduled territories:</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Provided that where a person resident outside the scheduled territories has paid a sum in or towards the satisfaction of a debt due from him. paragraph (c) shall not prohibit the acknowledgment or recording of the payment.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7653"><num>8</num><heading>SECTION 8 Payments outside Kenya.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>8.</xhtml:b>(1)* Except with the permission of the Minister, no person resident in Kenya shall, subject to this section, make any payment outside Kenya to or for the credit of a person resident outside the scheduled territories. 
<xhtml:p>(2) Nothing in this section shall prohibit the doing of anything otherwise lawful by any person with any foreign currency obtained by him in accordance with Part II or retained by him in pursuance of a consent of the Minister.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7654"><num>9</num><heading>SECTION 9 Compensation deals.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>9.</xhtml:b>(1)* Except with the permission of the Minister, no person shall in Kenya, and no person resident in Kenya shall outside Kenya, make any payment to or for the credit of a person resident in the scheduled territories as consideration for or in association with - 
<xhtml:p>(a) the receipt by any person of a payment made outside the scheduled territories, or the acquisition by any person of property which is outside the scheduled territories; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) the transfer to any person, or the creation in favour of any person, of a right (whether present or future, and whether vested or contingent) to receive a payment outside the scheduled territories or to acquire property which is outside the scheduled territories.<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(2) Nothing in this section shall prohibit the making of any payment in accordance with the terms of a permission or consent granted under this Act.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7655"><num>10</num><heading>SECTION 10 Issue of securities.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>10.</xhtml:b>* (1) Except with the permission of the Minister, no person shall in Kenya issue any security or, whether in Kenya or elsewhere, issue any security which is registered or to be registered in Kenya, unless the following requirements are<xhtml:br/>fulfilled - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) neither the person to whom the security is to be issued nor the person, if any, for whom he is to be a nominee is resident outside the scheduled territories; and</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) the prescribed evidence is produced to the person issuing the security as to the residence of the person to whom it is to be issued and that of the person. if any, for whom he is to be a nominee.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) The subscription of the memorandum of association of a company to be formed under the Companies Act, by a person resident outside the scheduled territories, or by a nominee for another person so resident, shall, unless he subscribes the memorandum with the permission of the Minister, be invalid in so far as it would on registration of the memorandum have the effect of making him a member of or shareholder in the company, so, however, that this provision shall not render invalid the incorporation of the company; and, if by virtue of this subsection the number of the subscribers of the memorandum who on its registration become members of the company is less than the minimum number required to subscribe the memorandum, the provisions of the Companies Act relating to the carrying on of business of a company the number of whose members is reduced below the legal minimum shall apply to the company as if the number of its members had been so reduced.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7656"><num>11</num><heading>SECTION 11 Transfer of securities and coupons.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>11.</xhtml:b>* (1) Except with the permission of the Minister, a security registered in Kenya shall not be transferred, and a security not so registered shall not be transferred in Kenya unless, in either case, the following requirements are fulfilled - 
<xhtml:p>(a) neither the transferor nor the person, if any, for whom he is a nominee is resident outside the scheduled territories: and<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(b) the transferor delivers to the transferee at or before the time of the transfer the prescribed declarations as to his residence and that of the person, if any, for whom he is a nominee; and</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) neither the transferee nor the person, if any, for whom he is to be a nominee is resident outside the scheduled territories; and</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(d) except where the security is registered in Kenya otherwise than in a subsidiary register, the Minister is satisfied that the requirements of paragraph (c) are fulfilled:</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Provided that - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(1) neither the transferee nor his agent shall be deemed to have committed an offence by reason only that the requirements of paragraph (a) were not fulfilled unless the transferee, or as the case may be, his agent, knew or had reason to believe that those requirements were not fulfilled; and</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(ii) neither the transferor nor his agent shall be deemed to have committed an offence by reason only that any of the requirements of paragraphs (c) and (d) have not been fulfilled unless, in the case of a non fulfilment of the requirements of paragraph (c), the transferor or, as the case may be, his agent, knew or had reason to believe that those requirements were not fulfilled.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) Except with the permission of the Minister, a security not registered in Kenya shall not be transferred outside Kenya if either the transferor or the transferee, or the person, if any, for whom the transferor or transferee is or is to be a nominee, is resident in Kenya.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) Except with the permission of the Minister - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) no coupon shall be transferred in Kenya if either the transferee or the person, if any, for whom he is to be a nominee is resident outside the scheduled territories;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) no person shall in Kenya do any act which involves. is in association with or is preparatory to the transfer of any coupon outside Kenya if either the transferor or the transferee, or the person, if any, for whom the transferor or transferee is or is to be a nominee. is resident in Kenya.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7657"><num>12</num><heading>SECTION 12 Substitution of securities and certificates outside Kenya.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>12.</xhtml:b>* Except with the permission of the Minister, no person shall in Kenya, and no person resident in Kenya shall, outside Kenya, issue any bearer certificate or coupon or so alter any document that it becomes a bearer certificate or coupon.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7658"><num>13</num><heading>SECTION 13 Substitution of securities and certificates outside Kenya.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>13</xhtml:b>.* Except with the permission of .the Minister, no person in or resident in Kenya shall do any act with intent to secure - 
<xhtml:p>(a) that a security which is - <xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(i) registered in Kenya; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(ii) transferable by means of a bearer certificate in Kenya, becomes, or is replaced by, a security registered outside Kenya or a security transferable by means of a bearer certificate outside Kenya; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) that a certificate of title to any other security, is issued outside Kenya in substitution for or in addition to a certificate of title thereto which is in, or is or has been lost or destroyed in, Kenya.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7659"><num>14</num><heading>SECTION 14 Payment of capital money outside Kenya.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>14</xhtml:b>.* Except with the permission of the Minister, no person resident in Kenya shall do any act with intent to secure that capital moneys payable on a security registered in Kenya are paid outside Kenya, or that. where the certificate of title to a security is in Kenya, capital moneys payable on the security are paid outside Kenya without production of the certificate to the person making the payment.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7660"><num>15</num><heading>SECTION 15 Duties of person keeping registers.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>15</xhtml:b>.* Except with the permission of the Minister, no person concerned with the keeping of any register in Kenya shall - 
<xhtml:p>(a) enter in the register the name of any person in relation to any security unless there has been produced to him the prescribed evidence that the entry does not form part of a transaction which involves the doing of anything prohibited by this Act; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) enter in the register, in respect of any security, an address outside the scheduled territories, except for the purpose of any transaction for which the<xhtml:br/>permission of the Minister has been granted with the knowledge that it involved the entry of that address; or<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(c) do any act in relation to the register which recognizes or gives effect to any act appearing to him to have been done with such intent as is mentioned in section 13 or section 14, whether done by a person in resident in Kenya or not.<xhtml:br/></xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7661"><num>16</num><heading>SECTION 16 Additional provisions as to nominee holdings.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>16.</xhtml:b>* (1) Where - 
<xhtml:p>(a) the holder of a security is a nominee and the person for whom he is a nominee is resident outside the scheduled territories; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) the holder of a security is not a nominee and is resident outside the scheduled territories, then, except with the permission of the Minister, no person resident in Kenya shall do any act whereby the holder becomes his nominee in respect of the security.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) Except with the permission of the Minister, a person resident in Kenya for whom the holder of a security is a nominee shall not do any act whereby - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) the holder, being a person resident outside the scheduled territories, holds the security otherwise than as his nominee; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) the holder, not being a person resident outside the scheduled territories, holds the security as nominee for a person resident outside the scheduled territories.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) Where the holder of a security is a nominee; then, except with the permission of the Minister, neither he, if he is resident in Kenya, nor any person resident in Kenya through whose agency the exercise of all or any of the holder's rights in respect of the security are controlled, shall - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) do any act whereby he recognizes or gives effect to the substitution of another person as the person from whom he directly receives his instructions unless both the person previously instructing him and the person substituted for that person were, immediately before the substitution, resident in the scheduled territories and not elsewhere; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) do any act whereby he ceases to be a person bound to give effect to the instructions of another person in relation to the security, unless the person who therefore instructed him is resident in the scheduled territories and not elsewhere.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) Where the holder of a security is not a nominee and is resident in Kenya, then, except with the permission of the Minister, he shall not do any act whereby he becomes the nominee of another person in respect of the security. unless that other person is resident in the scheduled territories and not elsewhere.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(5) No person resident in the scheduled territories shall in Kenya do any act which involves, is in association with or is preparatory to any such transaction outside Kenya as is referred to in this section.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7662"><num>17</num><heading>SECTION 17 Deposit of certificates of title.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>17</xhtml:b>.* (1) This section and section 18 apply to any security except - 
<xhtml:p>(a) a security which is registered in Kenya otherwise than in a subsidiary register, and on which none of the dividends or interest is payable on presentment of a coupon; and</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) such other securities as may be prescribed, and in the following provisions of this section and in section 18 "security", "certificate of title" and "coupon" mean respectively a security to which sections apply, a certificate of title to such a security and a coupon representing dividends or interest on such a security.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) Every person by whom or to whose order (whether directly or indirectly) a certificate of title is held in Kenya. and every person resident in Kenya by whom or to whose order (whether directly or indirectly) a certificate of title is kept at all times, except with the permission of the Minister, in the custody of an authorized depositary, and nothing in his Part shall prohibit the doing of anything for the purpose of complying with the requirements of this subsection.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) Except with the permission of the Minister, an authorized depositary shall not part with any certificate of title or coupon required under this section to be in the custody of an authorized depositary:</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Provided that this subsection shall not prohibit an authorized depositary - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(i) from parting with the certificate of title or coupon to or to the order of another authorized depositary, where the person from whom the other authorized depositary is to receive instructions in relation thereto is to be the same as the person from whom he receives instructions:</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(ii) from parting with a certificate of title, for the purpose of obtaining payment of capital moneys payable on the security, to the person entrusted with payment thereof; or<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(iii) from parting with a coupon in the ordinary course for collection.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) Except with the permission of the Minister, no capital moneys, interest or dividends shall be paid in Kenya on any security except to or to the order of an authorized depositary having the custody of the certificate of title to that security, so, however, that this subsection shall not be taken as restricting the manner in which any sums lawfully paid on account of the capital moneys, interest or dividends may be dealt with by the person receiving them.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(5) Except with the permission of the Minister, an authorized depositary shall not do any act whereby he recognizes or gives effect to the substitution of one person for another as the person from whom he receives instructions in relation to a certificate of title or coupon, unless there is produced to him the prescribed evidence that he is not by so doing giving effect to any transaction which is prohibited by this Act.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(6) Where a certificate of title which under this section should for the time being be in the custody of an authorized depositary is not in the custody of an authorized depositary then, except with the permission of the Minister, no person shall in Kenya, and no person resident in Kenya shall outside Kenya, buy, sell or transfer, or do anything which affects his rights or powers in relation to, the security.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(7) Except with the permission of the Minister, no person in or resident in Kenya shall, in the case of a certificate of title with coupons (whether attached or on separate coupon sheets), detach any of the coupons other than in the ordinary course of collection.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7663"><num>18</num><heading>SECTION 18 Additional provisions as to deposited certificates.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>18</xhtml:b>.* (1) Where a certificate of title to a security is by section 17 required to be and is in the custody of an authorized depositary, this section shall, except so far as the Minister otherwise directs, have effect in relation thereto until - 
<xhtml:p>(a) there are delivered to him the prescribed declarations as to the ownership of the security and the residence of the owners thereof; and</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) in the case of a certificate of title which - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(i) would ordinarily be accompanied by coupons (whether attached or on separate coupon sheets); but</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(ii) when it comes into the custody of the authorized depositary wants, in order to render it complete. any coupons which would not in the ordinary course have been detached for collection, there have also been deposited with him the coupons so wanting at the time when the certificate of title comes into his custody:</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Provided that where the prescribed declarations have been delivered to an authorized depositary and he has parted with the certificate of title, paragraph (a) shall not again apply on the certificate coming into the custody of another authorized depositary or again coming into his own custody.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) Except with the permission of the Minister, the authorized depositary shall not part with or destroy the certificate of title or any coupons belonging thereto, otherwise than as mentioned in paragraphs (ii) and (iii) of the proviso to section 17 (3), or do any act whereby he recognizes or gives effect to the substitution of one person for another as the person from whom he receives instructions in relation thereto:</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Provided that, where the person from whom an authorized depositary receives instructions in relation to any certificate of title becomes bankrupt in Kenya or dies, this subsection shall not prohibit the authorized depositary from recognizing the trustee in bankruptcy or personal representative as the person entitled to give instructions in relation to the certificate of title.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) The authorized depositary shall place any capital moneys, dividends or interest on the security received by him to the credit of the person by virtue of whose authority he received them. but shall not permit any part of the sums received to be dealt with except with the permission of the Minister.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7664"><num>19</num><heading>SECTION 19 Special provisions as to dealings in certain securities.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>19</xhtml:b>. (1) The Minister may, if in his opinion there are circumstances rendering it necessary or expedient so to do, by order direct that this section shall apply to such securities as may be prescribed, being securities on which capital moneys, dividends or interest are payable in a specified currency or as respects which the holder has an option to require payment of any capital moneys, dividends or interest thereon in a specified currency.<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(2)* Except with the permission of the Minister, no person shall in Kenya, and no person resident in Kenya shall outside Kenya, transfer, or do anything which affects his rights or powers in relation to, any security to which this section applies.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7665"><num>20</num><heading>SECTION 20 Validation of certain transfers.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>20.</xhtml:b>* (1) The title of any person to a security for which he has given value on a transfer thereof, and the title of all persons claiming through or under him, shall, notwithstanding that the transfer, or any previous transfer, or the issue of the. security, was by reason of the residence of any person concerned other than the first-mentioned person prohibited by the provisions of this Act relating to the transfer or issue of securities, be valid unless the first-mentioned person had notice of the facts by reason of which it was prohibited.<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(2) Without prejudice to subsection (1), the Minister may issue a certificate declaring, in relation to a security, that any acts done before the issue of the certificate purporting o effect the issue or transfer of the security, being acts which were prohibited by this Act, are to be, and are always to have been. "as valid as if they had been done with the permission of the competent authority, and those acts shall have effect accordingly. 
<xhtml:p>(3) Nothing in this section shall affect the liability of any person to prosecution for an offence under this Act.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7666"><num>21</num><heading>SECTION 21 Application of Part to secondary securities.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>21.</xhtml:b>(1) This Part shall apply, with such modifications (if any) as may be prescribed, in relation to a document mentioned in subsection (2) as if the document created, and were the certificate of title to, a security (hereafter in this Act referred to as a secondary security). 
<xhtml:p>(2) The documents referred to in subsection (1) are a letter of allotment which may be renounced, a letter of rights, a warrant conferring an option to acquire a security, a deposit certificate in respect of securities (but not including a receipt by an authorized depositary for a certificate of title deposited in pursuance of this Part), and such other documents conferring, or containing evidence of, rights as may be prescribed. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7667"><num>22</num><heading>SECTION 22 Interpretation of Part.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>22.</xhtml:b>(1) In this Part - 
<xhtml:p>"register" includes a book, file or index in which securities are registered;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"registered" includes inscribed;<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>"registered in Kenya" and "registered outside Kenya" mean, respectively, registered in a register in, and registered in a register outside, Kenya;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"security which is registered in Kenya otherwise than in a subsidiary register" means a security which either - <xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(a) is registered in Kenya, and can not without<xhtml:a><xhtml:br/>the necessity for an entry in the register in Kenya become, registered outside; or</xhtml:a></xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) is registered both in Kenya and outside but on a transfer cannot, without the necessity for an entry in the register in Kenya, become registered outside in the name of the transferee.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) For the purposes of any provision of this Part prohibiting the transfer of securities, a person shall be deemed to transfer a security if he executes an instrument of transfer thereof, whether effective or not, and shall be deemed to transfer it at the place where he executes the instrument.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) References in this Part to the person holding a certificate of title or coupon shall be construed as references to the person having physical custody of the certificate of title or coupon:</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Provided that, where the certificate of title or coupon is deposited with any person in a locked or sealed receptacle from which he is not entitled to remove it without the authority of some other person, that other person shall be deemed for the purposes of this provision to have the physical custody thereof.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) In this Part "holder" - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) in relation to a security transferable by means of a bearer certificate or to a coupon, includes the person holding the certificate or coupon; and</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) in relation to a security which is registered in the name of a deceased person, or of any person who by reason of bankruptcy, unsoundness of mind or any other disability is incapable of transferring the security, means the personal representative, trustee in bankruptcy or other person entitled to transfer the security.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(5) The holder of a security or coupon shall be deemed for the purposes of this Part to be a nominee in respect thereof if, as respects the exercise of any rights in respect thereof, he is not entitled to exercise those rights except in accordance with instructions given by some other person, and references in this Part to the person for whom the holder of a security or coupon is a nominee shall be construed as references to.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7668"><num>23</num><heading>SECTION 23 Restrictions on import.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>23</xhtml:b>.* (1) The importation of - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) notes of a class which are or have at any time been legal tender in East Africa or any part of East Africa; and</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) such other notes as may be specified by order of the Minister, being notes issued by a bank or notes of a class which are or have at any time been legal tender in any territory; and</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) any certificate of title to a security, including a certificate which has been cancelled, and any document certifying the destruction, loss or cancellation of any certificate of title to a security, is prohibited except with the permission of the Minister.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) In this section "note" includes part of a note, and "security" includes a secondary security.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7669"><num>23A</num><heading>SECTION 23A Payment for imports</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>23A. (</xhtml:b>1) Notwithstanding any law to the contrary, it shall be a condition in any approval granted by the Minister for the importation of any goods into Kenya that - 
<xhtml:p>(a) the price paid or to be paid for the goods by the importer as indicated in the application for foreign exchange allocation license shall be the best price available on the market taking into account the quality and quantity of the goods in the country of origin; and</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) the quality of the goods correspond with the description indicated in the import license and the standards established by the Kenya Bureau of Standards.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7670"><num>24</num><heading>SECTION 24 General restrictions on export.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>24.</xhtml:b>*<xhtml:b/>(1) The exportation of - 
<xhtml:p>(a) notes of a class which are or have at any time been legal tender in Kenya or in any other territory;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) postal orders;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) gold;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(d) any of the following documents (including any such document which has been cancelled) - <xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(i) a certificate of title to a security and any coupon;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(ii) a policy of assurance;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(iii) a bill of exchange or promissory note expressed in terms of a currency other than that of a scheduled territory and payable otherwise than within the scheduled territories;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(iv) a document to which section 6 applies not issued by an authorized dealer or in pursuance of a permission granted by the Minister; and any document certifying the destruction, loss or cancellation of any of those documents;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(e) such articles exported on the person of a traveler or in a traveler's baggage as may be prescribed, is prohibited except with the permission of the Minister.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) In this section "note" includes part of a note "security" includes a secondary security and "coupon" shall be construed in accordance with the meaning of "security".</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>________________________________________________________________<xhtml:br/>*The exercise of the powers and the performance of the duties conferred on the Minister by the provisions so marked has been delegated to the Central Bank of Kenya by L-N . 18/1968.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7671"><num>25</num><heading>SECTION 25 Payment for exports</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>25</xhtml:b>.* (1) The exportation of goods of any class or description to a destination in such territory as may be prescribed is prohibited except with the permission of the Minister, unless the Commissioner of Customs and Excise is satisfied - 
<xhtml:p>(a) that payment for the goods has been made to a person resident in Kenya in such manner as may be prescribed in relation to goods of that class or description exported to a destination in that territory, or is to be so made not later than three months after the date of exportation; and</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) that the amount of the payment that has been made or is to be made is such as to represent a return for the goods which is in all the circumstances satisfactory in the national interest:</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Provided that the Minister may direct that. in cases to which the direction applies, paragraph (a) shall have effect as if for the reference to three months there were substituted a , reference to such longer or shorter period as may be specified in the direction, or as if the words "or is to be so made not later than three months after the date of exporation" were omitted.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) For the purpose of satisfying himself in the case of any goods as to the matters specified in subsection (1), the Commissioner of Customs and Excise may require the person making entry of the goods for export to deliver to the collector or other proper officer together with the entry such declarations signed by such persons as he may require, and where any such declaration has been so required the goods shall not be exported until it has been so delivered.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) Where the Commissioner of Customs and Excise is not satisfied in the case of any goods as to the matters specified in paragraph (b) of subsection (1). he shall give his reasons to the person making entry of the goods for export and shall take into consideration any representations made by him.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) A reference in this section to the destination of goods includes a reference to the ultimate destination thereof<xhtml:br/>____________________________________________________________<xhtml:br/>*The exercise of the powers and the performance of (he duties conferred on the Minister by the provisions so marked' has been delegated to the Central Bank of Kenya by L.N.18/1968.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7672"><num>25A</num><heading>SECTION 25A Withholding e.t.c. of payment for export prohibited.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>25A</xhtml:b>. (1) No person resident in Kenya shall do any act which involves or is in association with or is preparatory to a delay or the withholding of any payment by a person resident outside Kenya to an authorized dealer which payment is due in respect of the exportation of goods for a period exceeding the period specified under section 25 (1). 
<xhtml:p>(2) No authorized dealer shall - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) aid, abet or do any act which involves or is in association with or is preparatory to the contravention of or contravenes any provision of this Act; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) delay or withhold collection of payments for exports; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) delay the sale of specified currency to the Central Bank of Kenya.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) For the purposes of subsection (2), the authorized dealer shall sell the specified currency to the Central Bank of Kenya immediately after collection thereof but an any case within a period not exceeding forty-eight hours thereafter.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) Any person in or resident in Kenya who contravenes subsection (1), (2) or (3) shall be guilty of an offence and liable to imprisonment for a term not exceeding ten years or a fine not exceeding three times the value of the exports payment of which is deplayed or withheld or to both.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7673"><num>25B</num><heading>SECTION 25B Provisions relating to export documents.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>25B.</xhtml:b>(1) The documents of title to the goods exported under section 25 (1) shall be made to the order of an authorized dealer who shall be assigned the right to receive payment; and the documents shall be deposited with the authorized dealer who is a party to the declaration made to the Commissioner of Customs and Excise and is entitled to receive specified currency on behalf of the person exporting the goods.<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(2) Any person who contravenes subsection (1) shall be guilty of an offence.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7674"><num>25C</num><heading>SECTION 25C Payment for services.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>25C</xhtml:b>. (1) Any person resident in Kenya who renders prescribed services to a person resident outside Kenya shall be paid in the specified currency, and the amount payable shall in all respects be commensurate with the nature and quality of the service in respect of which payment is made. 
<xhtml:p>(2) Any person who contravenes subsection (1) shall be guilty of an offence. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7675"><num>26</num><heading>SECTION 26 Duty to collect certain debts.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>26.</xhtml:b>(1)* Except with the permission of the Minister, no person resident in Kenya who has a right (whether present or future and whether vested or contingent) to receive any specified currency, or to receive from a person resident outside the scheduled territories a payment in Kenya shillings, shall do, or refrain from doing, any act with the intent to secure or shall do any act which involves, is in association with or is preparatory to any transaction securing - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) that the receipt by him of the whole or part of that currency or. as the case may be, of that payment in Kenya shillings is delayed; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) that the currency or payment ceases, in whole or in part, to be receivable by him:</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Provided that nothing in this subsection - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(i) shall, unless the Minister otherwise directs, impose on any person an obligation, in relation to a debt arising in the carrying on of a trade or business, to procure the payment thereof at an earlier time than is customary in the course of that trade or business; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(ii) shall, unless the Minister otherwise directs,<xhtml:br/>prohibit the transfer to a person resident in Kenya and not elsewhere of a right to receive specified currency or payment in Kenya shillings. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) Where a person has contravened subsection (1) in relation to any specified currency or payment in Kenya shillings, the Minister may give to him or to any other person who appears to the Minister to be in a position to give effect thereto (being a person in or resident in Kenya) such directions as appear to the Minister to be expedient for the purpose of obtaining or expediting the receipt of the currency or payment in question, and, without prejudice to the generality of the preceding provisions of this subsection, may direct that there shall be assigned to the Minister, or to such person as may be specified in the directions the right to receive the currency or payment or enforce any security for the receipt thereof.<xhtml:br/>________________________________________________________<xhtml:br/>*The exercise of the powers and the performance of the duties conferred on the Minister by the provisions so marked' has been delegated to the Central Bank of Kenya by L.N.18/1968.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7676"><num>27</num><heading>SECTION 27 Duty not to delay sale or importation of goods.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>27.</xhtml:b>* (1) Where - 
<xhtml:p>(a) permission or consent has been granted under this Act, or under any corresponding provision of the law in force in any territory comprised in the scheduled territories, subject to a condition providing that, or on the faith of an application slating an intention that, goods should be sold outside the scheduled territories; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) a statement or declaration has been made under this Act or any such corresponding provision that any goods are to be sold outside the scheduled<xhtml:br/>territories; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) currency has been obtained in, or by any person resident in, the scheduled territories on the faith of an application stating an intention that goods should be sold outside the scheduled territories,</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>then, except with the permission of the Minister, no person resident in Kenya who is entitled to sell or procure the sale of the goods shall do, or refrain from doing, any act with intent to secure or shall do any act which involves, is in association with or is preparatory to any transaction securing - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(i) that the sale is delayed to an extent which is unreasonable having regard to the ordinary course of trade; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(ii) that, on the sale, any payment made for the goods is not made in the manner indicated by the condition, statement or declaration, as the case may be.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) Where - <xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(a) permission or consent has been granted under this Act, or under any corresponding provisions of the law in force in any territory comprised in the scheduled territories, subject to a condition providing that, or on the faith of an application stating an intention that, goods should be imported from outside the scheduled territories into any part of the scheduled territories; or<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(b) currency has been obtained in, or by any person resident in, the scheduled territories on the faith of an application stating an intention that goods should be so imported,</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>then, except with the permission of the Minister, no person resident in Kenya who is entitled to procure the importation of the goods shall do, or refrain from doing, any act with intent to secure that the importation thereof is delayed to an extent which is unreasonable having regard to the ordinary course of trade.<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(3) Where in any case specified in paragraph (a), (b) or (c) of subsection (1), or paragraph (a) or (b) of subsection (2) - <xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(a) the goods have not been sold or imported as indicated by the condition, statement or declaration within the time thereby indicated or, if no time is thereby<xhtml:br/>indicated, a reasonable time, or (in either case) within such further time as may be allowed by the Minister; or<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(6) it appears to the Minister that the goods cannot be sold or imported as indicated by the. condition, statement or declaration,<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>the Minister may give any person resident in Kenya who appears to the Minister to be in a position to give effect thereto such directions as appear to him to be expedient as to the manner in which the goods are to be dealt with.<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(4) Without prejudice to the generality of subsection (3), the power conferred thereby on the Minister to give directions shall extend to the giving of directions that the goods shall be assigned to the Minister or to a person specified in the directions.<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(5) The powers conferred by subsections (3) and (4) in relation to any goods shall extend to the giving of directions with respect to any goods produced or manufactured therefrom, and, where goods to be sold outside the scheduled territories or to be imported were to be produced or manufactured from other goods, to the giving of directions with respect to those other goods and any goods produced or manufactured from those other goods.<xhtml:br/>_____________________________________________________________<xhtml:br/>*The exercise of the powers and the performance of the duties conferred on the Minister by the provisions so marked has been delegated to the Central Bank of Kenya by L.N.18/1968.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7677"><num>28</num><heading>SECTION 28 Property obtained by infringement of Act.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>28</xhtml:b>. (1) Where a person - 
<xhtml:p>(a) has made any payment which is prohibited by this Act; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) being bound under this Act to offer or cause to be offered any specified currency to an authorized dealer, has otherwise disposed of that currency, the Minister may direct him to sell or procure the sale of any property which he is entitled to sell or of which he is entitled to procure the sale, being property which represents, whether directly or indirectly, that payment or, that specified currency, as the case may be, and may by the same or a subsequent direction specify the manner in which, the persons to whom and the terms on which the property is to be sold.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) Without prejudice to the generality of subsection (1),the power conferred thereby on the Minister to give directions shall extend to the giving of directions that the property shall be assigned to the Minister or to a person specified in the directions.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7678"><num>29</num><heading>SECTION 29 Provisions supplemental to preceding provisions of Part.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>29.</xhtml:b>(1) Where, under the preceding provisions of this Part, the Minister has power to give directions that a right to receive a currency or payment in Kenya shillings or to enforce a security for the receipt thereof, or goods, or other property, shall be assigned to the Minister, the Minister may also direct that the right, goods or property shall vest in the Minister, and it or they shall vest in the Minister accordingly free from any mortgage, pledge or charge, and the Minister may deal with it or them as he thinks fit. 
<xhtml:p>(2) Where in pursuance of directions under those provisions, any right, .goods or property is or are assigned to the Minister or to a person specified in the directions or any right, goods or property vests or vest m the Minister in pursuance of directions given under subsection (I), the Minister shall pay the net sum recovered by him in respect of the right, goods or property to the person making the assignment or. in the case of any right, goods or property vested in the Minister under subsection (1), to the person who, but for the directions, could be entitled to the right, goods or property.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7679"><num>30</num><heading>SECTION 30 Transfer of annuities, policies, etc.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>30</xhtml:b>. (1)* Except with the permission of the Minister, no person resident in Kenya shall transfer to a person resident outside the scheduled territories, or who is to be a nominee for a person resident outside the scheduled territories, any right to the sums assured by a policy of assurance, so, however, that where the person liable for the sums so assured makes any payment thereof to a person resident in the scheduled territories and not elsewhere, or makes with the permission of the Minister any payment thereof to any other person - 
<xhtml:p>(c) he shall not be bound to inquire as to the residence of any person other than the person to whom, and (if it is not the same person) the person to whose order, the payment is made; and</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) the payment shall, to the extent of the sums paid, discharge him from his liability under the policy, notwithstanding that the payment is made to or to the order of a person who was not entitled thereto otherwise than by virtue of a transfer prohibited by this subsection.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) Subsections (2) and (3) of section 20 shall apply in relation to a transfer prohibited by this section as they apply in relation to a transfer prohibited by this Act of a security.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) In this section, "nominee" has, in relation to a policy, annuity or insurance, the same meaning as the expression has in Part IV in relation to a security.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7680"><num>31</num><heading>SECTION 31 settlements.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>31</xhtml:b>.* (1) Except with the permission of the Minister, no person resident in Kenya shall settle any property, otherwise than by will, so as to confer an interest in the property on a person who, at the time of the settlement, is resident outside the scheduled territories, or shall exercise, otherwise than by will, a power of appointment, whether created by ill or otherwise, in favour of a person who, at the time of the exercise of the power, is resident outside the scheduled territories. 
<xhtml:p>(2) A settlement or exercise of a power of appointment hall not be invalid by reason that it is prohibited by this section, except so far as it purports to confer an interest on any person who, at the time of the settlement or the exercise of the power, is resident outside the scheduled territories.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) Subsections (2) and (3) of section 20 shall apply in relation to a settlement or the exercise of a power of appointment prohibited by this section as they apply in relation to a transfer prohibited by this Act of a security.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) For the purposes of this section - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) a reference to settling property includes a reference to the making of a disposition, covenant, agreement or arrangement whereby the property becomes subject to a trust, or (in the case of a resettlement) to a different trust; and</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) a person shall be deemed to have an interest in property if he has any beneficial interest therein, whether present or future, and whether vested or contingent, or falls within a limited class of persons in whose favour a discretion or power in respect of property is exercisable; and</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) "will" includes any testamentary disposition.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(5) No person resident in the scheduled territories shall n Kenya do any act which involves, is in association with or is preparatory to any such transaction outside Kenya as is referred to in this section.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>________________________________________________________<xhtml:br/>*The exercise of the powers and the performance of the duties conferred on the Minister by the provisions so marked has been delegated to the Central Bank of Kenya by L.N.18/1968.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7681"><num>32</num><heading>SECTION 32 Companies.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>32</xhtml:b>.* (1) Where there is served on a person resident in Companies. Kenya a notice in writing that the Minister wishes any requirements hereinafter mentioned to be complied with by a body corporate specified in the Second Schedule in this subsection and in subsection (2) referred to as a foreign company), and that person can, by doing or refraining from doing any act - 
<xhtml:p>(a) cause the foreign company to comply with any of the requirements; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) remove any obstacle to the foreign company complying with any of the requirements; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) render it in any respect more probable that the foreign company will comply with any of the requirements, then, except so far as permission to the contrary may be given by the Minister, that person shall do, or, as the case may be, refrain from doing, that act.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) The requirements with respect to which such a notice may be given are that the foreign company shall - <xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(a) furnish to the Minister such particulars as to its assets and business as may be mentioned in the notice:<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(b) sell or procure the sale to an authorized dealer of any gold or specified currency mentioned in the notice, being gold or a specified currency which it is entitled to sell or of which it is entitled to procure the sale;<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(c) declare and pay such dividend as may be mentioned in the notice;<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(d) realize any of its assets mentioned in the notice in such manner as may be so mentioned;<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(e) refrain from selling, transferring, or doing anything which affects its rights or powers in relation to any such securities as may be mentioned in the notice.<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(3) (a) Except with the permission of the Minister, no person resident in Kenya shall do any act whereby a body corporate which is by any means controlled (whether directly or indirectly) by persons resident in Kenya ceases to be controlled by persons resident in Kenya:<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>Provided that this subsection shall not prohibit any person from selling securities authorized to be dealt in on any recognized stock exchange in Kenya if the sale takes place in pursuance of an agreement entered into in the ordinary course of business on that exchange.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) No person resident in the scheduled territories shall in Kenya do any act which involves, is in association with or is preparatory to any transaction outside Kenya referred to in paragraph (a).</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) (a) Except with the permission of the Minister, no person resident in Kenya shall lend money or securities to a body corporate resident in the scheduled territories which is by any means controlled (whether directly or indirectly) by persons resident outside the scheduled territories:</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Provided that this subsection shall not apply where the lender after making such inquiries as are reasonable in the circumstances of the case does not know and has no reason to suspect that the body corporate is so controlled,</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) No person resident in the scheduled territories shall in Kenya do any act which involves, is in association with or is preparatory to any transaction outside Kenya referred to in paragraph (a).</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(5) For the purposes of this section and of the Second Schedule, persons resident in Kenya or outside the scheduled territories shall be deemed to control a body corporate notwithstanding that other persons are associated with them in the control thereof if they can together override those other persons.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(6) In this section "security" includes a secondary security<xhtml:br/>____________________________________________________________<xhtml:br/>*The exercise of the powers and the performance of the duties conferred on the Minister by the provisions so marked has been delegated to the Central Bank of Kenya by L.N.18/1968.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7682"><num>33</num><heading>SECTION 33 Exemptions.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>33.</xhtml:b>Any provision of this Act imposing obligation or prohibition shall have effect subject to such exemptions as may be granted by order of the Minister, and any such exemption may be either absolute or conditional.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7683"><num>34</num><heading>SECTION 34 Blocked accounts.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>34.</xhtml:b>* Where - 
<xhtml:p>(a) under any provision of Part III, the permission of the Minister is required for the making of a payment or the placing of any sum to the credit of any person resident outside the scheduled territories; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) any payment falls to be made by an authorized dealer on the sale of any gold or specified currency by foreign company within the meaning of section 32 (1), being a sale made to comply with any requirement notified under that subsection,</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>the Minister may direct that the sum payable or to be credited shall be paid or credited to a blocked account only, and where such a direction is given the provisions of the Third Schedule shall have effect in relation to the payment or crediting of the sum.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7684"><num>35</num><heading>SECTION 35 Contracts, legal proceedings, etc.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>35.</xhtml:b>(1) It shall be an implied condition in any contract that, where, by virtue of this Act, the permission or consent of the Minister is at the time of the contract required for the performance of any term thereof, that term shall not be performed except in so far as the permission or consent is given or is not required: 
<xhtml:p>Provided that this subsection shall not apply in so far as it is shown to be inconsistent with the intention of the parties that it should apply, whether by reason of their having contemplated the performance of that term in spite of this Act or for any other reason.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) Notwithstanding anything in the Bills of Exchange Act, neither the provisions of this Act, nor any condition whether express or to be implied having regard to those provisions, that any payment shall not be made without the permission of the Minister under this Act shall be deemed to prevent an instrument being a bill of exchange or promissory note.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) The Fourth Schedule shall have effect with respect to legal proceedings, arbitrations, bankruptcy proceedings, the administration of the estates of deceased persons, the winding up of companies and the proceedings under deeds of arrangement or trust deeds on behalf of creditors.<xhtml:br/>______________________________________________________________<xhtml:br/>*The exercise of the powers and the performance of the duties conferred on the Minister by the provisions so marked has been delegated to the Central Bank of Kenya by L.N.18/1968.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7685"><num>36</num><heading>SECTION 36 Enforcement and admission.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>36</xhtml:b>. (1) The Fifth Schedule shall have effect for the purposes of the enforcement of this Act. 
<xhtml:p>(2)* Persons belonging to the following classes - <xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(a) bankers, authorized dealers, authorized depositaries;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) persons to whom any powers of the competent authority under this Act are delegated;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) persons who with the permission of the competent authority are in possession of documents which would, but for the permission, have to be in the custody of an authorized depositary;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(d) persons concerned with the keeping of any register in Kenya; and</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(e) persons entrusted with the payment of capital moneys, dividends or interest in Kenya,</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>shall comply with such directions as may be given to them respectively by the Minister, being - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(i) in the case of any such persons, directions as respects the exercise of any functions exercisable by them by virtue of, or by virtue of anything done under, this Act; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(ii) in the case of authorized dealers, directions under paragraph (i) or directions as to the terms on which they are to accept gold or foreign currency or directions requiring them to offer their gold or specified currency for sale to the Minister on such terms as may be specified therein.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) For the purposes of any proceedings which may be taken against any person in respect of an offence punishable under this Act. a document purporting to be a copy of any banking document shall be evidence of the contents of the banking document, and of the matters, transactions and accounts therein recorded, until the contrary is proved, notwithstanding section 177 (1) of the Evidence Act.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) A banker or officer of a bank shall not, in any proceedings to which the bank is not a party, be compelled to produce any banking document the contents of which can be evidenced by a copy under subsection (3), nor shall he be summoned or called as a witness to prove any matters, transactions or accounts therein recorded.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>__________________________________________________________<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>*The exercise of the powers and the performance of the duties conferred on the Minister by the provisions so marked! has been delegated to the Central Bank of Kenya -by L.N.18/1968.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7686"><num>37</num><heading>SECTION 37 Application Government.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>37</xhtml:b>. This Act shall bind the Government and shall apply to transactions by a Government department or other person acting on behalf of the Government, and the competent authority shall not, by virtue of any contract made by them or on their behalf in relation to any payments or securities, be under any obligation to grant permission under Part III or Part IV or any exemption from those Parts unless that contract is signed or countersigned in accordance-with section 8 of the Government Contract Act (which provides that certain provisions in Government contracts shall be subject to the express authority of the Treasury or is made under the External Loans and Credits Act.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7687"><num>38</num><heading>SECTION 38 Treasury orders.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>38</xhtml:b>. The Minister may by order make such transitional provisions as appear to him necessary or expedient in consequence of the exercise by any authority of any other power to make orders under this Act.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7688"><num>39</num><heading>SECTION 39 Other powers.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>39.</xhtml:b>(1) Any permission, consent or authority granted under this Act - 
<xhtml:p>(a) may be either general or special;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) may be revoked by the competent authority;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) may be absolute or conditional;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(d) may be limited so as to expire on a specified date, unless renewed; and<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(e) shall be published in such a way as, in the opinion of the competent authority, to give any person entitled to the benefit of it an adequate opportunity of getting to know of it, unless in his opinion publication is not necessary for that purpose.<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(2) Any directions given under this Act - <xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(a) may be either general or special;<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(b) may be revoked or varied by subsequent directions; and<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(c) shall be given to such persons and in such manner as the competent authority thinks appropriate, and if so given shall be valid for all purposes.<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(3) Notwithstanding paragraph (c) of subsection (2), a person shall not by virtue of any direction given by the competent authority under this Act be convicted of an offence under this Act, unless the direction was served on him or he knew or avoided getting to know, of the giving thereof:<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>Provided that. where reasonable steps were taken for the purpose of bringing the purport of the direction to his notice, it shall be for him to show that he neither knew nor avoided getting to know of the giving thereof.<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(4) The competent authority may, to such extent and subject to such restrictions and conditions as he may think proper, delegate or authorize the delegation of any of his powers (other than. power to make orders or to give authority to apply for a search warrant) to any person, or class or description of persons, approved by him, and references in this Act shall be construed accordingly.<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(5) A document stating that permission, consent, authority or direction is given under any provision of this Act by the competent authority, and purporting to be signed on his behalf, shall be evidence of the facts stated in the document.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7689"><num>39A</num><heading>SECTION 39A Rules.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>39A.</xhtml:b>The Minister may make rules prescribing the fees payable on application for any permission, consent or authority required under this Act.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7690"><num>40</num><heading>SECTION 40 Financial provisions.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>40</xhtml:b>. Any expenses incurred under or by virtue of this Act by a Government department shall be paid out of moneys provided by Parliament and any sums received under or by virtue of this Act by a Government department shall be paid into the Consolidated Fund.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7691"><num>41</num><heading>SECTION 41 Branches.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>41</xhtml:b>. (1) The Minister may by order or direction provide that, for such of the purposes of this Act as may be specified in the order or direction - 
<xhtml:p>(a) any transaction with or by a branch of any business, whether carried on by a body corporate or otherwise. shall be treated in all respects as if the branch were a body corporate resident where the branch is situated;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) the making of any book entry or other statement recording a debit against a branch of any business in favour of any other branch of that business shall be treated as a payment to that other branch; and</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) any property held by or on behalf of the person carrying on the business shall be deemed to be held by such of the branches of the business as may be determined in accordance with the order or direction,</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>and any such order or direction which makes, for any of the purposes of Part VI, such provision as is mentioned in paragraph (c) may contain provisions declaring the circumstances in which a branch is to be treated as a nominee for any other branch.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) Any reference in subsection (1) to a branch of a business shall be deemed to include a reference to the head office of that business.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) Subsections (1) and (2) shall apply in relation to any body of persons (whether corporate or unincorporated) carrying on any activity, whether for the purpose of profit or not, as they apply in relation to a business.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7692"><num>42</num><heading>SECTION 42 Persons leaving the scheduled territories.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>42</xhtml:b>* Where a person resident in Kenya leaves the scheduled territories, the Minister may before, at or after the time he leaves the scheduled territories direct that, for such period as may be specified in the direction, payments by him or on his behalf and to him or to his credit and transactions in or in relation to securities or secondary securities in which he is in any way concerned shall, whether or not he continues to be resident in Kenya, be subject to such restrictions as may be specified in the direction.<xhtml:br/>________________________________________________________<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>*The exercise of the powers and the performance of the duties conferred on the Minister by the provisions so marked has been delegated to the Central Bank of Kenya by L.N.18/1968.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7693"><num>43</num><heading>SECTION 43 Determination of residence.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>43</xhtml:b>.* (1) For the purposes of this Act, a personal representative of a deceased person shall, unless the Minister otherwise directs, be treated as a resident in the territory where the deceased person was resident for the purposes in question at the time of his death and as not resident elsewhere, so far as relates to any matters in which the personal representative is concerned solely in his capacity as such. 
<xhtml:p>(2) The Minister may give directions declaring that for all or any of the purposes of this Act a person is to be treated as resident or not resident in such territories as may be specified in the directions.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) For the purposes of any proceedings which may be taken against a person in respect of an offence under this Act, the court shall presume, until the contrary is proved, that the residence of a person at the time of the commission of the offence was as stated in the charge or information containing the particulars of the offence with which the person is charged. _________________________________________________________<xhtml:br/>*The exercise of the powers and the performance of the duties conferred on the Minister by the provisions so marked has been delegated to the Central Bank of Kenya by L.N.18/1968.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7694"><num>44</num><heading>SECTION 44 Acquisition by Minister of certain securities.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>44</xhtml:b>. (1) The Minister may by order direct - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) that, subject to any exemptions for which provision may be made by the order, no person shall, except with permission granted by or on behalf of the Minister, sell, transfer or do anything which involves the creation of a charge on, or affects his rights or powers in relation to, securities of any such class as may be specified in the order, being a class of securities which, in the opinion of the Minister, are likely to be marketable outside Kenya; and</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) that the owner of any securities of that class shall, in such manner and within such period as may be specified in the order, make a return to the Minister giving such particulars with respect to those securities as may be so specified;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>and for the purposes of this subsection a person who mortgages or pledges a security shall be deemed thereby to create a charge on the security.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) At any time while an order made under subsection (1) with respect to securities of any class is in force, the Minister, if he is of opinion that it is expedient so to do for the purpose of strengthening the financial position of Kenya, may, by an order made generally with respect to any specified securities of that class, or by directions given with respect to any securities of that class of which any particular person is the owner, transfer to himself the securities to which the order or directions relates or relate, at a price specified in the order or directions being a price which, in the opinion of the Minister, is not less than the market value of the securities on the date of the making of the order or the giving of the directions:<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>Provided that. where the Minister has by an order made under this subsection transferred to himself securities in respect of which returns had before the date of the making of that order been made to him under an order made under subsection (1), then, if by an order or directions subsequently made or given under this subsection the Minister transfers to himself securities which would have been transferred to him under the former order if such a return had been made before that date. the minimum price at which the securities may be transferred shall be the price specified in the former order subject to such reduction as the Minister thinks fit in respect of any dividend or interest payable since the date of the making of that order, or a price which in the opinion of the Minister is the market value of the securities on the date of the making or giving of the subsequent order or directions, whichever is the less.<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(3) Where any order is made, or directions given, under subsection (2) with respect to securities - <xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(a) those securities shall forthwith vest in the Minister free from any mortgage, pledge or charge, and the Minister may deal with the securities as he thinks fit;<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(b) the owner of any of those securities, and any person who is responsible for keeping any register or book in which any of those securities is registered or inscribed or who is otherwise concerned with the registration or inscription of any of those securities, shall do all such things as are necessary or as the Minister may direct to be done for the purpose of securing that the security and any document of title relating thereto will be delivered to the Minister or to such person as the Minister may direct, and, in the case of any registered or inscribed security, that the security will be registered or inscribed in the name of the Minister or such person as the Minister may direct.<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(4) The duty to deliver a security under subsection (3) shall include a duty to do all things necessary to secure that any dividends or interest on that security becoming payable on or after the date of the making of the order or the giving of the directions will be paid to the Minister, and, where in the case of a security payable to bearer which is delivered in pursuance of that subsection any coupons representing dividends or interest are not delivered with the security, such reduction in the price payable therefore shall be made as the Minister thinks fit:<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>Provided that, where the price specified in the order or directions in relation to any securities is ex any dividend or ex any interest, this subsection shall not apply to that dividend or interest or to any coupon representing it,<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(5) A certificate signed by a person authorized in that behalf by the Minister that specified securities are securities transferred to the Minister under this section shall be treated by all persons responsible for keeping any registers or books in which the securities are registered or inscribed, or who are otherwise concerned with the registration or inscription of those securities, as conclusive evidence that the securities have been so transferred.<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(6) Where, by virtue of paragraph (a) of subsection (3), a security has become vested in the Minister, then, at any time before the steps required by paragraph (b) of that subsection to be taken in relation to that security have been taken, the Minister may, by a declaration made in writing by him or on his behalf, divest himself of the security; and thereupon the order or directions in consequence of which the security so became vested in the Minister shall be deemed, for all purposes, not to have been made or given with respect to that security.<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(7) For the purposes of this section, "security" does not include - <xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(a) an annuity granted under the Government Annuities Act, 1929, of the United Kingdom, or an annuity to which either Part 1 or Part II of that Act applies; or<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(b) a life assurance policy or other contract entered into with an assurance company for securing the payment n the future of any capital sum or sums or of an annuity.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7695"><num>45</num><heading>SECTION 45 Power of Minister to direct sale of certain securities.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>45.</xhtml:b>Where the Minister has by an order made under section 44 (2) transferred to himself securities in respect of which returns had before the date of the making of that order been made to the Minister under an order made under subsection (1) of that section, he may give directions to the owner of any security which would have been transferred to him under the order if such a return had been made before that date requiring him to take such steps as may be specified in the directions to sell, or to procure the sale of. the security.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7696"><num>46</num><heading>SECTION 46 Custody and disposition of documents of title to securities.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>46</xhtml:b>. The Minister may give such directions as to the custody and disposition of documents of title relating to securities, or relating to any class or description of securities specified in the direction, as appear to the Minister to be expedient.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7697"><num>47</num><heading>SECTION 47 Power of Minister to prohibit action on certain orders as to gold, etc.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>47</xhtml:b>. (1) Where the Minister is satisfied that, owing to the changes in the external or internal position of any country or territory, action is being, or is likely to be. taken to the detriment of the economic position of Kenya, the Minister may give general or special directions prohibiting, either absolutely or to such extent as may be specified in the directions, the carrying out. except with permission granted by or on behalf of the Minister, of any order given by or on behalf of the government of that country or territory or any person resident therein at the time when the directions were given or at any later time while the directions are in force, in so far as the order - 
<xhtml:p>(a) requires the person to whom the order is given to make any payment or to part with any gold or securities; or<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(b) requires any change to be made in the persons to whose credit any sum is to stand or to whose order any gold or securities are to be held.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) Where directions are given under this section with respect to any country or territory, a branch in that country or territory of any business, whether carried on by a body corporate or otherwise, shall, for the purposes of this section, be treated in all respects as if the branch were a body corporate resident in that country or territory.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section></body><outOfLines><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-18818" id="w951aab1b9b1" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"/></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-18819" id="w951aab1b9b3" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"/></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-18820" id="w951aab1b9b5" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"/></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7646" id="w951aab1b9b7" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Short title</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7647" id="w951aab1b9b9" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Interpretation. 44 of 1952, Sch., 19 of 1965, s.2 and Sch., 17 of 1968, s.2.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7648" id="w951aab1b9c11" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Dealings in gold and foreign currency. 44 of 1952, Sch., 19 of 1965,s.2 and Sch.  
<xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7649" id="w951aab1b9c13" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Surrender of gold and foreign currency. 44 of 1952, Sch., 19 of 1965, Sch.  
<xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7650" id="w951aab1b9c15" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Bailees of gold and foreign currency.  
<xhtml:p>.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7651" id="w951aab1b9c17" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Travelers' cheques, etc. 44 of 1952, Sch., 19 of 1965, s. 2 and Sch.  
<xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7652" id="w951aab1b9c19" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Payments in Kenya.  
<xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7653" id="w951aab1b9c21" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Payments outside Kenya. 19 of l965.Sch.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7654" id="w951aab1b9c23" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Compensation deals. 19 of l965.Sch Payments in Kenya. .  
<xhtml:p/><xhtml:p> .</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7655" id="w951aab1b9c25" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Issue of securities. 19 of 1965, Sch.  
<xhtml:p> .</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7656" id="w951aab1b9c27" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Transfer of securities and coupons.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7657" id="w951aab1b9c29" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Issue of bearer certificates and coupons. 9 of 1965, B. 2.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7658" id="w951aab1b9c31" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Substitution of securities and certificates outside Kenya. 19 of I965, Sch.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7659" id="w951aab1b9c33" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Payment of capital money outside Kenya. 19 of 1965, Sch.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7660" id="w951aab1b9c35" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Duties of person keeping registers. 18 of 1963, a. 2.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7661" id="w951aab1b9c37" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Additional provisions as to nominee holdings.  
<xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7662" id="w951aab1b9c39" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Deposit of certificates of title. 19 of 1965, Sch.  
<xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7663" id="w951aab1b9c41" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Additional provisions as to deposited certificates.  
<xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7664" id="w951aab1b9c43" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Special provisions as to dealings in certain securities. 19 of 1965,Sch.  
<xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7665" id="w951aab1b9c45" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Validation of certain transfers.  
<xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7666" id="w951aab1b9c47" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Application of Part to secondary securities.  
<xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7667" id="w951aab1b9c49" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Interpretation of Part.  
<xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7668" id="w951aab1b9c51" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Restrictions on import. 19 of 1965. Sen.  
<xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7669" id="w951aab1b9c53" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Payment for imports. 17 of 1987, s. 2.  
<xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7670" id="w951aab1b9c55" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">General restrictions on export. 44 of 1952, Sch., 19 of 1965, Sch.  
<xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7671" id="w951aab1b9c57" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Payment for exports. 17 of 1987,s.3.  
<xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7672" id="w951aab1b9c59" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Withholding etc. of payment for export prohibited. 17 of 1987,s.4.  
<xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7673" id="w951aab1b9c61" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Provisions relating to export documents. 17 of 1987,s.4.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7674" id="w951aab1b9c63" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Payment for services. 17 of 1987, a.4.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7675" id="w951aab1b9c65" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Duty to collect certain debts. 44 of 1952. Sch., 19 of 1965. s. 2.  
<xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7676" id="w951aab1b9c67" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Duty not to delay sale or importation of goods.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7677" id="w951aab1b9c69" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Property obtained by infringement of Act.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7678" id="w951aab1b9c71" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Provisions supplemental to preceding provisions of Part. 44 of l952, Sch., 19of l965, Sch.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7679" id="w951aab1b9c73" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Transfer of annulties, policies, etc.  
<xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7680" id="w951aab1b9c75" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Settlements.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7681" id="w951aab1b9c77" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Companies.  
<xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7682" id="w951aab1b9c79" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Exemptions.  
<xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7683" id="w951aab1b9c81" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Blocked accounts.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7684" id="w951aab1b9c83" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Contracts, legal proceedings, etc.  
<xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p>Cap. 27.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7685" id="w951aab1b9c85" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Enforcement and admission. 17 of 1968,s.3.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7686" id="w951aab1b9c87" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Application to Government. L.N.303/1964, 8 of 1978,s.3. 18 of 1979, Sch. Cap. 25. Cap. 422.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7687" id="w951aab1b9c89" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Treasury orders.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7688" id="w951aab1b9c91" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Other powers.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7689" id="w951aab1b9c93" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Rules. 18 of 1963.s.3.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7690" id="w951aab1b9c95" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Financial provisions.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7691" id="w951aab1b9c97" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Branches.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7692" id="w951aab1b9c99" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Persons leaving the scheduled territories.  
<xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7693" id="w951aab1b9d101" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Determination of residence. 17 of 1968, s.4.  
<xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7694" id="w951aab1b9d103" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Acquisition by Minister of certain securities.  
<xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p>19 and 20 Geo.5. 29.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7695" id="w951aab1b9d105" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Power of Minister to direct sale of certain securities.  
<xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7696" id="w951aab1b9d107" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Custody and disposition of documents of title to securities.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7697" id="w951aab1b9d109" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Power of Minister to prohibit action on certain orders as to gold, etc. 44 of 1952, Sch.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine></outOfLines></act></akomaNtoso>