<akomaNtoso xmlns:an="http://www.akomantoso.org/1.0"><act contains="singleVersion"><meta><identification source="#kenyalaw"><FRBRWork><FRBRthis value="/ke/act/1927-05-14/27/main"/><FRBRuri value="/ke/act/1927-05-14/27"/><FRBRdate date="1927-05-14" name="Generation"/><FRBRauthor as="#author" href="#parliament"/><components><component href="#emain" id="wmain" name="main" showAs="Main Document"/></components></FRBRWork><FRBRExpression><FRBRthis value="/ke/act/1927-05-14/27/eng@/main"/><FRBRuri value="/ke/act/1927-05-14/27/eng@"/><FRBRdate date="1927-05-14" name="Generation"/><FRBRauthor as="#author" href="#parliament"/><components><component href="#mmain" id="emain" name="main" showAs="Main Document"/></components></FRBRExpression><FRBRManifestation><FRBRthis value="/ke/act/1927-05-14/27/eng@/main.xml"/><FRBRuri value="/ke/act/1927-05-14/27/eng@/.akn"/><FRBRdate date="1927-05-14" name="Generation"/><FRBRauthor as="#author" href="#parliament"/><components><component href="#mmain" id="mmain" name="main" showAs="Main Document"/></components></FRBRManifestation></identification><publication date="1927-05-14" name="" showAs=""/><lifecycle source="#bungeni"><event date="1927-05-14" id="e1" source="#ro1" type="generation"/></lifecycle><references source="#kenyalaw"><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActTitle" id="TheActTitle" showAs="Act Title"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActLongTitle" id="TheActLongTitle" showAs="Act Description"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/AssentDate" id="AssentDate" showAs="Assent Date"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/CommencementDate" id="CommencementDate" showAs="Commencement Date"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActNumber" id="TheActNumber" showAs="Act Number"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActID" id="TheActID" showAs="Act ID"/><TLCConcept href="http://bungeni-lexmigrate.googlecode.com" id="bungeni" showAs="Lex Migrator"/><TLCConcept href="http://kenyalaw.org" id="kenyalaw" showAs="Kenya Law"/></references><proprietary xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" source="#kenyalaw"><kl:meta name="gokcatid" num="4"/><kl:meta name="gokcatname">Civil Law and Procedure</kl:meta><kl:meta name="lexyy" num="1927"/><kl:meta name="lexmm" num="5"/><kl:meta name="lexdd" num="14"/></proprietary></meta><preface><block name="preface"><docTitle id="ActTitle" refersTo="#TheActTitle">Bills of Exchange</docTitle><docTitle id="ActLongTitle" refersTo="#TheActLongTitle">An Act of Parliament relating to bills of exchange, cheques and promissory notes</docTitle><docDate date="1927-05-14" refersTo="#CommencementDate">May 14, 1927</docDate><docDate date="1111-11-11" refersTo="#AssentDate">Nov 11, 1111</docDate><docNumber id="ActNumber" refersTo="#TheActNumber">27</docNumber><docNumber id="ActIdentifier" refersTo="#TheActID">29</docNumber></block></preface><preamble><p>ARRANGEMENT OF SECTIONS</p><toc><tocItem href="#part-1257" level="0">I PRELIMINARY</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12268" level="2">1 Short title.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12269" level="2">2 Interpretation.</tocItem><tocItem href="#part-1258" level="0">II BILLS OF EXCHANGE</tocItem><tocItem href="#sectionheading-38" level="1"> Bill in a Set</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12338" level="2">71 Rules as to sets.</tocItem><tocItem href="#sectionheading-37" level="1"> Conflict of Laws</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12338" level="2">71 Rules as to sets.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12339" level="2">72 Rules where laws conflict.</tocItem><tocItem href="#part-664" level="0">III CHEQUES ON A BANKER</tocItem><tocItem href="#sectionheading-36" level="1"> Crossed Cheques</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12343" level="2">76 General and special crossings defined.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12344" level="2">77 Crossing by drawer or after issue.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12345" level="2">78 Crossing a material part of cheque.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12346" level="2">79 Duties of banker as to crossed cheques.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12347" level="2">80 Protection to banker and drawer where cheque is crossed.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12348" level="2">81 Effect of words &amp;quot;not negotiable&amp;quot;.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-20970" level="2">81A Non-transferable cheques.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12349" level="2">82 Provisions as to crossed cheques to apply to certain other instruments.</tocItem><tocItem href="#part-663" level="0">IV PROMISSORY NOTES</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12350" level="2">84 Application to bankers&amp;apos; drafts. Promissory note defined.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12351" level="2">85 Delivery necessary.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12352" level="2">86 Joint and several notes.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12353" level="2">87 Note payable on demand.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12354" level="2">88 Presentment of note for payment.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12355" level="2">89 Liability of maker.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12356" level="2">90 Application of Part I to notes.</tocItem><tocItem href="#part-662" level="0">V SUPPLEMENTARY</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12357" level="2">91 Good faith.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12358" level="2">92 Signature.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12359" level="2">93 Computation of time.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12360" level="2">94 When noting equivalent to protest.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12361" level="2">95 Protest when notary not accessible.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12362" level="2">96 Dividend warrants may be crossed.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12363" level="2">97 Savings.</tocItem></toc></preamble><body><part id="part-1257"><num>I</num><heading>PART I PRELIMINARY</heading><section id="section-12268"><num>1</num><heading>SECTION 1 Short title.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:div><xhtml:b>1. </xhtml:b>This Act may be cited as the Bills of Exchange Act. 
</xhtml:div></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12269"><num>2</num><heading>SECTION 2 Interpretation.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>2. </xhtml:b>In this Act, except where the context otherwise requires - <xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/> "acceptance" means an acceptance completed by delivery or notification;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> "action" includes counterclaim and set-off;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> “bank” has the meaning assigned in section 2 of the Banking Act;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> "banker" includes a body of persons whether incorporated or not who carry on the business of banking;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> "bankrupt" includes any person whose estate is vested in a trustee or assignee under the law for the time being in force relating to bankruptcy;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> "bearer" means the person in possession of a bill or note which is payable to bearer;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> "bill" means bill of exchange;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> “Central Bank” means the Central Bank of Kenya established under section 3 of the Central Bank of Kenya Act;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> “cheque truncation” means a system of cheque clearing and settlement between banks based on electronic data or images or both electronic data and images, without the conventional physical exchange of instruments;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> "delivery" means transfer of possession, actual or constructive from one person to another;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> "endorsement" means an endorsement completed by delivery;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> "holder" means the payee or endorsee of a bill or note who is in possession of it, or the bearer thereof;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> "issue" means the first delivery of a bill or note, complete in form, to a person who takes it as a holder;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> “Minister” means the Minister for the time being responsible for matters relating to finance.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> "note" means promissory note;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> "value" means valuable consideration.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section></part><part id="part-1258"><num>II</num><heading>PART II BILLS OF EXCHANGE</heading><subpart id="subpart-38"><num/><heading>SECTIONHEADING  Bill in a Set</heading><section id="section-12338"><num>71</num><heading>SECTION 71 Rules as to sets.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>71.</xhtml:b> (1) Where a bill is drawn in a set, each part of the set being numbered, and containing a reference to the other parts, the whole of the parts constitute one bill.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> (2) Where the holder of a set endorses two or more parts to different persons, he is liable on every part, and every endorser subsequent to him is liable on the part he has himself endorsed as if those parts were separate bills.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> (3) Where two or more parts of a set are negotiated to different holders in due course, the holder whose title first accrues is as between such holders deemed the true owner of the bill; but nothing in this subsection shall affect the rights of a person who in due course accepts or pays the part first presented to him.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> (4) The acceptance may be written on any part, and it must be written on one part only; but if the drawee accepts more than one part, and the accepted parts get into the hands of different holders in due course, he is liable on every part as if it were a separate bill.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> (5) When the acceptor of a bill drawn in a set pays it without requiring the part bearing his acceptance to be delivered up to him, and that part at maturity is outstanding in the hands of a holder in due course, he is liable to the holder thereof.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> (6) Subject to the preceding rules, where any one part of a bill drawn in a set is discharged by payment or otherwise, the whole bill is discharged.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section></subpart><subpart id="subpart-37"><num/><heading>SECTIONHEADING  Conflict of Laws</heading><section id="section-12338"><num>71</num><heading>SECTION 71 Rules as to sets.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>71.</xhtml:b> (1) Where a bill is drawn in a set, each part of the set being numbered, and containing a reference to the other parts, the whole of the parts constitute one bill.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> (2) Where the holder of a set endorses two or more parts to different persons, he is liable on every part, and every endorser subsequent to him is liable on the part he has himself endorsed as if those parts were separate bills.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> (3) Where two or more parts of a set are negotiated to different holders in due course, the holder whose title first accrues is as between such holders deemed the true owner of the bill; but nothing in this subsection shall affect the rights of a person who in due course accepts or pays the part first presented to him.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> (4) The acceptance may be written on any part, and it must be written on one part only; but if the drawee accepts more than one part, and the accepted parts get into the hands of different holders in due course, he is liable on every part as if it were a separate bill.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> (5) When the acceptor of a bill drawn in a set pays it without requiring the part bearing his acceptance to be delivered up to him, and that part at maturity is outstanding in the hands of a holder in due course, he is liable to the holder thereof.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> (6) Subject to the preceding rules, where any one part of a bill drawn in a set is discharged by payment or otherwise, the whole bill is discharged.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12339"><num>72</num><heading>SECTION 72 Rules where laws conflict.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>72.</xhtml:b> Where a bill drawn in one country is negotiated, accepted, or payable in another, the rights, duties and liabilities of the parties thereto are determined as follows -</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> (a) the validity of a bill as regards requisites in form is determined by the law of the place of issue, and the validity as regards requisites in form of the supervening contracts, such as acceptance or endorsement or acceptance <xhtml:em>supra</xhtml:em> protest, is determined by the law of the place where such contract was made:</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> Provided that -</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> (i) where a bill is issued out of Kenya it is not invalid by reason only that it is not stamped in accordance with the law of the place of issue;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> (ii) where a bill issued out of Kenya conforms, as regards requisites in form, to the law of Kenya, it may, for the purpose of enforcing payment thereof, be treated as valid as between all persons who negotiate, hold, or become parties to it in Kenya;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> (b) subject to the provisions of this Act, the interpretation of the drawing, endorsement, acceptance or acceptance <xhtml:em>supra</xhtml:em> protest of a bill, is determined by the law of the place where the contract is made:</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> Provided that where an inland bill is endorsed in a foreign country the endorsement shall, as regards the payer, be interpreted according to the law of Kenya;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> (c) the duties of the holder with respect to presentment for acceptance or payment, and the necessity for or sufficiency of a protest or notice of dishonour, or otherwise, are determined by the law of the place where the act is done or the bill is dishonoured;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> (d) where a bill is drawn out of but payable in Kenya and the sum payable is not expressed in the currency of Kenya, the amount shall, in the absence of some express stipulation, be calculated according to the rate of exchange for sight drafts at the place of payment on the day the bill is payable;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> (e) where a bill is drawn in one country and is payable in another, the due date thereof is determined according to the law of the place where it is payable.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section></subpart></part><part id="part-664"><num>III</num><heading>PART III CHEQUES ON A BANKER</heading><subpart id="subpart-36"><num/><heading>SECTIONHEADING  Crossed Cheques</heading><section id="section-12343"><num>76</num><heading>SECTION 76 General and special crossings defined.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:em>Crossed Cheques<xhtml:br/></xhtml:em></xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:br/><xhtml:b>76.&#160; </xhtml:b>(1) Where a cheque bears across its face an addition of-</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> (a) the words "and company" or any abbreviation thereof between two parallel transverse lines, either with or without the words "not negotiable"; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> (b) two parallel transverse lines simply, either with or without the words "not negotiable",</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> that addition constitutes a crossing, and the cheque is crossed generally.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> (2) Where a cheque bears across its face an addition of the name of a banker, either with or without the words "not negotiable", that addition constitutes a crossing, and the cheque is crossed specially and to that banker.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12344"><num>77</num><heading>SECTION 77 Crossing by drawer or after issue.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>77.</xhtml:b> (1) A cheque may be crossed generally or specially by the drawer.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> (2) Where a cheque is uncrossed, the holder may cross it generally or specially.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> (3) Where a cheque is crossed generally, the holder may cross it specially.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> (4) Where a cheque is crossed generally or specially the holder may add the words "not negotiable".</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> (5) Where a cheque is crossed specially, the banker to whom it is crossed may again cross it specially to another banker for collection.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> (6) Where an uncrossed cheque, or a cheque crossed generally, is sent to a banker for collection, he may cross it specially to himself.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12345"><num>78</num><heading>SECTION 78 Crossing a material part of cheque.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>78. </xhtml:b>A crossing authorized by this Act is a material part of the cheque; and no person shall obliterate or, except as authorized by this Act, add to or alter the crossing.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12346"><num>79</num><heading>SECTION 79 Duties of banker as to crossed cheques.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>79.</xhtml:b> (1) Where a cheque is crossed specially to more than one banker, except when crossed to an agent for collection being a banker, the banker on whom it is drawn shall refuse payment thereof.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> (2) Where the banker on whom a cheque is drawn which is so crossed nevertheless pays it, or pays a cheque crossed generally otherwise than to a banker, or if crossed specially otherwise than to the banker to whom it is crossed, or his agent for collection being a banker, he is liable to the true owner of the cheque for any loss he may sustain owing to the cheque having been so paid :</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> Provided that where a cheque is presented for payment which does not at the time of presentment appear to be crossed, or to have had a crossing which has been obliterated, or to have been added to or altered otherwise than as authorized by this Act, the banker paying the cheque in good faith and without negligence shall not be responsible or incur any liability, nor shall the payment be questioned by reason of the cheque having been crossed, or of the crossing having been obliterated or having been added to or altered otherwise than as authorized by this Act, and of payment having been made otherwise than to a banker or to the banker to whom the cheque is or was crossed, or to his agent for collection being a banker, as the case may be.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12347"><num>80</num><heading>SECTION 80 Protection to banker and drawer where cheque is crossed.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>80.</xhtml:b> Where the banker, on whom a crossed cheque or cheque which either under section 81A or otherwise is not transferable is drawn, in good faith and without negligence pays it, if crossed generally, to a banker, and if crossed specially, to the banker to whom it is crossed, or his agent for collection being a banker, the banker paying the cheque, and, if the cheque has come into the hands of the payee, the drawer, shall respectively be entitled to the same rights and be placed in the same position as if payment of the cheque had been made to the true owner thereof.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12348"><num>81</num><heading>SECTION 81 Effect of words &amp;quot;not negotiable&amp;quot;.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>81.</xhtml:b> Where a person takes a crossed cheque which bears on it the words "not negotiable", he shall not have, and shall not be capable of giving, a better title to the cheque than that which the person from whom he took it had.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-20970"><num>81A</num><heading>SECTION 81A Non-transferable cheques.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>81A.</xhtml:b> (1) Where a cheque is crossed and bears across its face the words â€œaccount payeeâ€� or â€œa/c payeeâ€�, with or without the word â€œonlyâ€� the cheque is not transferable and is valid only between the parties thereto.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> (2) For the purposes of section 80, a banker is not negligent by reason only of his failure to concern himself with any purported endorsement of a cheque which either under subsection (1) or otherwise is not transferable.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12349"><num>82</num><heading>SECTION 82 Provisions as to crossed cheques to apply to certain other instruments.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>82.</xhtml:b> The foregoing provisions of this Part relating to the crossing of cheques and crossed cheques shall apply in relation to a prescribed instrument within the meaning of the Cheques Act (not being a cheque) as they apply to a cheque.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section></subpart></part><part id="part-663"><num>IV</num><heading>PART IV PROMISSORY NOTES</heading><section id="section-12350"><num>84</num><heading>SECTION 84 Application to bankers&amp;apos; drafts. Promissory note defined.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>84. </xhtml:b>(1) A promissory note is an unconditional promise in writing made by one person to another signed by the maker, engaging to pay, on demand or at a fixed or determinable future time, a sum certain in money, to, or to the order of, a specified person or to bearer.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> (2) An instrument in the form of a note payable to maker's order is not a note within the meaning of this section unless and until it is endorsed by the maker.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> (3) A note is not invalid by reason only that it contains also a pledge of collateral security with authority to sell or dispose thereof.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> (4) A note which is, or on the face of it purports to be, both made and payable within Kenya is an inland note; and any other note is a foreign note.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12351"><num>85</num><heading>SECTION 85 Delivery necessary.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>85.</xhtml:b> A promissory note is inchoate and incomplete until delivery thereof to the payee or bearer.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12352"><num>86</num><heading>SECTION 86 Joint and several notes.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>86.</xhtml:b> (1) A promissory note may be made by two or more makers, and they may be liable thereon jointly, or jointly and severally, according to its tenor.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> (2) Where a note runs "I promise to pay", and is signed by two or more persons, it is deemed to be their joint and several note.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12353"><num>87</num><heading>SECTION 87 Note payable on demand.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>87.</xhtml:b>(1) Where a note payable on demand has been endorsed, it must be presented for payment within a reasonable time of the endorsement; and if it be not so presented the endorser is discharged.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> (2) In determining what is a reasonable time, regard shall be had to the nature of the instrument, the usage of trade, and the facts of the particular case.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> (3) Where a note payable on demand is negotiated, it is not deemed to be overdue, for the purpose of affecting the holder with defects of title of which he had no notice, by reason that it appears that a reasonable time for presenting it for payment has elapsed since its issue.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12354"><num>88</num><heading>SECTION 88 Presentment of note for payment.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>88.</xhtml:b> (1) Where a promissory note is in the body of it made payable at a particular place, it must be presented for payment at that place in order to render the maker liable; but in any other case, presentment for payment is not necessary in order to render the maker liable.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> (2) Presentment for payment is necessary in order to render the endorser of a note liable.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> (3) Where a note is in the body of it made payable at a particular place, presentment at that place is necessary in order to render an endorser liable; but when a place of payment is indicated by way of memorandum only, presentment at that place is sufficient to render the endorser liable, but a presentment to the maker elsewhere, if sufficient in other respects, shall also suffice.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12355"><num>89</num><heading>SECTION 89 Liability of maker.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>89.</xhtml:b> The maker of a promissory note by making it -</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> (a) engages that he will pay it according to its tenor;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> (b) is precluded from denying to a holder in due course the existence of the payee and his then capacity to endorse.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12356"><num>90</num><heading>SECTION 90 Application of Part I to notes.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>90.</xhtml:b> (1) Subject to the provisions of this Part and except as provided by this section, the provisions of this Act relating to bills of exchange apply, with the necessary modifications, to promissory notes.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> (2) In applying those provisions the maker of a note shall be deemed to correspond with the acceptor of a bill, and the first endorser of a note shall be deemed to correspond with the drawer of an accepted bill payable to drawer's order.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> (3) The following provisions as to bills do not apply to notes, namely, provisions relating to -</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> (a) presentment for acceptance;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> (b) acceptance;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> (c) acceptance <xhtml:em>supra</xhtml:em> protest;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> (d) bills in a set.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> (4) Where a foreign note is dishonoured, protest thereof is unnecessary.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section></part><part id="part-662"><num>V</num><heading>PART V SUPPLEMENTARY</heading><section id="section-12357"><num>91</num><heading>SECTION 91 Good faith.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>91. </xhtml:b>A thing is deemed to be done in good faith within the meaning of this Act where it is in fact done honestly, whether it is done negligently or not.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12358"><num>92</num><heading>SECTION 92 Signature.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>92. </xhtml:b>(1) Where, by this Act, any instrument or writing is required to be signed by any person, it is not necessary that he should sign it with his own hand, but it is sufficient if his signature is written thereon by some other person by or under his authority.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> (2) In the case of a corporation, where by this Act any instrument or writing is required to be signed, it is sufficient if the instrument or writing be sealed with the corporate seal.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> (3) Nothing in this section shall be construed as requiring the bill or note of a corporation to be under seal.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12359"><num>93</num><heading>SECTION 93 Computation of time.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>93.</xhtml:b> (1) Where, by this Act, the time limited for doing any act or thing is less than three days, in reckoning time, non-business days are excluded.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> (2) "Non-business day" for the purposes of this Act means -</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> (a) in the case of any bill -</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> (i) a Sunday;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> (ii) a public holiday; or<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/> (iii) a bank holiday declared in respect of all banks under section 46 of the Banking Act; and also<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/> (b) in the case of a foreign bill, a Saturday,</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> and any other day is a business day.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12360"><num>94</num><heading>SECTION 94 When noting equivalent to protest.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>94.</xhtml:b>&#160; For the purposes of this Act, where a bill or note is required to be protested within a specified time, or before some further proceeding is taken, it is sufficient that the bill has been noted for protest before the expiration of the specified time or the taking of the proceeding; and the formal protest may be extended at any time thereafter as of the date of the noting.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12361"><num>95</num><heading>SECTION 95 Protest when notary not accessible.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>95.</xhtml:b> (1) Where a dishonoured bill or note is authorized or required to be protested, and the services of a notary cannot be obtained at the place where the bill is dishonoured, any householder or substantial resident of the place may, in the presence of two witnesses, give a certificate, signed by them, attesting the dishonour of the bill, and the certificate shall in all respects operate as if it were a formal protest of the bill.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> (2) The form set out in the Schedule may be used with necessary modifications, and if used shall be sufficient.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12362"><num>96</num><heading>SECTION 96 Dividend warrants may be crossed.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>96. </xhtml:b>The provisions of this Act as to crossed cheques shall apply to a warrant for payment of dividend.<xhtml:br/> &#160;</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12363"><num>97</num><heading>SECTION 97 Savings.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>97. </xhtml:b>(1) The rules in bankruptcy relating to bills of exchange, promissory notes, and cheques shall continue to apply thereto notwithstanding anything contained in this Act.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> (2) The rules of common law including the law merchant, save in so far as they are inconsistent with the express provisions of this Act, shall continue to apply to bills of exchange, promissory notes and cheques.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> (3) Nothing in this Act shall affect -</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> (a) the provisions of the Stamp Duty Act or any law or enactment for the time being in force relating to the revenue;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> (b) the provisions of the Companies Act or any Act relating to joint stock banks or companies;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> (c) the validity of any usage relating to dividend warrants, or the endorsements thereof.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section></part></body><outOfLines><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12268" id="w327aab1b9b1" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Short title.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12269" id="w327aab1b9b3" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Interpretation. 8 of 2009,s.31.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12338" id="w327aab1b9b5" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Rules as to sets.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12338" id="w327aab1b9b7" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Rules as to sets.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12339" id="w327aab1b9b9" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Rules where laws conflict.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12343" id="w327aab1b9c11" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">General and special crossings defined.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12344" id="w327aab1b9c13" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Crossing by drawer or after issue.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12345" id="w327aab1b9c15" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Crossing a material part of cheque.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12346" id="w327aab1b9c17" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Duties of banker as to crossed cheques.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12347" id="w327aab1b9c19" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Protection to banker and drawer where cheque is crossed. A 2 of 2002</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12348" id="w327aab1b9c21" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Effect of words "not negotiable".</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-20970" id="w327aab1b9c23" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Non-transferable cheques. A 2 of 2002.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12349" id="w327aab1b9c25" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Provisions as to crossed cheques to apply to certain other instruments. 41 of 1968, s. 7. Cap. 35.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12350" id="w327aab1b9c27" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Application to bankers' drafts. Promissory note defined.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12351" id="w327aab1b9c29" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Delivery necessary.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12352" id="w327aab1b9c31" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Joint and several notes.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12353" id="w327aab1b9c33" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Note payable on demand.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12354" id="w327aab1b9c35" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Presentment of note for payment.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12355" id="w327aab1b9c37" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Liability of maker.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12356" id="w327aab1b9c39" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Application of Part I to notes.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12357" id="w327aab1b9c41" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Good faith.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12358" id="w327aab1b9c43" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Signature.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12359" id="w327aab1b9c45" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Computation of time. 9 of 1973, s.3.Cap 488, A 9 of 1989</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12360" id="w327aab1b9c47" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">When noting equivalent to protest.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12361" id="w327aab1b9c49" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Protest when notary not accessible.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12362" id="w327aab1b9c51" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Dividend warrants may be crossed.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12363" id="w327aab1b9c53" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Savings. Cap.480. Cap.486.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine></outOfLines></act></akomaNtoso>