<akomaNtoso xmlns:an="http://www.akomantoso.org/1.0"><act contains="singleVersion"><meta><identification source="#kenyalaw"><FRBRWork><FRBRthis value="/ke/act/1962-10-30/18/main"/><FRBRuri value="/ke/act/1962-10-30/18"/><FRBRdate date="1962-10-30" name="Generation"/><FRBRauthor as="#author" href="#parliament"/><components><component href="#emain" id="wmain" name="main" showAs="Main Document"/></components></FRBRWork><FRBRExpression><FRBRthis value="/ke/act/1962-10-30/18/eng@/main"/><FRBRuri value="/ke/act/1962-10-30/18/eng@"/><FRBRdate date="1962-10-30" name="Generation"/><FRBRauthor as="#author" href="#parliament"/><components><component href="#mmain" id="emain" name="main" showAs="Main Document"/></components></FRBRExpression><FRBRManifestation><FRBRthis value="/ke/act/1962-10-30/18/eng@/main.xml"/><FRBRuri value="/ke/act/1962-10-30/18/eng@/.akn"/><FRBRdate date="1962-10-30" name="Generation"/><FRBRauthor as="#author" href="#parliament"/><components><component href="#mmain" id="mmain" name="main" showAs="Main Document"/></components></FRBRManifestation></identification><publication date="1962-10-30" name="" showAs=""/><lifecycle source="#bungeni"><event date="1962-10-30" id="e1" source="#ro1" type="generation"/></lifecycle><references source="#kenyalaw"><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActTitle" id="TheActTitle" showAs="Act Title"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActLongTitle" id="TheActLongTitle" showAs="Act Description"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/AssentDate" id="AssentDate" showAs="Assent Date"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/CommencementDate" id="CommencementDate" showAs="Commencement Date"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActNumber" id="TheActNumber" showAs="Act Number"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActID" id="TheActID" showAs="Act ID"/><TLCConcept href="http://bungeni-lexmigrate.googlecode.com" id="bungeni" showAs="Lex Migrator"/><TLCConcept href="http://kenyalaw.org" id="kenyalaw" showAs="Kenya Law"/></references><proprietary xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" source="#kenyalaw"><kl:meta name="gokcatid" num="3"/><kl:meta name="gokcatname">Courts and Officers of the Court</kl:meta><kl:meta name="lexyy" num="1962"/><kl:meta name="lexmm" num="10"/><kl:meta name="lexdd" num="30"/></proprietary></meta><preface><block name="preface"><docTitle id="ActTitle" refersTo="#TheActTitle">Law Society of Kenya</docTitle><docTitle id="ActLongTitle" refersTo="#TheActLongTitle">An Act of Parliament to consolidate the law relating to the Law Society of Kenya</docTitle><docDate date="1962-10-30" refersTo="#CommencementDate">Oct 30, 1962</docDate><docDate date="1111-11-11" refersTo="#AssentDate">Nov 11, 1111</docDate><docNumber id="ActNumber" refersTo="#TheActNumber">18</docNumber><docNumber id="ActIdentifier" refersTo="#TheActID">20</docNumber></block></preface><preamble><p>ARRANGEMENT OF SECTIONS</p><toc><tocItem href="#part-631" level="0">I PRELIMINARY</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10071" level="2">1 Short title.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10072" level="2">2 Interpretation.</tocItem><tocItem href="#part-632" level="0">II ESTABLISHMENT</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10073" level="2">3 Establishment of Law Society of Kenya.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10074" level="2">4 Objects of Society.</tocItem><tocItem href="#part-633" level="0">III MEMBERSHIP</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10075" level="2">5 Membership.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10076" level="2">6 Special membership.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10077" level="2">7 Honorary membership.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10078" level="2">8 Subscriptions.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10079" level="2">9 No entrance fee.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10080" level="2">10 Resignations.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10081" level="2">11 Expulsion.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10082" level="2">12 Members ceasing to be qualified for membership.</tocItem><tocItem href="#part-634" level="0">IV COUNCIL</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10083" level="2">13 Constitution of Council.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10084" level="2">14 Powers of Council.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10085" level="2">15 Committees and delegation of powers.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10086" level="2">16 Procedure.</tocItem><tocItem href="#part-635" level="0">V OTHER OFFICERS</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10087" level="2">17 Officers of Society.</tocItem><tocItem href="#part-636" level="0">VI GENERAL MEETINGS</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10088" level="2">18 Ordinary general meeting.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10089" level="2">19 Special general meetings.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10090" level="2">20 General meeting to act by simple majority vote.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10091" level="2">21 Alteration of resolutions.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10092" level="2">22 Convening and procedure.</tocItem><tocItem href="#part-637" level="0">VII COMMON SEAL</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10093" level="2">23 Common seal.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-20967" level="2">24 Minutes.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10095" level="2">25 Accounts to be kept..</tocItem><tocItem href="#part-640" level="0">IX REGULATIONS</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10096" level="2">26 Annual report.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-10097" level="2">27 Regulations.</tocItem></toc></preamble><body><part id="part-631"><num>I</num><heading>PART I PRELIMINARY</heading><section id="section-10071"><num>1</num><heading>SECTION 1 Short title.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>1. </xhtml:b>This Act may be cited as the Law Society of Kenya Act. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-10072"><num>2</num><heading>SECTION 2 Interpretation.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>2. </xhtml:b>In this Act, except where the context otherwise requires - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"advocate" has the same meaning as in the Advocates Act; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"Council" means the Council established under section 13; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"Disciplinary Committee" means the Disciplinary Committee established under section 59 of the Advocates Act; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"ordinary general meeting" means the meeting convened in accordance with the provisions in section 18; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"Society" means the society established and incorporated by section 3 of the Law Society of Kenya Ordinance, 1949 (now repealed), and continued in existence by section 3 of this Act; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"special resolution" means a resolution passed by not less than two-thirds of such members of the Society as may be present and vote thereon at a general meeting of the Society, duly convened with notice of the intention to propose such resolution, or, in the case of a postal ballot, not less than two-thirds of those effectively participating therein. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section></part><part id="part-632"><num>II</num><heading>PART II ESTABLISHMENT</heading><section id="section-10073"><num>3</num><heading>SECTION 3 Establishment of Law Society of Kenya.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>3. </xhtml:b>The body corporate established by section 3 of the Law Society of Kenya Ordinance, 1949 (now repealed), shall continue in existence by virtue of this Act as a body corporate by the name of the Law Society of Kenya with perpetual succession and a common seal and with power to sue and be sued in its corporate name. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-10074"><num>4</num><heading>SECTION 4 Objects of Society.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>4. </xhtml:b>The objects for which the Society is established are - 
<xhtml:p>(a) to maintain and improve the standards of conduct and learning of the legal profession in Kenya; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) to facilitate the acquisition of legal knowledge by members of the legal profession and others; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) to assist the Government and the courts in all matters affecting legislation and the administration and practice of the law in Kenya; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(d) to represent, protect and assist members of the legal profession in Kenya in respect of conditions of practice and otherwise; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(e) to protect and assist the public in Kenya in all matters touching, ancillary or incidental to the law; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(f) to acquire, hold, develop and dispose of property, whether movable or immovable, and to derive capital or income therefrom, for all or any of the foregoing objects; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(g) to raise or borrow money for all or any of the foregoing objects in such manner and upon such security as may from time to time be determined by the Society; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(h) to invest and deal with moneys of the Society not immediately required in such manner as may from time to time be determined by the Society; and </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(i) to do all such other things as are incidental or conducive to the attainment of all or any of the foregoing objects. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section></part><part id="part-633"><num>III</num><heading>PART III MEMBERSHIP</heading><section id="section-10075"><num>5</num><heading>SECTION 5 Membership.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>5. </xhtml:b>The membership of the Society shall consist of - 
<xhtml:p>(a) any advocate who is a member of the Society by virtue of section 28 of the Advocates Act; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) any person admitted to membership of the society under section 6 of this Act; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) any person elected as an honorary member of the Society under section 7 of this Act; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(d) any person who has at any time previously been a member of the Society and who complies with the regulations of the Society for the time being in force: </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Provided that this paragraph shall not apply to a person to whom the proviso to section 6 of this Act applies, nor to a former member of the Society who, as a result of disciplinary proceedings, has for the time being been suspended from practice or whose name has been struck off the Roll of Advocates. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-10076"><num>6</num><heading>SECTION 6 Special membership.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>6. </xhtml:b>Any of the following persons who applies for membership of the Society in the prescribed manner may be admitted as a member of the Society by the Council - 
<xhtml:p>(a) any person mentioned in section 9 of the Advocates Act; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) any other legally qualified person for the time being resident in Kenya: </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Provided that no person who has been expelled from membership of the Society shall thereafter be admitted as a member thereof under this section without the authority of a special resolution. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-10077"><num>7</num><heading>SECTION 7 Honorary membership.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>7. </xhtml:b>The Council may elect as an honorary member of the Society any person whom it may think fit so to honour, either for life or for such period as the Council may in any case deem appropriate.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-10078"><num>8</num><heading>SECTION 8 Subscriptions.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>8. </xhtml:b>Subject to the provisions of sections 27 and 28 of the Advocates Act, every member of the Society shall pay the Society such annual subscription as may be prescribed from time to time: 
<xhtml:p>Provided that no honorary member shall be liable to pay any such subscription. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-10079"><num>9</num><heading>SECTION 9 No entrance fee.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>9. </xhtml:b>No entrance fee shall be payable by any person on becoming a member of the Society.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-10080"><num>10</num><heading>SECTION 10 Resignations.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>10. </xhtml:b>No member of the Society shall resign or be permitted to resign his membership thereof at any time while he holds a current practising certificate issued under section 26 of the Advocates Act.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-10081"><num>11</num><heading>SECTION 11 Expulsion.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>11. </xhtml:b>Subject to the provisions of section 28 of the Advocates Act, any member of the Society, other than a member who holds a current practising certificate issued under section 26 of that Act or an honorary member, may be expelled therefrom in such manner and upon such grounds, after being given a reasonable opportunity to answer all allegations made against him, as may be prescribed from time to time.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-10082"><num>12</num><heading>SECTION 12 Members ceasing to be qualified for membership.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>12. </xhtml:b>Any member of the Society, other than an honorary member, who ceases to be qualified for membership shall thereupon automatically cease to be a member.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section></part><part id="part-634"><num>IV</num><heading>PART IV COUNCIL</heading><section id="section-10083"><num>13</num><heading>SECTION 13 Constitution of Council.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>13. </xhtml:b>(1) For the proper management of the affairs of the Society there shall be a Council consisting of a chairman, a vice-chairman and ten other members, all of whom shall be members of the Society. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) The chairman, the vice-chairman and the ten other members mentioned in subsection (1) shall be elected bi-annually by the members of the Society by means of a postal ballot conducted in accordance with regulations made under section 27: </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Provided that at least one of the members so elected shall be a member of the Society who ordinarily practices in Mombasa and at least two of the members shall be members who do not ordinarily practice in Nairobi or Mombasa. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) No member of the Society shall be eligible for election as chairman or vice-chairman, and no member of the Society shall put himself forward for such election, unless he is at the time of the election, a member of the Council. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) The chairman, the vice-chairman and the other members of the Council shall take office immediately after the ordinary general meeting of the Society, and shall hold office as such until the conclusion of the ordinary general meeting held in the second year, after their election:<xhtml:br/></xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Provided that, in the event of the death, resignation, removal or disqualification of the chairman, the vice-chairman or any other member of the council during his term of office, the vacancy so created shall be filled by the society- </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(i) in the case of the chairman or vice-chairman, from persons who are members of the Council; or<xhtml:br/></xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(ii) in the case of any other member, from among the members of the Society. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-10084"><num>14</num><heading>SECTION 14 Powers of Council.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>14. </xhtml:b>Except as otherwise expressly provided by this Act or by any regulations made under this Act, the Council may exercise all the powers of the Society; and no regulations made under this Act shall invalidate any prior act of the Council which would have been valid if the regulations had not been made.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-10085"><num>15</num><heading>SECTION 15 Committees and delegation of powers.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>15. </xhtml:b>(1) The Council may from time to time appoint committees or subcommittees consisting of members of the Society; and may, except as otherwise expressly provided by this Act or by any regulations made under this Act, delegate to any such committee or subcommittee all or any of the powers of the Council. 
<xhtml:p>(2) Any committee or subcommittee appointed under subsection (1) may, with the prior approval of the Council, from time to time co-opt additional members, and any such additional member may, but need not, be a member of the Society. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-10086"><num>16</num><heading>SECTION 16 Procedure.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>16. </xhtml:b>The procedure of the Council, and of every committee appointed under section 15, shall be as may be prescribed from time to time.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section></part><part id="part-635"><num>V</num><heading>PART V OTHER OFFICERS</heading><section id="section-10087"><num>17</num><heading>SECTION 17 Officers of Society.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>17. </xhtml:b>There shall be such secretary, treasurer and other officers of the Society, paid or unpaid, as the Council may from time to time appoint. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section></part><part id="part-636"><num>VI</num><heading>PART VI GENERAL MEETINGS</heading><section id="section-10088"><num>18</num><heading>SECTION 18 Ordinary general meeting.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>18. </xhtml:b>The Council shall, within twelve weeks after the 31st December in each year, convene an ordinary general meeting of the Society.<xhtml:br/></xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-10089"><num>19</num><heading>SECTION 19 Special general meetings.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>19. </xhtml:b>(1) The Council may at any time at its own discretion convene a special general meeting of the Society. 
<xhtml:p>(2) Any fifteen members of the Society may at any time requisition a special general meeting of the Society by written notice in that behalf signed by all of them, specifying the object of the proposed meeting and sent by post, or delivered, to the secretary of the Society; and the Council shall thereupon convene a special general meeting of the Society accordingly, which shall be held within forty-two days after the delivery of such notice. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) If the Council fails within twenty-eight days after the delivery of the written notice mentioned in subsection (2) to convene a special general meeting of the Society in accordance with the requisition, to be held within forty-two days after such delivery, the requisitioning members may themselves convene such meeting to be held at any time within two months after such delivery. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-10090"><num>20</num><heading>SECTION 20 General meeting to act by simple majority vote.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>20. </xhtml:b>Except for any purpose for which a special resolution is expressly required by this Act or by any regulations made under this Act, all resolutions of the Society in general meeting shall be by simple majority vote.<xhtml:br/></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-10091"><num>21</num><heading>SECTION 21 Alteration of resolutions.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>21. </xhtml:b>No resolution of the Society in general meeting shall be altered or rescinded within nine months after the passing thereof otherwise than by a special resolution of the Society.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-10092"><num>22</num><heading>SECTION 22 Convening and procedure.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>22. </xhtml:b>The manner of convening general meetings of the Society and the procedure and voting thereat shall, subject to any express provisions of this Act, be as may be prescribed from time to time.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section></part><part id="part-637"><num>VII</num><heading>PART VII COMMON SEAL</heading><section id="section-10093"><num>23</num><heading>SECTION 23 Common seal.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>23. </xhtml:b>The common seal of the Society shall be kept in such custody and used in such manner as may be prescribed from time to time. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-20967"><num>24</num><heading>SECTION 24 Minutes.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:div>
  PART VIII-MINUTES,ACCOUNTS AND REPORTS 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:div>
  &#160; 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:div>
  24. The Council shall cause proper minutes of all general meetings of the Society and of all meetings of the Council to be taken and recorded.<xhtml:br/></xhtml:div></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-10095"><num>25</num><heading>SECTION 25 Accounts to be kept..</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>25. </xhtml:b>(1) The Council shall cause proper accounts of all funds, property, assets and liabilities of the Society to be kept, and to be audited as on the 31st December in every year. 
<xhtml:p>(2) The audited accounts shall be presented by the Council to the ordinary general meeting. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section></part><part id="part-640"><num>IX</num><heading>PART IX REGULATIONS</heading><section id="section-10096"><num>26</num><heading>SECTION 26 Annual report.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>26. </xhtml:b>The Council shall present to the ordinary general meeting a full report of the activities of the Society.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-10097"><num>27</num><heading>SECTION 27 Regulations.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>27. </xhtml:b>The Council may, subject to the provisions of this Act and to approval by a special resolution, make regulations, which shall be binding on all members of the Society, prescribing all or any of the following matters - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) annual subscriptions; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) manner of application for membership of the Society; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) grounds for, and procedure relating to, expulsion of members of the Society; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(d) resignation of members from the Society; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(e) regulation of powers exercisable by the Council and any committees or subcommittees thereof, and delegation of powers; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(f) manner of convening meetings of the Council and committees, and quorums and procedure thereof:; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(g) manner of convening general meetings of the Society, and quorums and procedure thereof; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(h) manner of election, removal and replacement of the chairman, the vice-chairman and the other members of the Council, and of representatives of the Society on the Disciplinary Committee; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(i) custody and use of the common seal; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(j) arbitration in disputes; and </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(k) such other matters as may be deemed by the Council to be necessary for the promotion of the objects and the regulation of the affairs of the Society. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section></part></body><outOfLines><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10071" id="w220aab1b9b1" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Short title.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10072" id="w220aab1b9b3" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Interpretation. 44 of 1962, Sch. Cap.16. 10 of 1949.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10073" id="w220aab1b9b5" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Establishment of Law Society of Kenya. 10 of 1949.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10074" id="w220aab1b9b7" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Objects of Society.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10075" id="w220aab1b9b9" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Membership. Cap.16.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10076" id="w220aab1b9c11" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Special membership. Cap. 16.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10077" id="w220aab1b9c13" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Honorary membership.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10078" id="w220aab1b9c15" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Subscriptions. Cap.16.  
<xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10079" id="w220aab1b9c17" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">No entrance fee.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10080" id="w220aab1b9c19" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Resignations. Cap.16.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10081" id="w220aab1b9c21" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Expulsion. Cap.16.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10082" id="w220aab1b9c23" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Members ceasing to be qualified for membership.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10083" id="w220aab1b9c25" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Constitution of Council. 12 of 1976, s. 2. 10 of 1997, Sch. A 7 of 2007.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10084" id="w220aab1b9c27" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Powers of Council.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10085" id="w220aab1b9c29" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Committees and delegation of powers.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10086" id="w220aab1b9c31" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Procedure.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10087" id="w220aab1b9c33" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Officers of Society.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10088" id="w220aab1b9c35" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Ordinary general meeting. 18 of 1986, Sch.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10089" id="w220aab1b9c37" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Special general meetings.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10090" id="w220aab1b9c39" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">General meeting to act by simple majority vote.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10091" id="w220aab1b9c41" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Alteration of resolutions.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10092" id="w220aab1b9c43" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Convening and procedure.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10093" id="w220aab1b9c45" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Common seal.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-20967" id="w220aab1b9c47" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Minutes.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10095" id="w220aab1b9c49" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Accounts to be kept.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10096" id="w220aab1b9c51" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Annual report.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-10097" id="w220aab1b9c53" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Regulations. 4 of 1973, Sch.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine></outOfLines></act></akomaNtoso>