<akomaNtoso xmlns:an="http://www.akomantoso.org/1.0"><act contains="singleVersion"><meta><identification source="#kenyalaw"><FRBRWork><FRBRthis value="/ke/act/1934-07-01/29/main"/><FRBRuri value="/ke/act/1934-07-01/29"/><FRBRdate date="1934-07-01" name="Generation"/><FRBRauthor as="#author" href="#parliament"/><components><component href="#emain" id="wmain" name="main" showAs="Main Document"/></components></FRBRWork><FRBRExpression><FRBRthis value="/ke/act/1934-07-01/29/eng@/main"/><FRBRuri value="/ke/act/1934-07-01/29/eng@"/><FRBRdate date="1934-07-01" name="Generation"/><FRBRauthor as="#author" href="#parliament"/><components><component href="#mmain" id="emain" name="main" showAs="Main Document"/></components></FRBRExpression><FRBRManifestation><FRBRthis value="/ke/act/1934-07-01/29/eng@/main.xml"/><FRBRuri value="/ke/act/1934-07-01/29/eng@/.akn"/><FRBRdate date="1934-07-01" name="Generation"/><FRBRauthor as="#author" href="#parliament"/><components><component href="#mmain" id="mmain" name="main" showAs="Main Document"/></components></FRBRManifestation></identification><publication date="1934-07-01" name="" showAs=""/><lifecycle source="#bungeni"><event date="1934-07-01" id="e1" source="#ro1" type="generation"/></lifecycle><references source="#kenyalaw"><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActTitle" id="TheActTitle" showAs="Act Title"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActLongTitle" id="TheActLongTitle" showAs="Act Description"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/AssentDate" id="AssentDate" showAs="Assent Date"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/CommencementDate" id="CommencementDate" showAs="Commencement Date"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActNumber" id="TheActNumber" showAs="Act Number"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActID" id="TheActID" showAs="Act ID"/><TLCConcept href="http://bungeni-lexmigrate.googlecode.com" id="bungeni" showAs="Lex Migrator"/><TLCConcept href="http://kenyalaw.org" id="kenyalaw" showAs="Kenya Law"/></references><proprietary xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" source="#kenyalaw"><kl:meta name="gokcatid" num="4"/><kl:meta name="gokcatname">Civil Law and Procedure</kl:meta><kl:meta name="lexyy" num="1934"/><kl:meta name="lexmm" num="7"/><kl:meta name="lexdd" num="1"/></proprietary></meta><preface><block name="preface"><docTitle id="ActTitle" refersTo="#TheActTitle">Partnership</docTitle><docTitle id="ActLongTitle" refersTo="#TheActLongTitle">An Act of Parliament to declare the law of partnership</docTitle><docDate date="1934-07-01" refersTo="#CommencementDate">Jul 1, 1934</docDate><docDate date="1111-11-11" refersTo="#AssentDate">Nov 11, 1111</docDate><docNumber id="ActNumber" refersTo="#TheActNumber">29</docNumber><docNumber id="ActIdentifier" refersTo="#TheActID">31</docNumber></block></preface><preamble><p>ARRANGEMENT OF SECTIONS</p><toc><tocItem href="#part-1001" level="0">I PRELIMINARY</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12170" level="2">1 Short title.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12171" level="2">2 Interpretation.</tocItem><tocItem href="#part-1002" level="0">II NATURE OF PARTNERSHIP</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12172" level="2">3 Definition of partnership.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12173" level="2">4 Rules for determining existence of partnership.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12174" level="2">5 Postponement of rights of persons lending or selling in consideration of share of profits in case of bankruptcy.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12175" level="2">6 Meaning of &amp;quot;firm&amp;quot;.</tocItem><tocItem href="#part-1003" level="0">III RELATIONS OF PARTNERS TO PERSONS DEALING WITH THEM</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12176" level="2">7 Power of partner to bind the firm.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12177" level="2">8 Partners bound by acts on behalf of firm.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12178" level="2">9 Partners using credit of firm for private purposes.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12179" level="2">10 Effect of notice that firm will not be bound by acts of partner.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12180" level="2">11 Liability of Partners.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12181" level="2">12 Minor partner not personally liable, but his share is.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12182" level="2">13 Liability of minor partner on attaining majority.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12183" level="2">14 Liability of the firm for wrongs of partners.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12184" level="2">15 Misapplication of money or property received for or in custody of the firm.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12185" level="2">16 Liability for wrongs joint and several.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12186" level="2">17 Improper employment of trust property for partnership purposes.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12187" level="2">18 Persons liable by</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12188" level="2">19 Admissions and representations of partners.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12189" level="2">20 Notice to acting partner to be notice to the firm.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12190" level="2">21 Liabilities of incoming and outgoing partners.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12191" level="2">22 Revocation of continuing guaranty by change in firm.</tocItem><tocItem href="#part-1004" level="0">IV RELATIONS OF PARTNERS TO ONE ANOTHER</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12192" level="2">23 Variation by consent of terms of partnership.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12193" level="2">24 Partnership property.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12194" level="2">25 Property bought with partnership money.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12195" level="2">26 Conversion into personal estate of land held as partnership property.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12196" level="2">27 Execution against partnership property.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12197" level="2">28 Rules as to interests and duties of partners.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12198" level="2">29 Expulsion of partner.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12199" level="2">30 Retirement from partnership at will.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12200" level="2">31 Where partnership for a term is continued over, continuance on old terms presumed.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12201" level="2">32 Duty of partners to render accounts, etc.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12202" level="2">33 Accountability of partners for private profits.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12203" level="2">34 Duty of partner not to compete with firm.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12204" level="2">35 Rights of assignee of share in partnership.</tocItem><tocItem href="#part-1005" level="0">V DISSOLUTION OF PARTNERSHIP AND ITS CONSEQUENCES</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12205" level="2">36 Dissolution by expiration or notice.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12206" level="2">37 Dissolution by bankruptcy, death or charge.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12207" level="2">38 Dissolution by illegality of partnership.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12208" level="2">39 Dissolution by the court.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12209" level="2">40 Change in constitution of partnership.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12210" level="2">41 Partner may notify dissolution.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12211" level="2">42 Continuing authority of partners for purposes of winding up.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12212" level="2">43 Rights of partners as to application of partnership property.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12213" level="2">44 Apportionment of premium where partnership prematurely dissolved.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12214" level="2">45 Rights where partnership dissolved for fraud or misrepresentation.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12215" level="2">46 Right of outgoing partner in certain cases to share profits made after dissolution.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12216" level="2">47 Retiring or deceased partner&amp;apos;s share to be a debt.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12217" level="2">48 Rule for distribution of assets on final settlement of accounts.</tocItem><tocItem href="#part-1006" level="0">VI GENERAL</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-12218" level="2">49 Existing rules applicable to partnership.</tocItem></toc></preamble><body><part id="part-1001"><num>I</num><heading>PART I PRELIMINARY</heading><section id="section-12170"><num>1</num><heading>SECTION 1 Short title.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>1.</xhtml:b>This Act may be cited as the Partnership Act. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12171"><num>2</num><heading>SECTION 2 Interpretation.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>2.</xhtml:b>In this Act, except where inconsistent with the context - 
<xhtml:p>"business" includes every trade, occupation or profession; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"court" means the High Court or, where the gross assets of a partnership do not exceed fifty thousand shillings, the Resident Magistrate's Court. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section></part><part id="part-1002"><num>II</num><heading>PART II NATURE OF PARTNERSHIP</heading><section id="section-12172"><num>3</num><heading>SECTION 3 Definition of partnership.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>3.</xhtml:b>(1) Partnership is the relation which subsists between persons carrying on a business in common with a view of profit. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) The relation between members of any company or association which is - (a) registered as a company under the Companies Act or any other Act for the time being in force and relating to the registration of joint stock companies; or </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) formed or incorporated by or in pursuance of any other Act or of any Order in Council, or Act of the United Kingdom Parliament, or Letters Patent, or Royal Charter, </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>is not a partnership within the meaning of this Act. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12173"><num>4</num><heading>SECTION 4 Rules for determining existence of partnership.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>4.</xhtml:b>In determining whether a partnership does or does not exist, regard shall be had to the following rules - 
<xhtml:p>(a) joint tenancy, tenancy in common, joint property, common property or part ownership does not of itself create a partnership as to anything so held or owned, whether the tenants or or owners do or do not share any profits made by the use thereof; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) the sharing of gross returns does not of itself create a partnership, whether the persons sharing those returns have or have not a joint or common right or interest in any property from which, or from the use of which, the returns are derived; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) the receipt by a person of a share of the profits of a business is prima facie evidence that he is a partner in the business, but the receipt of such a share, or of a payment contingent on or varying with the profits of a business, does not of itself make him a partner in the business; and in particular - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(i) the receipt by a person of a debt or other liquidated amount by instalments or otherwise, out of the accruing profits of a business, does not of itself make him a partner in the business or liable as such;<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(ii) a contract for the remuneration of a servant or agent of a person engaged in a business by a share of the profits of the business does not of itself make the servant or agent a partner in the business or liable as such; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(iii) a person being the widow or child of a deceased partner and receiving by way of annuity a portion of the profits made in the business in which the deceased person was a partner is not, by reason only of that receipt, a partner in the business or liable as such;<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(iv) the advance of money by way of loan to a person engaged, or about to engage, in any business on a contract with that person that the lender shall receive a rate of interest varying with the profits, or shall receive a share of the profits arising from carrying on the business, does not of itself make the lender a partner with the person or persons carrying on the business or liable as such, provided that the contract is in writing, and signed by or on behalf of all the parties thereto; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(v) a person receiving, by way of annuity or otherwise, a portion of the profits of a business in consideration of the sale by him of the goodwill of the business is not, by reason only of that receipt, a partner in the business or liable as such. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12174"><num>5</num><heading>SECTION 5 Postponement of rights of persons lending or selling in consideration of share of profits in case of bankruptcy.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>5.</xhtml:b>In the event of any person to whom money has been advanced by way of loan upon such a contract as is mentioned in section 4, or of any buyer of a goodwill in consideration of a share of the profits of the business, being adjudged a bankrupt, entering into an arrangement to pay his creditors less than twenty shillings in the pound, or dying in insolvent circumstances, the lender of the loan shall not be entitled to recover anything in respect of his loan, and the seller of the goodwill shall not be entitled to recover anything in respect of the share of profits contracted for, until the claims of the other creditors of the borrower or buyer for valuable consideration in money or money's worth have been satisfied.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12175"><num>6</num><heading>SECTION 6 Meaning of &amp;quot;firm&amp;quot;.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>6.</xhtml:b>Persons who have entered into partnership with one another are, for the purposes of this Act, called collectively a firm, and the name under which their business is carried on is called the firm-name.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section></part><part id="part-1003"><num>III</num><heading>PART III RELATIONS OF PARTNERS TO PERSONS DEALING WITH THEM</heading><section id="section-12176"><num>7</num><heading>SECTION 7 Power of partner to bind the firm.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>7.</xhtml:b>Every partner is an agent of the firm and his other partners for the purpose of the business of the partnership; and the acts of every partner who does any act for carrying on in the usual way business of the kind carried on by the firm of which he is a member bind the firm and his partners, unless the partner so acting has in fact no authority to act for the firm in the particular matter, and the person with whom he is dealing either knows that he has no authority or does not know or believe him to be a partner. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12177"><num>8</num><heading>SECTION 8 Partners bound by acts on behalf of firm.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>8.</xhtml:b>An act or instrument relating to the business of the firm, and done or executed in the firm-name, or in any other manner showing an intention to bind the firm, by any person thereto authorized, whether a partner or not, is binding on the firm and all the partners: 
<xhtml:p>Provided that this section shall not affect any general rule of law relating to the execution of deeds or negotiable instruments. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12178"><num>9</num><heading>SECTION 9 Partners using credit of firm for private purposes.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>9.</xhtml:b>Where one partner pledges the credit of the firm for a purpose apparently not connected with the firm's ordinary course of business, the firm is not bound, unless that partner is in fact specially authorized by the other partners; but this section does not affect any personal liability incurred by an individual partner.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12179"><num>10</num><heading>SECTION 10 Effect of notice that firm will not be bound by acts of partner.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>10.</xhtml:b>If it has been agreed between the partners that any restriction shall be placed on the power of any one or more of them to bind the firm, no act done in contravention of the agreement is binding on the firm with respect to persons having notice of the agreement. 
<xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12180"><num>11</num><heading>SECTION 11 Liability of Partners.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>11.</xhtml:b>Every partner in a firm is liable jointly with the other partners for all debts and obligations of the firm incurred while he is a partner, but a person who is admitted as a partner into an existing firm does not thereby become liable to the creditors of the firm for anything done before he became a partner; and after his death his estate is also severally liable in the due course of administration for those debts and obligations, so far as they remain unsatisfied, but subject to the prior payment of his separate debts.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12181"><num>12</num><heading>SECTION 12 Minor partner not personally liable, but his share is.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>12.</xhtml:b>A person who is under the age of majority according to the law to which he is subject may be admitted to the benefits of partnership, but cannot be made personally liable for any obligation of the firm; but the share of the minor in the property of the firm is liable for the obligations of the firm.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12182"><num>13</num><heading>SECTION 13 Liability of minor partner on attaining majority.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>13.</xhtml:b>A person who has been admitted to the benefits of partnership under the age of majority becomes, on attaining that age, liable for all obligations incurred by the partnership since he was so admitted, unless he gives public notice within a reasonable time of his repudiation of the partnership.<xhtml:br/></xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12183"><num>14</num><heading>SECTION 14 Liability of the firm for wrongs of partners.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>14.</xhtml:b>Where, by any wrongful act or omission of any partner acting in the ordinary course of the business of the firm, or with the authority of his co-partners, loss or injury is caused to any person not being a partner in the firm, or any penalty is incurred, the firm is liable therefore to the same extent as the partner so acting or omitting to act. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12184"><num>15</num><heading>SECTION 15 Misapplication of money or property received for or in custody of the firm.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>15.</xhtml:b>In the following cases - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) where one partner, acting within the scope of his apparent authority, receives the money or property of a third person, and misapplies it; and </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) where a firm in the course of its business receives money or property of a third person, and the money or property so received is misapplied by one or more of the partners while it is in the custody of the firm, the firm is liable to make good the loss. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12185"><num>16</num><heading>SECTION 16 Liability for wrongs joint and several.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>16.</xhtml:b>Every partner is liable jointly with his co-partners and also severally for everything for which the firm, while he is a partner therein, becomes liable under section 14 or 15.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12186"><num>17</num><heading>SECTION 17 Improper employment of trust property for partnership purposes.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>17.</xhtml:b>If a partner, being a trustee, improperly employs trust property in the business or on the account of the partnership, no other partner is liable for the trust property to the persons beneficially interested therein: 
<xhtml:p>Provided that - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(i) this section shall not affect any liability incurred by any partner by reason of his having notice of a breach of trust; and </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(ii) nothing in this section shall prevent trust money from being followed and recovered from the firm if still in its possession or under its control. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12187"><num>18</num><heading>SECTION 18 Persons liable by</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>18.</xhtml:b>Any person who, by words spoken or written or by conduct, represents himself, or who knowingly suffers himself to be represented, as a partner in a particular firm is liable as a partner to anyone who has on the faith of any such representation, given credit to the firm, whether the representation has or has not been made or communicated to the person so giving credit by or with the knowledge of the apparent partner making the representation or suffering it to be made: 
<xhtml:p>Provided that where, after a partner's death, the partnership business is continued in the old firm-name, the continued use of that name or of the deceased partner's name as part thereof shall not of itself make his executors or administrators, estate or effects liable for any partnership debts contracted after his death. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12188"><num>19</num><heading>SECTION 19 Admissions and representations of partners.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>19.</xhtml:b>An admission or representation made by any partner concerning the partnership affairs, and in the ordinary course of its business, is evidence against the firm.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12189"><num>20</num><heading>SECTION 20 Notice to acting partner to be notice to the firm.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>20.</xhtml:b>Notice to any partner who habitually acts in the partnership business of any matter relating to partnership affairs operates as notice to the firm, except in the case of a fraud on the firm committed by or with the consent of that partner.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12190"><num>21</num><heading>SECTION 21 Liabilities of incoming and outgoing partners.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>21.</xhtml:b>(1) A person who is admitted as a partner into an existing firm does not thereby become liable to the creditors of the firm for anything done before he became a partner. 
<xhtml:p>(2) A partner who retires from a firm does not thereby cease to be liable for partnership debts or obligations incurred before his retirement. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) A retiring partner may be discharged from any existing liabilities by an agreement to that effect between himself and the members of the firm as newly constituted and the creditors, and this agreement may be either express or inferred as a fact from the course of dealing between the creditors and the firm as newly constituted. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12191"><num>22</num><heading>SECTION 22 Revocation of continuing guaranty by change in firm.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>22.</xhtml:b>A continuing guaranty or cautionary obligation given either to a firm or to a third person in respect of the transactions of a firm is, in the absence of agreement to the contrary, revoked as to future transactions by any change in the constitution of the firm to which, or of the firm in respect of the transactions of which, the guaranty or obligation was given.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section></part><part id="part-1004"><num>IV</num><heading>PART IV RELATIONS OF PARTNERS TO ONE ANOTHER</heading><section id="section-12192"><num>23</num><heading>SECTION 23 Variation by consent of terms of partnership.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>23.</xhtml:b>The mutual rights and duties of partners, whether ascertained by agreement or defined by this Act, may be varied by the consent of all the partners, and that consent may be either expressed or inferred from a course of dealing. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12193"><num>24</num><heading>SECTION 24 Partnership property.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>24.</xhtml:b>(1) All property and rights and interests in property originally brought into the partnership stock or acquired, whether by purchase or otherwise, on account of the firm, or for the purposes and in the course of the partnership business, are called in this Act partnership property, and must be held and applied by the partners exclusively for the purposes of the partnership and in accordance with the partnership agreement: </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Provided that the legal estate or interest in any land which belongs to the partnership shall devolve according to the nature and tenure thereof and the general rules of law applicable thereto, but in trust, so far as necessary, for the persons beneficially interested in the land under this section. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) Where co-owners of an estate or interest in any land, not being itself partnership property, are partners as to profits made by the use of that land or estate, and purchase other land or estate out of the profit to be used in the same manner, the land or estate so purchased belongs to them, in the absence of an agreement to the contrary, not as partners but as co-owners for the same respective estates and interests as are held by them in the land or estate first mentioned at the date of the purchase. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12194"><num>25</num><heading>SECTION 25 Property bought with partnership money.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>25.</xhtml:b>Unless the contrary intention appears, property bought with money belonging to the firm is deemed to have been bought on account of the firm. 
<xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12195"><num>26</num><heading>SECTION 26 Conversion into personal estate of land held as partnership property.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>26.</xhtml:b>Where land or any interest therein has become partnership property, it shall, unless the contrary intention appears, be treated as between the partners (including the representatives of a deceased partner) and also as between the heir's of a deceased partner and his executors or administrators as personal and not real estate. 
<xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12196"><num>27</num><heading>SECTION 27 Execution against partnership property.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>27.</xhtml:b>(1) Execution of a decree shall not issue against any partnership property except on a judgment against the firm. 
<xhtml:p>(2) The court may, on the application by summons of any judgment creditor of a partner, make an order charging that partner's interest in the partnership property and profits with payment of the amount of the judgment debt and interest thereon, and may by the same or a subsequent order appoint a receiver of that partner's share of profits (whether already declared or accruing), and of any other money which may be coming to him in respect of the partnership, and direct all accounts and inquiries, and give all other orders and directions which might have been directed or given if the charge had been made in favour of the judgment creditor by the partner, or which the circumstances of the case may require. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) The other partner or partners shall be at liberty at any time to redeem the interest charged, or, in case of a sale being directed, to purchase the same. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12197"><num>28</num><heading>SECTION 28 Rules as to interests and duties of partners.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>28.</xhtml:b>The interests of partners in the partnership property and their rights and duties in relation to the partnership shall be determined, subject to any agreement express or implied between the partners, by the following rules - 
<xhtml:p>(a) all the partners are entitled to share equally in the capital and profits of the business and must contribute equally towards the losses whether of capital or otherwise sustained by the firm; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) the firm must indemnify every partner in respect of payments made and personal liabilities incurred by him - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(i) in the ordinary and proper conduct of the business of the firm; or </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(ii) in or about anything necessarily done for the preservation of the business or property of the firm; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) a partner making, for the purpose of the partnership, any actual payment or advance beyond the amount of capital which he has agreed to subscribe is entitled to interest at the rate of six per centum per annum from the date of the payment or advance; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(d) a partner is not entitled, before the ascertainment of profits, to interest on the capital subscribed by him; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(e) every partner may take part in the management of the partnership business; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(f) no partner shall be entitled to remuneration for acting in the partnership business; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(g) no person may be introduced as a partner without the consent of all existing partners; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(h) any difference arising as to ordinary matters connected with the partnership business may be decided by a majority of the partners, but no change may be made in the nature of the partnership business without the consent of all existing partners; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(i) the partnership books are to be kept at the place of business of the partnership (or the principal place, if there is more than one) and every partner may, at all reasonable times, have access to and inspect and copy any of them. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12198"><num>29</num><heading>SECTION 29 Expulsion of partner.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>29.</xhtml:b>No majority of the partners can expel any partner unless a power to do so has been conferred by express agreement between the partners.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12199"><num>30</num><heading>SECTION 30 Retirement from partnership at will.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>30.</xhtml:b>(1) Where no fixed term has been agreed upon for the duration of the partnership, any partner may determine the partnership at any time on giving reasonable notice of his intention to do so to all the other partners. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) Where the partnership has originally been constituted by deed, a notice in writing, signed by the partner giving it, shall be sufficient for this purpose. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12200"><num>31</num><heading>SECTION 31 Where partnership for a term is continued over, continuance on old terms presumed.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>31.</xhtml:b>(1) Where a partnership entered into for a fixed term is continued after the term has expired, and without any express new agreement, the rights and duties of the partners remain the same as they were at the expiration of the term, so far as is consistent with the incidents of a partnership at will. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) A continuance of the business by the partners or such of them as habitually acted therein during the term without any settlement or liquidation of the partnership affairs is presumed to be a continuance of the partnership. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12201"><num>32</num><heading>SECTION 32 Duty of partners to render accounts, etc.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>32.</xhtml:b>Partners are bound to render true accounts and full information of all things affecting the partnership to any partner or his legal representatives.<xhtml:br/></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12202"><num>33</num><heading>SECTION 33 Accountability of partners for private profits.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>33.</xhtml:b>(1) Every partner must account to the firm for any benefit derived by him without the consent of the other partners from any transaction concerning the partnership, or from any use by him of the partnership property, name or business connexion. 
<xhtml:p>(2) This section applies also to transactions undertaken after a partnership has been dissolved by the death of a partner and before the affairs thereof have been completely wound up, either by any surviving partner or by the representatives of the deceased partner. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12203"><num>34</num><heading>SECTION 34 Duty of partner not to compete with firm.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>34.</xhtml:b>If a partner without the consent of the other partners carries on any business of the same nature as and competing with that of the firm, he must account for and pay over to the firm all profits made by him in that business.<xhtml:br/></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12204"><num>35</num><heading>SECTION 35 Rights of assignee of share in partnership.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>35.</xhtml:b>(1) An assignment by any partner of his share in the partnership, either absolute or by way of mortgage or redeemable charge, does not, as against the other partners, entitle the assignee, during the continuance of the partnership, to interfere in the management or administration of the partnership business or affairs, or to require any accounts of the partnership transactions, or to inspect the partnership books, but entitles the assignee only to receive the share of profits to which the assigning partner would otherwise be entitled, and the assignee must accept the account of profits agreed to by the partners. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) In the case of a dissolution of the partnership, whether as respects all the partners or as respects the assigning partner, the assignee is entitled to receive the share of the partnership assets to which the assigning partner is entitled as between himself and the other partners, and, for the purpose of ascertaining that share, to an account as from the date of the dissolution. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section></part><part id="part-1005"><num>V</num><heading>PART V DISSOLUTION OF PARTNERSHIP AND ITS CONSEQUENCES</heading><section id="section-12205"><num>36</num><heading>SECTION 36 Dissolution by expiration or notice.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>36.</xhtml:b>(1) Subject to any agreement between the partners, a partnership is dissolved - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) if entered into for a fixed term, by the expiration of that term; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) if entered into for a single adventure or undertaking, by the termination of that adventure or undertaking; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) if entered into for an undefined time, by any partner giving notice to the other or others of his intention to dissolve the partnership. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) In the last-mentioned case, the partnership is dissolved as from the date mentioned in the notice as the date of dissolution, or, if no date is so mentioned, as from the date of the communication of the notice. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12206"><num>37</num><heading>SECTION 37 Dissolution by bankruptcy, death or charge.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>37.</xhtml:b>(1) Subject to any agreement between the partners, every partnership is dissolved as regards all the partners by the death or bankruptcy of any partner. 
<xhtml:p>(2) A partnership may, at the option of the other partners, be dissolved if any partner suffers his share of the partnership property to be charged under this Act for his separate debt. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12207"><num>38</num><heading>SECTION 38 Dissolution by illegality of partnership.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>38.</xhtml:b>A partnership is in every case dissolved by the happening of any event which makes it unlawful for the business of the firm to be carried on or for the members of the firm to carry it on in partnership.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12208"><num>39</num><heading>SECTION 39 Dissolution by the court.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>39.</xhtml:b>On application by a partner the court may decree a dissolution of the partnership in any of the following cases - 
<xhtml:p>(a) When a partner is adjudged a lunatic, or is shown to the satisfaction of the court to be of permanently unsound mind, in either of which cases the application may be made as well on behalf of the partner by his guardian<xhtml:i>ad litem</xhtml:i>or next friend or person having title to intervene as by any other partner; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) when a partner, other than the partner suing, becomes in any other way permanently incapable of performing his part of the partnership contract.; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) when a partner, other than the partner suing, has been guilty of such conduct as, in the opinion of the court, regard being had to the nature of the business, is calculated to affect prejudicially the carrying on of the business;<xhtml:i><xhtml:br/></xhtml:i><xhtml:br/>(d) when a partner, other than the partner suing, wilfully or persistently commits a breach of the partnership agreement, or otherwise so conducts himself in matters relating to the partnership business that it is not reasonably practicable for the other partner or partners to carry on the business in partnership with him; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(e) when the business of the partnership can only be carried on at a loss; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(f) whenever in any case circumstances have arisen which, in the opinion of the court, render it just and equitable that the partnership be dissolved. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12209"><num>40</num><heading>SECTION 40 Change in constitution of partnership.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>40.</xhtml:b>(1) When a person deals with a firm after a change in its constitution, he is entitled to treat all apparent members of the old firm as still being members of the firm until he has notice of the change. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) An advertisement in the Gazette shall be notice as to persons who had not dealings with the firm before the date of the dissolution or change so advertised. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) The estate of a partner who dies or who becomes bankrupt, or of a partner who, not having been known to the person dealing with the firm to be a partner, retires from the firm, is not liable for partnership debts contracted after the date of the death, bankruptcy or retirement respectively. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12210"><num>41</num><heading>SECTION 41 Partner may notify dissolution.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>41.</xhtml:b>On the dissolution of a partnership or retirement of a partner, any partner may publicly notify the same and may require the other partner or partners to concur for that purpose in all necessary or proper acts, if any, which cannot be done without his or their concurrence. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12211"><num>42</num><heading>SECTION 42 Continuing authority of partners for purposes of winding up.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>42.</xhtml:b>After the dissolution of a partnership, the authority for each partner to bind the firm, and the other rights and obligations of the partners, continue notwithstanding, the dissolution, so far as may be necessary to wind up the affairs of the partnership, and to complete transactions begun but unfinished at the time of the dissolution, but not otherwise: </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Provided that the firm is in no case bound by the acts of a partner who has become bankrupt; but this proviso does not affect the liability of any person who has, after the bankruptcy, represented himself or knowingly suffered himself to be represented as a partner of the bankrupt. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12212"><num>43</num><heading>SECTION 43 Rights of partners as to application of partnership property.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>43.</xhtml:b>On the dissolution of a partnership, every partner is entitled, as against the other partners in the firm, and all persons claiming through them in respect of their interests as partners, to have the property of the partnership applied in payment of the debts and liabilities of the firm, and to have the surplus assets after such payment applied in payment of what may be due to the partners respectively after deducting what may be due from them as partners to the firm; and for that purpose any partner or his representatives may, on the termination of the partnership, apply to the court to wind up the business and affairs of the firm.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12213"><num>44</num><heading>SECTION 44 Apportionment of premium where partnership prematurely dissolved.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>44.</xhtml:b>Where one partner has paid a premium to another on entering into a partnership for a fixed term and the partnership is dissolved before the expiration of that term otherwise than by the death of a partner, the court may order the repayment of the premium, or of such part thereof as it thinks just, having regard to the terms of the partnership contract and to the length of time during which the partnership has continued, unless - 
<xhtml:p>(a) the dissolution is, in the judgment of the court, wholly or chiefly due to the misconduct of the partner who paid the premium; or </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) the partnership has been dissolved by an agreement containing no provision for a return of any part of the premium. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12214"><num>45</num><heading>SECTION 45 Rights where partnership dissolved for fraud or misrepresentation.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>45.</xhtml:b>Where a partnership contract is rescinded on the ground of the fraud or misrepresentation of one of the parties thereto, the party entitled to rescind is, without prejudice to any other right, entitled - 
<xhtml:p>(a) to a lien on, or right of retention of, the surplus of the partnership assets, after satisfying the partnership liabilities, for any sum of money paid by him for the purchase of a share in the partnership and for any capital contributed by him; and </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) to stand in the place of the creditors of the firm for any payments made by him in respect of the partnership liabilities; and </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) to be indemnified by the person guilty of the fraud or making the representation against all the debts and liabilities of the firm. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12215"><num>46</num><heading>SECTION 46 Right of outgoing partner in certain cases to share profits made after dissolution.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>46.</xhtml:b>Where any member of a firm has died or otherwise ceased to be a partner, and the surviving or continuing partners carry on the business of the firm with its capital or assets without any final settlement of accounts as between the firm and the outgoing partner or his estate, then, in the absence of any agreement to the contrary, the outgoing partner or his estate is entitled at the option of himself or his representatives to such share of the profits made since the dissolution as the court may find to be attributable to the use of his share of the partnership assets, or to interest at the rate of eight per centum per annum on the amount of his share of the partnership assets: 
<xhtml:p>Provided that where, by the partnership contract, an option is given to surviving or continuing partners to purchase the interest of a deceased or outgoing partner, and that option is duly exercised, the estate of the deceased partner or the outgoing partner or his estate, as the case may be, is not entitled to any further or other share of profits; but if any partner assuming to act in exercise of the option does not in all material respects comply with the terms thereof, he is liable to account under this section. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12216"><num>47</num><heading>SECTION 47 Retiring or deceased partner&amp;apos;s share to be a debt.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>47.</xhtml:b>Subject to any agreement between the parties, the amount due from surviving or continuing partners to an out-going partner or the representatives of a deceased partner in respect of the outgoing or deceased partner's share is a debt accruing at the date of the dissolution or death.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-12217"><num>48</num><heading>SECTION 48 Rule for distribution of assets on final settlement of accounts.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>48.</xhtml:b>In settling accounts between the partners after a dissolution of partnership, the following rules shall, subject to any agreement, be observed - 
<xhtml:p>(a) losses, including losses and deficiencies of capital, shall be paid first out of profits, next out of capital, and lastly, if necessary, by the partners individually in the proportion in which they were entitled to share profits; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) the assets of the firm, including the sums, if any, contributed by the partners to make up losses or deficiencies of capital, shall be applied in the following manner and order - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(i) in paying the debts and liabilities of the firm to persons who are not partners therein; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(ii) in paying to each partner rateably what is due from the firm to him for advances as distinguished from capital; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(iii) in paying to each partner rateably what is due from the firm to him in respect of capital; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(iv) the ultimate residue, if any, shall be divided among the partners in the proportion in which profits are divisible. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section></part><part id="part-1006"><num>VI</num><heading>PART VI GENERAL</heading><section id="section-12218"><num>49</num><heading>SECTION 49 Existing rules applicable to partnership.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>49.</xhtml:b>The rules of equity and common law applicable to partnerships in England shall apply to partnerships in Kenya, except in so far as they are inconsistent with the provisions of this Act. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section></part></body><outOfLines><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12170" id="w353aab1b9b1" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Short title.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12171" id="w353aab1b9b3" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Interpretation. 13 of 1978, Sch.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12172" id="w353aab1b9b5" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Definition of partnership. Cap.486.  
<xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12173" id="w353aab1b9b7" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Rules for determining existence of partnership.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12174" id="w353aab1b9b9" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Postponement of rights of persons lending or selling in consideration of share of profits in case of bankruptcy.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12175" id="w353aab1b9c11" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Meaning of </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12176" id="w353aab1b9c13" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Power of partner to the bind firm.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12177" id="w353aab1b9c15" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Partners bound by acts on behalf of firm.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12178" id="w353aab1b9c17" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Partners using credit of firm for private purposes.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12179" id="w353aab1b9c19" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Effect of notice that firm will not be bound by acts of partner.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12180" id="w353aab1b9c21" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Liability of partners.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12181" id="w353aab1b9c23" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Minor partner not personally liable, but his share is.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12182" id="w353aab1b9c25" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Liability of minor partner on attaining majority.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12183" id="w353aab1b9c27" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Liability of the firm for wrongs of partners.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12184" id="w353aab1b9c29" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Misapplication of money or property received for or in custody of the firm.  
<xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12185" id="w353aab1b9c31" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Liability for wrongs joint and several.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12186" id="w353aab1b9c33" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Improper employment of trust property for partnership purposes.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12187" id="w353aab1b9c35" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Persons liable by </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12188" id="w353aab1b9c37" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Admissions and representations of partners.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12189" id="w353aab1b9c39" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Notice to acting partner to be notice to firm.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12190" id="w353aab1b9c41" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Liability of incoming and outgoing partners.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12191" id="w353aab1b9c43" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Revocation of continuing guaranty by change in firm.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12192" id="w353aab1b9c45" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Variation by consent of terms of partnership.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12193" id="w353aab1b9c47" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Partnership property.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12194" id="w353aab1b9c49" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Property bought with partnership money.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12195" id="w353aab1b9c51" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Conversion into personal estate of land held as partnership property.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12196" id="w353aab1b9c53" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Execution against partnership property.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12197" id="w353aab1b9c55" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Rules as to interests and duties of partners.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12198" id="w353aab1b9c57" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Expulsion of partner.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12199" id="w353aab1b9c59" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Retirement from partnership at will.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12200" id="w353aab1b9c61" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Where partnership for a term is continued over, continuance on old terms presumed.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12201" id="w353aab1b9c63" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Duty of partners to render accounts, etc.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12202" id="w353aab1b9c65" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Accountability of partners for private profits.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12203" id="w353aab1b9c67" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Duty of partners not to compete with firm.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12204" id="w353aab1b9c69" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Rights of assignee of share in partnership.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12205" id="w353aab1b9c71" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Dissolution by expiration or notice.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12206" id="w353aab1b9c73" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Dissolution by bankruptcy, death or charge.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12207" id="w353aab1b9c75" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Dissolution by illegality of partnership.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12208" id="w353aab1b9c77" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Dissolution by the court.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12209" id="w353aab1b9c79" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Change in constitution of partnership.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12210" id="w353aab1b9c81" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Partner may notify dissolution.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12211" id="w353aab1b9c83" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Continuing authority of partners for purposes of winding up</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12212" id="w353aab1b9c85" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Rights of partners as to application of partnership property.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12213" id="w353aab1b9c87" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Apportionment of premium where partnership prematurely dissolved.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12214" id="w353aab1b9c89" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Rights where partnership dissolved for fraud or misrepresentation.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12215" id="w353aab1b9c91" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Right of outgoing partner in certain cases to share profits made after dissolution.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12216" id="w353aab1b9c93" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Retiring or deceased partner's share to be a debt.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12217" id="w353aab1b9c95" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Rule for distribution of assets on final settlement of accounts.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-12218" id="w353aab1b9c97" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Existing rules applicable to partnership.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine></outOfLines></act></akomaNtoso>