<akomaNtoso xmlns:an="http://www.akomantoso.org/1.0"><act contains="singleVersion"><meta><identification source="#kenyalaw"><FRBRWork><FRBRthis value="/ke/act/1970-06-05/44/main"/><FRBRuri value="/ke/act/1970-06-05/44"/><FRBRdate date="1970-06-05" name="Generation"/><FRBRauthor as="#author" href="#parliament"/><components><component href="#emain" id="wmain" name="main" showAs="Main Document"/></components></FRBRWork><FRBRExpression><FRBRthis value="/ke/act/1970-06-05/44/eng@/main"/><FRBRuri value="/ke/act/1970-06-05/44/eng@"/><FRBRdate date="1970-06-05" name="Generation"/><FRBRauthor as="#author" href="#parliament"/><components><component href="#mmain" id="emain" name="main" showAs="Main Document"/></components></FRBRExpression><FRBRManifestation><FRBRthis value="/ke/act/1970-06-05/44/eng@/main.xml"/><FRBRuri value="/ke/act/1970-06-05/44/eng@/.akn"/><FRBRdate date="1970-06-05" name="Generation"/><FRBRauthor as="#author" href="#parliament"/><components><component href="#mmain" id="mmain" name="main" showAs="Main Document"/></components></FRBRManifestation></identification><publication date="1970-06-05" name="" showAs=""/><lifecycle source="#bungeni"><event date="1970-06-05" id="e1" source="#ro1" type="generation"/></lifecycle><references source="#kenyalaw"><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActTitle" id="TheActTitle" showAs="Act Title"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActLongTitle" id="TheActLongTitle" showAs="Act Description"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/AssentDate" id="AssentDate" showAs="Assent Date"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/CommencementDate" id="CommencementDate" showAs="Commencement Date"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActNumber" id="TheActNumber" showAs="Act Number"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActID" id="TheActID" showAs="Act ID"/><TLCConcept href="http://bungeni-lexmigrate.googlecode.com" id="bungeni" showAs="Lex Migrator"/><TLCConcept href="http://kenyalaw.org" id="kenyalaw" showAs="Kenya Law"/></references><proprietary xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" source="#kenyalaw"><kl:meta name="gokcatid" num="4"/><kl:meta name="gokcatname">Civil Law and Procedure</kl:meta><kl:meta name="lexyy" num="1970"/><kl:meta name="lexmm" num="6"/><kl:meta name="lexdd" num="5"/></proprietary></meta><preface><block name="preface"><docTitle id="ActTitle" refersTo="#TheActTitle">Indemnity</docTitle><docTitle id="ActLongTitle" refersTo="#TheActLongTitle">An Act of Parliament to restrict the taking of legal proceedings in respect of certain acts and matters done in certain areas between the 25th December, 1963, and the 1st December, 1967, and to make provision for matters incidental thereto or connected therewith</docTitle><docDate date="1970-06-05" refersTo="#CommencementDate">Jun 5, 1970</docDate><docDate date="1111-11-11" refersTo="#AssentDate">Nov 11, 1111</docDate><docNumber id="ActNumber" refersTo="#TheActNumber">44</docNumber><docNumber id="ActIdentifier" refersTo="#TheActID">46</docNumber></block></preface><preamble><p>ARRANGEMENT OF SECTIONS</p><toc><tocItem href="#section-11948" level="2">1 Short title.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11949" level="2">2 Interpretation.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11950" level="2">3 Restriction on proceedings in respect of acts done in prescribed area.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11951" level="2">4 Saving for certain proceedings.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11952" level="2">5 Evidence.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11953" level="2">6 Saving for judgements.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-19422" level="2"> INDEMNITY (CONSTITUTION AND PROCEDURE OF COMMITTEES) ORDER, 1972</tocItem></toc></preamble><body><section id="section-11948"><num>1</num><heading>SECTION 1 Short title.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>1.</xhtml:b>This Act may be cited as the Indemnity Act.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11949"><num>2</num><heading>SECTION 2 Interpretation.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>2.</xhtml:b>In this Act, "the prescribed area" means the North-Eastern Province and the Isiolo, Marsabit, Tana River and Lamu Districts.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11950"><num>3</num><heading>SECTION 3 Restriction on proceedings in respect of acts done in prescribed area.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>3.</xhtml:b>(1) No proceeding or claim to compensation or indemnity shall be instituted or made in or entertained by any court, or by any authority or tribunal established by or under any law, for or on account of or in respect of any act, matter or thing done within or in respect of the prescribed area after the 25th December, 1963, and before 1st December, 1967, if it was - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) done in good faith; and</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) done or purported to be done in the execution of duty in the interests of public safety or of the maintenance of public order, or otherwise in the public interest,</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>by a public officer or by a member of the armed forces, or by a person acting under the authority of a public officer or of a member of the armed forces.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) If any proceeding or claim such as is referred to in subsection (1) of this section has been instituted before the commencement of this Act, it shall be discharged, subject in the case of proceedings instituted before the 1st June, 1969, to such order as to costs as the court may think fit to make.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11951"><num>4</num><heading>SECTION 4 Saving for certain proceedings.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>4.</xhtml:b>Section 3 of this Act does not prevent - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) the institution or prosecution of proceedings on behalf of the Government; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) the institution or prosecution of proceedings in respect of any rights under, or alleged breaches of, contract, if the proceedings are instituted within one year after the commencement of this Act.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11952"><num>5</num><heading>SECTION 5 Evidence.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>5.</xhtml:b>(1) The Minister shall appoint a Committee in each administrative district, consisting of the District Commissioner and the local elected leaders, which shall scrutinize every aggrieved case, and shall report their findings to the Minister, who shall issue the necessary certificate. 
<xhtml:p>(2) A certificate under subsection (1) of this section purporting to be signed by a Minister shall be presumed to have been so signed unless the contrary is proved.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) The Minister may make regulations generally for the implementation of this Act and in particular such regulations may - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) prescribe the constitution and rules of procedure of committees established under subsection (1) of this section; and</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) prescribe the purposes for which the Minister's certificate shall be sufficient evidence.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11953"><num>6</num><heading>SECTION 6 Saving for judgements.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>6.</xhtml:b>Nothing in this Act shall prejudice or prevent the institution or prosecution of proceedings for giving effect to a final judgment, decree or order given or made before the commencement of this Act by any court of final resort, or by any other court where the judgment, decree or order of such court is not then the subject of a pending appeal.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-19422"><num/><heading>SECTION  INDEMNITY (CONSTITUTION AND PROCEDURE OF COMMITTEES) ORDER, 1972</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:div><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>INDEMNITY (CONSTITUTION AND PROCEDURE OF COMMITTEES) ORDER, 1972</xhtml:b></xhtml:p></xhtml:div><xhtml:div>
  1. This Order may be cited as the Indemnity (Constitution and' Procedure of Committees) Order, 1972. 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:div>
  &#160; 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:div>
  2. In this order, "petitioner" means any person who submits to the committee a petition in respect of an aggrieved case. 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:div>
  &#160; 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:div>
  3. (1) Every committee shall consist of the District Commissioner who shall be the Chairman and two local elected leaders appointed by the Minister. 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:div>
  &#160; 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:div>
  (2) Every committee shall appoint a public officer in the district to be its secretary. 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:div>
  &#160; 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:div>
  4. (1) Every claim under the Act shall be made by a petition addressed to the Chairman of the Committee and such petition shall be in triplicate and in the form in the Schedule to this Order. 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:div>
  &#160; 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:div>
  (2) The petition shall be accompanied by such other written sub­missions as the petitioner may wish to make, and by a list of any witnesses he may propose to call, in support of the aggrieved case. 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:div>
  &#160; 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:div>
  (3) No further witnesses shall be called at the hearing except with the permission of the Chairman of the Committee 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:div>
  &#160; 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:div>
  5. The Committee shall, :within thirty days after receipt of a petition fix a date for the hearing of the petition and inform the petitioner accordingly. 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:div>
  &#160; 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:div>
  6. Where the Committee considers that the nature and particulars of the aggrieved' case are not adequately set out in the petition the Committee may require the petitioner to provide such further parti­culars as the Committee may consider necessary and within such period as the Committee may direct. 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:div>
  &#160; 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:div>
  7. The Committee may, where it considers it expedient so to do and with the consent of the petitioner, appoint one or more assessors to assist it and where an assessor is so appointed the Committee may compile its findings on the aggrieved case partially or wholly with the assistance of such assessor. 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:div>
  &#160; 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:div>
  8. The Committee shall have the same powers as are vested in a court when :trying a suit under the Civil Procedure Act in respect (1948). of the following matters 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:div>
  &#160; 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:div>
  ­ 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:div>
  (a) appearance of parties; 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:div>
  (b) enforcing the attendance of any person and examining him on oath or affirmation; and 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:div>
  (c) compelling the production of a document. 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:div>
  &#160; 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:div>
  9. The Chairman shall, in his discretion, decide whether or not the hearing of any petition shall be open to the public. 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:div>
  &#160; 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:div>
  10. A quorum of the Committee shall be the Chairman and one other member. 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:div>
  &#160; 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:div>
  11. A decision of the Committee shall be made by a majority of the votes of the members present and voting, and, in :the event of any equality of votes, the Chairman shall have and exercise a casting vote in addition to is original vote. 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:div>
  &#160; 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:div>
  12. Sittings of the Committee shall be held at the Office of the District Commissioner: 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:div>
  &#160; 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:div>
  Provided that such sittings may be held anywhere within the administrative district if this is necessary for the just assessment and scrutiny of the nature and particulars of any item set out in the petition. 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:div>
  &#160; 
</xhtml:div><xhtml:div>
  13. The Committee shall at any time correct any clerical mistakes, incidental errors or omissions appearing in any proceedings 'before it and shall forthwith notify the petitioner as to such corrections. 
</xhtml:div></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section></body><outOfLines><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11948" id="w522aab1b9b1" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Short title.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11949" id="w522aab1b9b3" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Interpretation.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11950" id="w522aab1b9b5" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Restriction on proceedings in respect of acts done in prescribed area.  
<xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11951" id="w522aab1b9b7" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Saving for certain proceedings.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11952" id="w522aab1b9b9" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Evidence.  
<xhtml:p>.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11953" id="w522aab1b9c11" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Saving for judgments.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-19422" id="w522aab1b9c13" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"/></foreign></outOfLine></outOfLines></act></akomaNtoso>