<akomaNtoso xmlns:an="http://www.akomantoso.org/1.0"><act contains="singleVersion"><meta><identification source="#kenyalaw"><FRBRWork><FRBRthis value="/ke/act/1958-06-20/85/main"/><FRBRuri value="/ke/act/1958-06-20/85"/><FRBRdate date="1958-06-20" name="Generation"/><FRBRauthor as="#author" href="#parliament"/><components><component href="#emain" id="wmain" name="main" showAs="Main Document"/></components></FRBRWork><FRBRExpression><FRBRthis value="/ke/act/1958-06-20/85/eng@/main"/><FRBRuri value="/ke/act/1958-06-20/85/eng@"/><FRBRdate date="1958-06-20" name="Generation"/><FRBRauthor as="#author" href="#parliament"/><components><component href="#mmain" id="emain" name="main" showAs="Main Document"/></components></FRBRExpression><FRBRManifestation><FRBRthis value="/ke/act/1958-06-20/85/eng@/main.xml"/><FRBRuri value="/ke/act/1958-06-20/85/eng@/.akn"/><FRBRdate date="1958-06-20" name="Generation"/><FRBRauthor as="#author" href="#parliament"/><components><component href="#mmain" id="mmain" name="main" showAs="Main Document"/></components></FRBRManifestation></identification><publication date="1958-06-20" name="" showAs=""/><lifecycle source="#bungeni"><event date="1958-06-20" id="e1" source="#ro1" type="generation"/></lifecycle><references source="#kenyalaw"><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActTitle" id="TheActTitle" showAs="Act Title"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActLongTitle" id="TheActLongTitle" showAs="Act Description"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/AssentDate" id="AssentDate" showAs="Assent Date"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/CommencementDate" id="CommencementDate" showAs="Commencement Date"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActNumber" id="TheActNumber" showAs="Act Number"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActID" id="TheActID" showAs="Act ID"/><TLCConcept href="http://bungeni-lexmigrate.googlecode.com" id="bungeni" showAs="Lex Migrator"/><TLCConcept href="http://kenyalaw.org" id="kenyalaw" showAs="Kenya Law"/></references><proprietary xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" source="#kenyalaw"><kl:meta name="gokcatid" num="10"/><kl:meta name="gokcatname">Police</kl:meta><kl:meta name="lexyy" num="1958"/><kl:meta name="lexmm" num="6"/><kl:meta name="lexdd" num="20"/></proprietary></meta><preface><block name="preface"><docTitle id="ActTitle" refersTo="#TheActTitle">Administration Police</docTitle><docTitle id="ActLongTitle" refersTo="#TheActLongTitle">An Act of Parliament to make provision for the establishment, discipline, powers and duties of the administration police, and for matters incidental thereto  
<p/></docTitle><docDate date="1958-06-20" refersTo="#CommencementDate">Jun 20, 1958</docDate><docDate date="1111-11-11" refersTo="#AssentDate">Nov 11, 1111</docDate><docNumber id="ActNumber" refersTo="#TheActNumber">85</docNumber><docNumber id="ActIdentifier" refersTo="#TheActID">65</docNumber></block></preface><preamble><p>ARRANGEMENT OF SECTIONS</p><toc><tocItem href="#part-1221" level="0">I PRELIMINARY</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-3437" level="2">1 Short title.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-3438" level="2">2 Interpretation.</tocItem><tocItem href="#part-1220" level="0">II ESTABLISHMENT AND ADMINISTRATION OF THE FORCE</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-3439" level="2">3 Establishment of the Force.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-3440" level="2">4 Appointment of administration police.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-3441" level="2">5 Employment of administration police.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-3442" level="2">6 Administration of administration police in districts</tocItem><tocItem href="#part-1222" level="0">III POWERS AND DUTIES OF ADMINISTRATION POLICE OFFICERS</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-3443" level="2">7 Area of duty.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-3444" level="2">8 Duties of officers.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-3445" level="2">9 Power to lay information or complaint.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-3446" level="2">10 Power to enter premises and to stop vehicles, etc., without warrant.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-3447" level="2">11 Power to stop and detain any person for production of licence, etc.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-3448" level="2">12 Power to erect barriers.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-3449" level="2">13 Powers of arrest without warrant.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-3450" level="2">14 Power to use firearms.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-3451" level="2">15 Custody of unclaimed property.</tocItem><tocItem href="#part-1223" level="0">IV PROTECTION OF OFFICERS</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-3452" level="2">16 Non-liability for act done under authority of a warrant.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-3453" level="2">17 [Repealed]</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-3454" level="2">18 Assault in execution of duty.</tocItem><tocItem href="#part-1224" level="0">V DISCIPLINE</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-3455" level="2">19 Nature of office.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-3456" level="2">20 Penalties for offences by officers.</tocItem><tocItem href="#part-1225" level="0">VI GENERAL</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-3457" level="2">23 Rules.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-3458" level="2">24 Standing orders.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-3459" level="2">25 Expenses.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-3460" level="2">26 Officers appointed under Act 10 of 1929.</tocItem></toc></preamble><body><part id="part-1221"><num>I</num><heading>PART I PRELIMINARY</heading><section id="section-3437"><num>1</num><heading>SECTION 1 Short title.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>PART 1-PRELIMINARY</xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>1. </xhtml:b>This Act may be cited as the Administration Police Act. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-3438"><num>2</num><heading>SECTION 2 Interpretation.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>2. </xhtml:b>In this Act unless the context otherwise requires - 
<xhtml:p>"chief" and "sub-chief" have the meanings respectively assigned to those expressions by the Chiefs' Authority Act; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"Commandant" means the Commandant of Administration Police; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"Force" means, the Administration Police Force established by section 3; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"officer" means an officer of the Force.<xhtml:br/></xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section></part><part id="part-1220"><num>II</num><heading>PART II ESTABLISHMENT AND ADMINISTRATION OF THE FORCE</heading><section id="section-3439"><num>3</num><heading>SECTION 3 Establishment of the Force.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>3. </xhtml:b>(1) There is hereby established a force, to be known as the Administration Police Force, which shall consist of such number of officers as may from time to time be authorized by the President.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) The Minister shall be the Commandant of the Force with the title of Commandant of Administration Police. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) The Force shall consist of officers of the ranks specified in the First Schedule; and the Minister may from lime to time, by notice in the Gazette, amend that Schedule. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-3440"><num>4</num><heading>SECTION 4 Appointment of administration police.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>4. </xhtml:b>(1) The District Commissioner of any district or area within which the Minister may, by notice in the Gazette, approve the appointment of administration police may appoint fit and proper persons to be officers of the Force within that district or area. 
<xhtml:p>(2) Every officer shall, on being appointed to the Force, make the declaration contained in the Second Schedule. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) The declaration shall be made before an administrative officer and shall be signed by the officer making it. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) A certificate of appointment in such form as may be required by the Commandant and signed by the District Commissioner shall be issued by the District Commissioner to every officer and shall be evidence of his appointment under this Act.<xhtml:br/></xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-3441"><num>5</num><heading>SECTION 5 Employment of administration police.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>5. </xhtml:b>(1) The Force shall be employed in Kenya for the performance of the duties hereinafter specified. 
<xhtml:p>(2) The President may, in case of war or other emergency, employ the Force or an part thereof in the defence of Kenya: </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Provided that any part of the Force so employed shall continue to be under the direction of the Commandant. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-3442"><num>6</num><heading>SECTION 6 Administration of administration police in districts</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>6. </xhtml:b>The District Commissioner of any district within which the appointment of administration police has been approved shall, except when the provisions of section 5 (2)are applied, administer the administration police in his district subject to the general or special directions of the Provincial Commissioner.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section></part><part id="part-1222"><num>III</num><heading>PART III POWERS AND DUTIES OF ADMINISTRATION POLICE OFFICERS</heading><section id="section-3443"><num>7</num><heading>SECTION 7 Area of duty.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>PART III -POWERS AND DUTIES OF ADMINISTRATION POLICE OFFICERS </xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>7</xhtml:b>. An officer shall carry out the duties imposed upon him by this Act within the district or area in which he is appointed. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-3444"><num>8</num><heading>SECTION 8 Duties of officers.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>8</xhtml:b>. Every officer shall - 
<xhtml:p>(a) when called upon by any chief or sub-chief assist him in the exercise of his lawful duties; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) obey and execute promptly all orders and warrants lawfully issued to him by any competent authority; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) preserve the public peace, prevent the commission of offences and apprehend all persons in respect of whom he holds a valid warrant of arrest; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(d) undergo such training as may be ordered by the District Commissioner; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>e) act as messenger in any matter connected with the administration or the public service. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-3445"><num>9</num><heading>SECTION 9 Power to lay information or complaint.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>9</xhtml:b>. An officer may lay an information or complaint before any subordinate court and may make application thereto for a summons, warrant or other legal process.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-3446"><num>10</num><heading>SECTION 10 Power to enter premises and to stop vehicles, etc., without warrant.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>10. </xhtml:b>(1) If an officer (other than a recruit constable) has reasonable cause to believe- 
<xhtml:p>(a) that anything necessary to the investigation of an alleged offence is in any premises and that the delay caused by obtaining a warrant to enter and search the premises would be likely to imperil the success of the investigation; or </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) that any person in respect of whom a warrant of arrest is in force, or who is reasonably suspected of being guilty of a cognizable offence, is in any premises, <xhtml:br/></xhtml:p><xhtml:p>he may demand that the person residing in or being in charge of such premises shall allow him free ingress thereto and afford him all reasonable facilities for a search therein, and if, after notification of his authority and purpose, ingress cannot without unreasonable delay be so obtained the officer may without warrant enter such premises and search therein, and may, if necessary in order to effect such entry, break open any outer or inner door or window or other part of such premises. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) An officer may stop, search and detain any vehicle or vessel which he has reasonable cause to suspect is being employed in the commission of, or to facilitate the commission of, an offence. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) A person who fails to obey a reasonable signal given by an officer in uniform requiring him to stop any vehicle or vessel shall be guilty of an offence and liable to imprisonment for a term not exceeding six months, and an officer may arrest that person without warrant unless he gives his name and address and otherwise satisfies the officer that he will duly answer any summons or other proceedings which may issue or be taken against him. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4)<xhtml:i> Repealed by 10 of 1997.</xhtml:i></xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-3447"><num>11</num><heading>SECTION 11 Power to stop and detain any person for production of licence, etc.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>11. </xhtml:b>(1) An officer in uniform may stop and detain any person whom he - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) sees doing any act or thing; or </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) sees in possession of any thing; or </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) suspects of doing any act or thing or of being in possession of any thing, <xhtml:br/></xhtml:p><xhtml:p>for which a licence, permit, certificate or pass is required under any written law and may require the person to produce the licence, permit, certificate or pass. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) A person who fails to produce a licence, permit, certificate or pass when called upon by an officer so to do may be arrested without a warrant unless he gives his name and address and otherwise satisfies the officer that he will duly answer any summons or other proceedings which may issue or be taken against him. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-3448"><num>12</num><heading>SECTION 12 Power to erect barriers.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>12. </xhtml:b>(1) A District Commissioner or a District Officer may, if he considers it necessary so to do for the maintenance and preservation of law and order or for the prevention or detection of any offence, order an officer to erect or place barriers in or across any road or street or in any public place. 
<xhtml:p>(2) An officer in uniform may take all reasonable steps to prevent any vehicle from being driven past any such barrier, and a driver who fails to comply with any reasonable signal given by an officer in uniform requiring him to stop the vehicle before the barrier shall be guilty of an offence and liable to imprisonment for a term not exceeding twelve months or to a fine not exceeding one thousand shillings or to both. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) <xhtml:i>Repealed by 10 of 1997.</xhtml:i></xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-3449"><num>13</num><heading>SECTION 13 Powers of arrest without warrant.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>13. </xhtml:b>An officer may without a warrant arrest - 
<xhtml:p>(a) a person whom he suspects on reasonable grounds of having committed a cognizable offence; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) person who commits a breach of the peace in his presence; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) a person who obstructs an officer while in the execution of his duty or who has escaped or attempts to escape from lawful custody; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(d) a person in whose possession is found anything which may reasonably be suspected to be stolen property or who may reasonably be suspected of having committed an offence with reference to that thing; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(e) a person whom he suspects upon reasonable grounds of being a deserter from the armed forces or the National Youth Service; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(f) person whom he finds in any highway, yard or other place during the night and whom he suspects upon reasonable grounds of having committed or being about to commit a felony; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(g) a person having in his possession without lawful excuse the burden of proving which excuse shall lie on the person, any implement of housebreaking; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(h) a person for whom he has reasonable cause to believe a warrant of arrest has been issued. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-3450"><num>14</num><heading>SECTION 14 Power to use firearms.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>14. </xhtml:b>An officer may use firearms, if and to such extent only as is necessary, against- 
<xhtml:p>(a) any person in lawful custody charged with or convicted of a felony, when that person is escaping or attempting to escape; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) any person who by force rescues or attempts to rescue any other person from lawful custody; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) any person who by force prevents or attempts to prevent the lawful arrest of himself or any other person: </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Provided that resort shall not be had to the use of firearms- </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(i) under paragraph (a), unless the officer has reasonable ground to believe that he cannot otherwise prevent the escape, and unless he shall give warning to such person that he is about to use firearms against him and such warning is unheeded; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(ii) under paragraph (b) or paragraph (c) unless the officer has reasonable ground to believe that he or any other person is in danger of grievous bodily harm or that he cannot otherwise prevent such rescue, or, as the case may be, effect such arrest. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-3451"><num>15</num><heading>SECTION 15 Custody of unclaimed property.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>15</xhtml:b>. Every officer shall take charge of all unclaimed property handed to him by any person or found by him to be unclaimed and shall deliver that property without delay to the nearest police station.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section></part><part id="part-1223"><num>IV</num><heading>PART IV PROTECTION OF OFFICERS</heading><section id="section-3452"><num>16</num><heading>SECTION 16 Non-liability for act done under authority of a warrant.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>16</xhtml:b>. (1) Where the defence to any suit instituted against an officer is that the act complained of was done in obedience to a warrant purporting to be issued by a court the court shall, upon production of the warrant, accept that warrant as prima facie evidence of the due making thereof and, upon proof that the act complained of was done in obedience to that warrant, enter judgement in favour of such officer. 
<xhtml:p>(2) No proof of the signature upon such warrant shall be required unless the court has reason to doubt its genuineness, and, where such signature is proved not to be genuine, the court shall nevertheless enter judgment in favour of the officer if it is satisfied that, at the time of the act complained of, such officer believed, or on reasonable grounds, that the signature was genuine. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-3453"><num>17</num><heading>SECTION 17 [Repealed]</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>17</xhtml:b>. [ Repealed by 9 of 1962. s. 2]<xhtml:br/></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-3454"><num>18</num><heading>SECTION 18 Assault in execution of duty.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>18. </xhtml:b>Any person who assaults, resists or wilfully obstructs any officer in the due execution of his duty or any person acting in aid of such officer shall be guilty of an offence and liable to imprisonment for a term not exceeding five years.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section></part><part id="part-1224"><num>V</num><heading>PART V DISCIPLINE</heading><section id="section-3455"><num>19</num><heading>SECTION 19 Nature of office.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>PART V-DISCIPLINE</xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>19.&#160; </xhtml:b>Every officer shall be deemed to be an officer in the public service of Kenya and, save as otherwise provided in this Act or in any rules or standing orders made under this Act, shall be subject to the law and regulations from time to time in force relating to the public service.<xhtml:br/></xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-3456"><num>20</num><heading>SECTION 20 Penalties for offences by officers.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>20. </xhtml:b>(1) Any officer who wilfully disobeys any lawful order or warrant or who is guilty of any act or conduct to the prejudice of good order or discipline shall be liable to be punished by a District Commissioner or a District Officer, or by any public officer duly authorized in writing by a Provincial Commissioner, by - 
<xhtml:p>(a) reprimand: or </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) confinement to barracks for a period not exceeding fourteen days, with or without punishment drills, extra guard fatigues or other duties; or </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) fine not exceeding the equivalent of fourteen days pay; or </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(d) stoppage of salary increments; or </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(e) reduction in rank; or </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(f) dismissal from the Force, <xhtml:br/></xhtml:p><xhtml:p>or by any combination of such punishments: </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Provided that - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(i) any sentence by a District Officer or public officer authorized as aforesaid shall be subject to confirmation by a District Commissioner; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(ii) any sentence of dismissal from the Force awarded by a District Commissioner shall be subject to confirmation by a Provincial Commissioner; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(iii) no District Officer or public officer authorized as aforesaid shall impose the sentence of dismissal. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) The officer awarding, or, as the case may be, confirming, any punishment inflicted upon an administration police officer under this section shall enter a record of such punishment, the date thereof and the offence for which it was inflicted on the record sheet of such administration police officer. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) All fines imposed by a District Commissioner, District Officer or other public officer under this section shall be recoverable by monthly deductions from the pay due and thereafter becoming due to the administration police officer. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) The amount of such deduction in respect of any fine shall, subject to any general or special direction by a Provincial Commissioner, lie in the discretion of the officer imposing the fine, but shall in no case exceed one-third of the monthly salary of the administration police officer concerned; and whenever more than one order for deduction from an administration police officer's salary is in force, so much only of his salary may be deducted as shall leave such officer not less than two-thirds of his salary.<xhtml:br/></xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section></part><part id="part-1225"><num>VI</num><heading>PART VI GENERAL</heading><section id="section-3457"><num>23</num><heading>SECTION 23 Rules.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>23</xhtml:b>. The Minister may make rules for the better carrying into effect of the provisions of this Act.<xhtml:br/></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-3458"><num>24</num><heading>SECTION 24 Standing orders.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>24</xhtml:b>. The Commandant may issue standing orders for the general control, direction and administration of the Force.<xhtml:br/></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-3459"><num>25</num><heading>SECTION 25 Expenses.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>25</xhtml:b>. The expenditure incurred in carrying out the provisions of this Act shall be defrayed out of moneys provided by Parliament.<xhtml:br/></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-3460"><num>26</num><heading>SECTION 26 Officers appointed under Act 10 of 1929.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>26</xhtml:b>. Any tribal police officer appointed under the Tribal Police Act 1929, shall be deemed to have been appointed under this Act.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section></part></body><outOfLines><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-3437" id="w736aab1b9b1" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Short title.9 of 1967, Sch</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-3438" id="w736aab1b9b3" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Interpretation. 20 of 1959, s .2 9 of 1967, Sch., 10 of 1969, Sch. Cap.128.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-3439" id="w736aab1b9b5" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Establishment of the Force. 9 of 1967,Sch</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-3440" id="w736aab1b9b7" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Appointment of administration police. 9 of 1967, Sch. 10 of 1969, Sch.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-3441" id="w736aab1b9b9" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Employment of administration police.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-3442" id="w736aab1b9c11" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Administration of administration police in districts.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-3443" id="w736aab1b9c13" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Area of duty. 14 of 1971, Sch.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-3444" id="w736aab1b9c15" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Duties of officers.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-3445" id="w736aab1b9c17" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Power to lay information or complaint. 17 of 1967, 1st Sch. 10 of 1983, Sch.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-3446" id="w736aab1b9c19" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Power to enter premises and to stop vehicles, etc., without warrant. 20 of 1959, s. 3. 10 of 1997.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-3447" id="w736aab1b9c21" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Power to stop and detain any person for production of licence, etc.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-3448" id="w736aab1b9c23" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Power to erect barriers. 20 of 1959, s. 4. 10 of 1997.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-3449" id="w736aab1b9c25" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Powers of arrest without warrant. 17 of 1967, 1st Sch.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-3450" id="w736aab1b9c27" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Power to use firearms.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-3451" id="w736aab1b9c29" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Custody of unclaimed property.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-3452" id="w736aab1b9c31" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Non-liability for act done under authority of a warrant. 10 of 1983, Sch.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-3453" id="w736aab1b9c33" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Repealed</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-3454" id="w736aab1b9c35" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Assault in execution of duty.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-3455" id="w736aab1b9c37" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Nature of office.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-3456" id="w736aab1b9c39" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Penalties for offences by officers.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-3457" id="w736aab1b9c41" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Rules.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-3458" id="w736aab1b9c43" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Standing orders.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-3459" id="w736aab1b9c45" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Expenses. 9 of 1967, Sch.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-3460" id="w736aab1b9c47" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Officers appointed under Act 10 of 1929.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine></outOfLines></act></akomaNtoso>