<akomaNtoso xmlns:an="http://www.akomantoso.org/1.0"><act contains="singleVersion"><meta><identification source="#kenyalaw"><FRBRWork><FRBRthis value="/ke/act/1966-03-29/76/main"/><FRBRuri value="/ke/act/1966-03-29/76"/><FRBRdate date="1966-03-29" name="Generation"/><FRBRauthor as="#author" href="#parliament"/><components><component href="#emain" id="wmain" name="main" showAs="Main Document"/></components></FRBRWork><FRBRExpression><FRBRthis value="/ke/act/1966-03-29/76/eng@/main"/><FRBRuri value="/ke/act/1966-03-29/76/eng@"/><FRBRdate date="1966-03-29" name="Generation"/><FRBRauthor as="#author" href="#parliament"/><components><component href="#mmain" id="emain" name="main" showAs="Main Document"/></components></FRBRExpression><FRBRManifestation><FRBRthis value="/ke/act/1966-03-29/76/eng@/main.xml"/><FRBRuri value="/ke/act/1966-03-29/76/eng@/.akn"/><FRBRdate date="1966-03-29" name="Generation"/><FRBRauthor as="#author" href="#parliament"/><components><component href="#mmain" id="mmain" name="main" showAs="Main Document"/></components></FRBRManifestation></identification><publication date="1966-03-29" name="" showAs=""/><lifecycle source="#bungeni"><event date="1966-03-29" id="e1" source="#ro1" type="generation"/></lifecycle><references source="#kenyalaw"><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActTitle" id="TheActTitle" showAs="Act Title"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActLongTitle" id="TheActLongTitle" showAs="Act Description"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/AssentDate" id="AssentDate" showAs="Assent Date"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/CommencementDate" id="CommencementDate" showAs="Commencement Date"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActNumber" id="TheActNumber" showAs="Act Number"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActID" id="TheActID" showAs="Act ID"/><TLCConcept href="http://bungeni-lexmigrate.googlecode.com" id="bungeni" showAs="Lex Migrator"/><TLCConcept href="http://kenyalaw.org" id="kenyalaw" showAs="Kenya Law"/></references><proprietary xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" source="#kenyalaw"><kl:meta name="gokcatid" num="8"/><kl:meta name="gokcatname">Criminal Law and Procedure</kl:meta><kl:meta name="lexyy" num="1966"/><kl:meta name="lexmm" num="3"/><kl:meta name="lexdd" num="29"/></proprietary></meta><preface><block name="preface"><docTitle id="ActTitle" refersTo="#TheActTitle">Extradition (Contiguous and Foreign Countries)</docTitle><docTitle id="ActLongTitle" refersTo="#TheActLongTitle">An Act to amend and consolidate the law relating to the extradition of criminals and for matters connected therewith and incidental thereto</docTitle><docDate date="1966-03-29" refersTo="#CommencementDate">Mar 29, 1966</docDate><docDate date="1111-11-11" refersTo="#AssentDate">Nov 11, 1111</docDate><docNumber id="ActNumber" refersTo="#TheActNumber">76</docNumber><docNumber id="ActIdentifier" refersTo="#TheActID">60</docNumber></block></preface><preamble><p>ARRANGEMENT OF SECTIONS</p><toc><tocItem href="#part-337" level="0">I PRELIMINARY</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-9536" level="2">1 Short title.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-9537" level="2">2 Interpretation.</tocItem><tocItem href="#part-338" level="0">II SURRENDER OF FUGITIVE CRIMINALS</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-9538" level="2">3 Application of Part.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-9539" level="2">4 Liability of fugitive criminals to surrender.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-9540" level="2">5 Requisition for surrender.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-9541" level="2">6 Issue of warrant.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-9542" level="2">7 Hearing of case and evidence.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-9543" level="2">8 Committal or discharge of prisoner.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-9544" level="2">9 Surrender of fugitive criminal.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-9545" level="2">10 Discharge of fugitive criminal.</tocItem><tocItem href="#part-339" level="0">III RECIPROCAL BACKING OF WARRANTS</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-9546" level="2">11 Application of Part.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-9547" level="2">12 Backing of warrants issued in another country.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-9548" level="2">13 Provisional warrant.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-9549" level="2">14 Return of prisoner.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-9550" level="2">15 Discharge of prisoner.</tocItem><tocItem href="#part-340" level="0">IV MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS RELATING TO SURRENDER AND RETURN</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-9551" level="2">16 Restrictions on surrender or return.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-9552" level="2">17 Evidence.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-9553" level="2">18 Authorization of warrants and depositions.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-9554" level="2">20 Search warrants.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-9555" level="2">21 Power to take photographs, X-rays, fingerpringts e.t.c. Cap. 75.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-9556" level="2">22 Declaration of application.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-9557" level="2">23 Discontinuance.</tocItem><tocItem href="#part-341" level="0">V TAKING OF EVIDENCE FOR CRIMINAL TRIALS IN OTHER COUNTRIES</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-9558" level="2">24 Obtaining evidence in Kenya.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-9559" level="2">25 Taking of evidence in Kenya for foreign criminal matters.</tocItem><tocItem href="#part-342" level="0">VI CRIMINALS SURRENDERED TO KENYA</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-9560" level="2">26 Trial of criminal surrendered.</tocItem><tocItem href="#part-343" level="0">VII TRANSITIONAL REPEAL AND APPLICATION</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-9561" level="2">27 Transitional.</tocItem></toc></preamble><body><part id="part-337"><num>I</num><heading>PART I PRELIMINARY</heading><section id="section-9536"><num>1</num><heading>SECTION 1 Short title.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>1</xhtml:b>. This Act may be cited as the Extradition (Contiguous and Foreign Countries) Act.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-9537"><num>2</num><heading>SECTION 2 Interpretation.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>2.</xhtml:b>(1) In this Act, unless the context otherwise requires - 
<xhtml:p>"conviction" and "convicted" do not include or refer to a conviction which under the law of some other country is a conviction for contumacy, but the term "accused person" includes a person convicted of contumacy; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"extradition crime" means a crime which, if committed within the jurisdiction of Kenya, would be one of the crimes described in the Schedule; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"fugitive criminal" means any person accused or convicted of an extradition crime committed within the jurisdiction of any other country who is in or is suspected of being in Kenya, and a reference to a fugitive criminal of a country is a reference to a fugitive criminal accused or convicted of an extradition crime committed within the jurisdiction of that country; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>" magistrate" means a chief magistrate, a senior principal magistrate, a principal magistrate, a senior resident magistrate or a resident magistrate </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"warrant" in the case of any other country includes any judicial document authorizing the arrest of a person accused or convicted of a crime. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) If any fugitive criminal or other person is arrested in pursuance of the provisions of this Act and brought before a magistrate who has no power to exercise jurisdiction under this Act, that magistrate shall have power to order such person to be brought before some magistrate having such jurisdiction, and to remand or admit such person to bail, and effect shall be given to any such order. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section></part><part id="part-338"><num>II</num><heading>PART II SURRENDER OF FUGITIVE CRIMINALS</heading><section id="section-9538"><num>3</num><heading>SECTION 3 Application of Part.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>3.</xhtml:b>(1) Where an agreement has been made with any country other than a designated Commonwealth country within the meaning of the Extradition (Commonwealth Countries) Act, with respect to the surrender to that country of any fugitive criminal, the Minister may, by order published in the Gazette, declare that this Part shall apply in the case of that country subject to such conditions, exceptions and qualifications as may be specified in the order, and this Part shall apply accordingly. 
<xhtml:p>(2) An order made under this section shall recite or embody the terms of the agreement and shall not remain in force for any longer period than the agreement.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) Every order made under this section shall be laid before the National Assembly.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-9539"><num>4</num><heading>SECTION 4 Liability of fugitive criminals to surrender.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>4.</xhtml:b>Subject to section 16, where this Part applies in the case of any country, ever fugitive criminal of that country who is in or suspected of being in Kenya shall be liable to be arrested, detained and surrendered in the manner provided by this Part - 
<xhtml:p><xhtml:i>(a)</xhtml:i>whether the crime in respect of which the surrender is sought was committed before or after the commencement of this Act or the application of this Part to that country; and</xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>(b)</xhtml:i>whether there is or is not any concurrent jurisdiction in a court in Kenya over that crime.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-9540"><num>5</num><heading>SECTION 5 Requisition for surrender.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>5.</xhtml:b>(1) A requisition for the surrender of a fugitive criminal of any country who is in or suspected of being in Kenya shall be made to the Minister by a diplomatic representative or consular officer of that country and, upon receipt of such requisition, the Minister may, by order under his hand, signify to a magistrate that a requisition has been made and require the magistrate to issue his warrant for the arrest and detention of the fugitive criminal. 
<xhtml:p>(2) If the Minister is of the opinion that the offence is one of a political character, he may refuse to make an order and may also at any time order a fugitive criminal accused or convicted of such offence to be discharged from custody.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-9541"><num>6</num><heading>SECTION 6 Issue of warrant.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>6.</xhtml:b>(1) The warrant for the arrest of a fugitive criminal, whether accused or convicted of a crime, who is in or suspected of being in Kenya, may be issued by a magistrate - 
<xhtml:p><xhtml:i>(a)</xhtml:i>on the receipt of the order of the Minister and on such evidence as would, in the opinion of the magistrate, justify the issue of the warrant if the crime had been committed or the criminal convicted in Kenya; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>(b)</xhtml:i>on such information or complaint and such evidence or after such proceedings as would, in the opinion of the magistrate, justify the issue of a warrant if the crime had been committed or the criminal convicted in Kenya.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) A magistrate issuing a warrant under this section without an order from the Minister shall forthwith send a report of the fact of the issue, together with the evidence and information or complaint or certified copies thereof, to the Minister, who may order the warrant to be cancelled and the person who has been arrested and detained on the warrant to be discharged.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) A fugitive criminal when arrested on a warrant under this section shall be brought before a magistrate as soon as possible.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) A fugitive criminal arrested and detained on a warrant issued without the order of the Minister shall be discharged by the magistrate unless the magistrate, within such reasonable time as, with reference to the circumstances of the case, he may fix, receives from the Minister an order signifying that a requisition has been made for the surrender of the criminal.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(5) The warrant of a magistrate issued in pursuance of this Part may be executed in any part of Kenya in the same manner as if it had been originally issued or subsequently endorsed by a magistrate having jurisdiction in the place where it is executed.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-9542"><num>7</num><heading>SECTION 7 Hearing of case and evidence.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>7.</xhtml:b>(1) When a fugitive criminal is brought before a magistrate, the magistrate shall hear the case in the same manner and have the same jurisdiction and powers, as nearly as may be, as in a trial before a subordinate court. 
<xhtml:p>(2) The magistrate shall receive any evidence which may be tendered to show that the case is one to which the relevant provisions of section 16 apply or that the crime of which the prisoner is accused is not an extradition crime.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-9543"><num>8</num><heading>SECTION 8 Committal or discharge of prisoner.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>8.</xhtml:b>(1) In the case of a fugitive criminal accused of an extradition crime, if the foreign warrant authorizing the arrest of the criminal is duly authenticated, and such evidence is produced as, subject to the provisions of this Act, would according to the law of Kenya, justify the committal for trial of the prisoner if the crime of which he is accused was committed in Kenya. The magistrate shall commit him to prison, but otherwise shall order him to be discharged. 
<xhtml:p>(2) In the case of a fugitive criminal alleged to have been convicted of an extradition crime, if such evidence is produced as, subject to the provisions of this Act would, according to the law of Kenya, prove that the prisoner was convicted of such crime, the magistrate shall commit him to prison, but otherwise shall order him to be discharged.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) If the magistrate commits such criminal to prison, he shall commit him to prison to await the warrant of the Minister for his surrender; and the magistrate shall forthwith send to the Minister a certificate of the committal and such report on the case as he may think fit.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-9544"><num>9</num><heading>SECTION 9 Surrender of fugitive criminal.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>9.</xhtml:b>(1) Whenever a magistrate commits a fugitive criminal to prison under this Part, he shall inform the criminal that he will not be surrendered until after the expiration of fifteen days and that he has a right to apply for the issue of directions in the nature of<xhtml:i>habeas corpus.</xhtml:i><xhtml:p>(2) Upon the expiration of the period of fifteen days, or, if directions in the nature of<xhtml:i>habeas corpus</xhtml:i>are issued, after the decision of the court upon the return to the directions, as the case may be, or after such further period as may be allowed in either case by the Minister, the Minister may by warrant under his hand order the fugitive criminal, if not set at liberty on the decision of the court, to be surrendered to such person as is in his opinion, duly authorized to receive the fugitive criminal by the country from which the requisition for the surrender proceeded, and the fugitive criminal shall be surrendered accordingly.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) Any person to whom such warrant is directed, and the person so authorized as aforesaid, may receive, hold in custody and convey into the jurisdiction of that country the criminal mentioned in the warrant.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-9545"><num>10</num><heading>SECTION 10 Discharge of fugitive criminal.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>10</xhtml:b>. Whenever a fugitive criminal who has been committed to prison is not surrendered and conveyed out of Kenya within two months after the committal or, if directions in the nature of <xhtml:i>habeas corpus </xhtml:i>are issued, after the decision of the court upon the return to the directions, any judge of the High Court may - 
<xhtml:p><xhtml:i>(a)</xhtml:i>upon application made to him by or on behalf of the criminal; and </xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>(b)</xhtml:i>upon proof that reasonable notice of the intention to make the application has been given to the Minister, </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>order the criminal to be discharged out of custody unless sufficient cause is shown to the contrary. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section></part><part id="part-339"><num>III</num><heading>PART III RECIPROCAL BACKING OF WARRANTS</heading><section id="section-9546"><num>11</num><heading>SECTION 11 Application of Part.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>11</xhtml:b>. (1) Where the Minister is satisfied that reciprocal provision has been or will be made by or under the law of any contiguous country other than a designate Commonwealth country within the meaning of the Extradition (Commonwealth Countries) Act, for the backing of warrants issued in Kenya and their execution in that country and that it is appropriate to do so, he may, by order published in the Gazette, declare that this Part shall apply in the case of that country subject to such conditions, exceptions and qualifications as may be specified in the order, and this Part shall apply accordingly. 
<xhtml:p>(2) Every order made under this section shall be laid before the National Assembly.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-9547"><num>12</num><heading>SECTION 12 Backing of warrants issued in another country.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>12.</xhtml:b>(1) Where a warrant has been issued in a country to which this Part applies for the arrest of a person accused of an offence punishable by law in that country, and he is or is suspected of being in or on the way to Kenya, a magistrate may, if satisfied that the warrant was issued by a person having lawful authority to issue it, endorse such warrant. 
<xhtml:p>(2) An endorsement of a warrant shall be signed by the magistrate and shall authorize all or any of the persons named in the endorsement and every police officer to execute the warrant by arresting the person named in it and bringing him before a magistrate.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) A warrant endorsed under this section shall be sufficient authority to arrest, within the jurisdiction of the endorsing magistrate, the person named in the warrant and to bring him before a magistrate.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) This Part shall apply whatever the date of the warrant and whether the offence is alleged to have been committed before or after the commencement of this Act or the application of this Part to the country concerned.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-9548"><num>13</num><heading>SECTION 13 Provisional warrant.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>13.</xhtml:b>(1) Notwithstanding that a warrant for the arrest of any person issued in a country to which this Part applies may not yet have been endorsed in pursuance of this Part, a magistrate may issue a provisional warrant for the arrest of such person on such information and under such circumstances as would, in his opinion, justify the issue of a warrant if the offence of which that person is accused were an offence punishable by the law of Kenya and had been committed within his jurisdiction; and such warrant may be endorsed in the manner provided in the Criminal Procedure Code, and may be executed accordingly. 
<xhtml:p>(2) Where a person is arrested under such a provisional warrant - <xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/><xhtml:i>(a)</xhtml:i>no order may be made under section 14 for his return to the country in which the original warrant was issued unless the original warrant is produced and endorsed in accordance with this Part; and</xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>(b)</xhtml:i>he shall be discharged unless the original warrant is produced and endorse within such time as the magistrate thinks reasonable in the circumstances.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-9549"><num>14</num><heading>SECTION 14 Return of prisoner.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>14.</xhtml:b>(1) Subject to section 16, where a person arrested under a warrant endorsed in accordance with section 12, or a provisional warrant issued under section 13, is brought before a magistrate and, in the case of a person arrested under a provisional warrant, the original warrant has been produced and endorsed, the magistrate may, if he is satisfied - 
<xhtml:p><xhtml:i>(a)</xhtml:i>that the warrant is duly authenticated as directed by this Act and was issued by a person having lawful authority to issue the same; and</xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>(b)</xhtml:i>by evidence on oath, that the prisoner is the person named or otherwise described in the warrant,</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>order the prisoner to be returned to the country in which the original warrant was issued, and for that purpose to be delivered into the custody of the persons to whom the warrant is directed or any one or more of them and to be held in custody and conveyed into that country.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) A person to whom the warrant is directed and the person so authorized may receive, hold in custody and convey into the jurisdiction of that country the prisoner mentioned in the warrant.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) A magistrate shall, so far as is requisite for the exercise of the powers of this section, have the same power, including the power to remand and admit to bail a prisoner, as he has in the case of a person arrested under a warrant issued by him.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) In proceedings under this section, the magistrate shall receive any evidence which may be tendered to show that the case is one to which the relevant provisions of section 16 apply.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-9550"><num>15</num><heading>SECTION 15 Discharge of prisoner.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>15.</xhtml:b>(1) Whenever a prisoner whose return is authorized in pursuance of this Pan is not conveyed out of Kenya within one month after the date of the order for his return, a magistrate may - 
<xhtml:p><xhtml:i>(a)</xhtml:i>upon application by or on behalf of the prisoner; and</xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>(b)</xhtml:i>upon proof that reasonable notice of the intention to make the application has been given to the person holding the warrant and to the. Commissioner of Police or chief officer of the police of the district, city, town or area where the prisoner is in custody; and</xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>(c)</xhtml:i>unless sufficient cause is shown to the contrary, order the prisoner to be discharged out of custody.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) Without prejudice to any application for directions in the nature of a writ of<xhtml:i>habeas corpus</xhtml:i>in respect of anything purporting to be done under this Part, any order or refusal to make an order of discharge under subsection (1) may be the subject of an appeal to the High Court.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) If, in any proceedings under this Part which are brought to his attention, the Minister is of opinion that the offence is one of a political character, he may order a person arrested under this Part to be discharged from custody.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section></part><part id="part-340"><num>IV</num><heading>PART IV MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS RELATING TO SURRENDER AND RETURN</heading><section id="section-9551"><num>16</num><heading>SECTION 16 Restrictions on surrender or return.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>Restrictions</xhtml:i></xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>16</xhtml:b>. (1) A fugitive criminal shall not be surrendered under Part II and a person arrested under Part III shall not be returned - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>(a)</xhtml:i>if the offence in respect of which his surrender is required, or the offence specified in the warrant, as the case may be, is one of a political character or if it appears to a court or the Minister that the requisition for the surrender, or the application for endorsement of a warrant and the return of the person named therein, has in fact been made with a view to try or to punish him for an offence of a political character; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>(b)</xhtml:i>if the fugitive criminal or the person arrested is accused of some offence triable by a court in Kenya or is undergoing sentence under any conviction in Kenya, until after he has been discharged, whether by acquittal or on the expiration of his sentence or otherwise.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) Subject to section 27, a fugitive criminal shall not be surrendered under Part II - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>(a)</xhtml:i>unless provision is made by the law of the country to which he is to be surrendered, or by agreement, that the fugitive criminal shall not, unless he has been restored or had an opportunity of returning to Kenya, be detained or tried in that country for any offence committed before his surrender other than an extradition crime proved by the facts on which the surrender is grounded; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>(b)</xhtml:i>until the expiration of fifteen days from the date of his being committed to prison to await his surrender.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) Where the return of a prisoner is sought or arranged under Part III and it appears to the magistrate that by reason of the trivial nature of the case, or by reason of the application for the return of the prisoner not being made in good faith in the interests of justice, or otherwise, it would, having regard to the distance, to the facilities of communication and to all the circumstances of the case, be unjust or oppressive or too severe a punishment to return the prisoner either at all or until the expiration of a certain period, the magistrate may discharge the prisoner either absolutely or on bail or order that lie shall not be returned until after the expiration of the period named in the order or may make such other order in the matter as the magistrate thinks proper.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) Without prejudice to any application for directions in the nature of a writ of<xhtml:i>habeas corpus</xhtml:i>in respect of anything purporting to be done under Part III, an order or refusal to make an order of discharge under subsection (3) may be the subject of an appeal to the High Court.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-9552"><num>17</num><heading>SECTION 17 Evidence.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>Evidence</xhtml:i></xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>17.</xhtml:b>(1) Depositions or statements on oath or affirmation taken in the country concerned and copies of the original depositions or statements and official certificates of or judicial documents stating the fact of conviction may, if duly authenticated, be received in evidence in any proceedings under this Act.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) In addition to any other means by which the same may be proved, a magistrate or the High Court - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>(a)</xhtml:i>shall take judicial notice of any law of a country by which the surrender of a fugitive criminal is required which makes provision for any such matter as is referred to in section 16 (2) (a), if an official copy of such law is produced and certified by the Minister responsible for foreign affairs or a diplomatic representative or consular officer of that country to be in force;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>(b)</xhtml:i>may receive as prima facie evidence of any such agreement as is referred to in the said paragraph a certificate to that effect by such Minister or diplomatic representative or consular officer aforesaid.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-9553"><num>18</num><heading>SECTION 18 Authorization of warrants and depositions.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>18.</xhtml:b>(1)Warrants and depositions or statements on oath or affirmation and copies thereof and certificate of or judicial documents stating the fact of a conviction shall be deemed duly authenticated for the purposes of this Act if authenticated in manner provided for the time being by law or if - 
<xhtml:p><xhtml:i>(a)</xhtml:i>the warrant purports to be signed by a judge, magistrate or officer of the country where it was issued; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>(b)</xhtml:i>the depositions or statements or the copies thereof purport to be certified under the hand of a judge, magistrate or officer of the country where they were taken to be the original depositions or statements or to be true copies thereof, as the case may require; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>(c)</xhtml:i>the certificate of or judicial document stating the fact of conviction purports to be certified by a judge, magistrate or officer of the country where the conviction took place;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>and in every case the warrants, depositions, statements, copies, certificates and judicial documents, as the case may be, are authenticated by the oath of some witness or - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(i) in a case to which Part II applies, by being sealed with the official seal of the Minister for the time being responsible for legal affairs, or some other Minister of State, of the country concerned; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(ii) in a case to which Part III applies, by sealing in the manner aforesaid or by the signature of the Attorney-General, Solicitor-General or Director of Public Prosecutions of the country concerned.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) All courts and magistrates shall take judicial notice of the official seal and signature referred to in paragraph (i) and (ii) of subsection (1) and shall admit any such document so authenticated in evidence without further proof.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-9554"><num>20</num><heading>SECTION 20 Search warrants.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>20.</xhtml:b>Where a warrant for the arrest of a person accused of an offence has been endorsed in pursuance of Part III, the magistrate shall have the same power of issuing a warrant to search for any property alleged to be stolen or otherwise unlawfully taken or obtained by such person, or otherwise to be the subject of such offence, as that magistrate would have if the property had been stolen or otherwise unlawfully taken or obtained, or the offence had been committed, wholly within the jurisdiction of such magistrate.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-9555"><num>21</num><heading>SECTION 21 Power to take photographs, X-rays, fingerpringts e.t.c. Cap. 75.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>21.</xhtml:b>(1) Any magistrate or police officer, and any person appointed to give certificates under subsection (2) of section 142 of the Criminal Procedure Code, may take, or cause to be taken in his presence -</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) during the course of any investigation into any drug related offence, such X-ray or other electromagnetic ray photographs as may be considered necessary for the purposes of the investigation; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) for the purposes of record and identification, the measurements, photographs, footprints and casts thereof, palmprints and fingerprints of any person in lawful custody or who is subject to police supervision.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Provided that if such person is not charged with an offence punishable by imprisonment or is discharged or acquitted by a court, and has not previously been convicted&#160; of an offence so punishable, all records of such X-rays or other electromagnetic ray photographs, measurements, photographs, footprints and casts thereof, palmprints and fingerprints and any negatives and copies of such photographs or of photographs of such footprints and casts thereof, palmprints and fingerprints shall forthwith be destroyed or handed over to such person.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) The Commissioner may specify the form upon which footprints, palmprints and fingerprints shall be taken in accordance with this section, and the magistrate, police officer or other person appointed as the case may be, shall certify on such form that thte footprints, palmprints or fingerprints have been taken by him, or caused to be taken in his presence, in accordance with the directions contained on such form and that the particulars entered on such form are to the best of his knowledge and belief accurate and true.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) Any person who refuses to permit such X-ray or other electromagnetic ray photographs, his measurements, photographs, footprints and casts thereof, palmprints and fingerprints to be taken under this section shall be guilty of an offence, and upon conviction, reasonable force may be used to enable such X-ray or other electromagnetic ray photographs as or, as the case may be, his measurements, photographs, footprints and casts thereof, palmprints and fingerprints to be taken.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) For the purposes of this Section the expression "drug related offence" means any offence specified in the Narcotic Drugs and Psychotropic Substances (Control) Act, 1994 and includes the possession, manufacture, sale, distribution, or receipt of any drug in any quantity whatsoever. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-9556"><num>22</num><heading>SECTION 22 Declaration of application.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>22.</xhtml:b>The Minister may from time to time, by order published in the Gazette, declare the countries to which Part II and Part III apply (including the countries to which Part II applies under section 27 and, subject to any later order providing for the discontinuance of such application, the declaration shall be conclusive as to the application of the relevant Part to countries to which it relates</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-9557"><num>23</num><heading>SECTION 23 Discontinuance.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>23.</xhtml:b>Whenever it appears to the Minister that an agreement with a country to which Part II of this Act applies is no longer in force (or in the case of country to which Part II applies under section 27 (1) (a), that the law of that country no longer contains reciprocal provision), or that the law of a country to which Part III applies no longer makes reciprocal provision or that such provision, has ceased to apply to Kenya or any part thereof, he may, by order published in the Gazette, discontinue the application of the appropriate Part to that country.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section></part><part id="part-341"><num>V</num><heading>PART V TAKING OF EVIDENCE FOR CRIMINAL TRIALS IN OTHER COUNTRIES</heading><section id="section-9558"><num>24</num><heading>SECTION 24 Obtaining evidence in Kenya.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>24.</xhtml:b>(1) The testimony of any witness may be obtained in relation to any criminal matter pending in any court or tribunal in any other country in like manner as it may be obtained in relation to any civil matter under any rules of court or any enactment for the time being in force in that part of Kenya in which the testimony is to be taken for the taking of evidence in relation to civil and commercial matters pending before the tribunals of other countries.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) Nothing in this section shall apply in the case of any criminal matter of a political nature.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-9559"><num>25</num><heading>SECTION 25 Taking of evidence in Kenya for foreign criminal matters.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>25.</xhtml:b>(1) Subject to section 24 (2), the Minister may, by order, require a magistrate to take evidence for the purpose of any criminal matter pending in any court or tribunal in any other country. 
<xhtml:p>(2) A magistrate, upon the receipt of an order made under this section, shall take down in writing the evidence of every witness appearing before him for the purpose in like manner as if the witness appeared in a preliminary inquiry and shall certify at the foot of the deposition so taken that the evidence was taken before him, and shall transmit it to the Minister.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) The evidence may be taken in the presence or absence of the person charged, if any, and the fact of the presence or absence shall be stated in the deposition.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) Any person may, after payment or tender to him of a reasonable sum for his costs and expenses in this behalf, be compelled, for the purposes of this section, to attend and give evidence and answer questions and produce documents in like manner and subject to like conditions as he may in the case of a trial for an offence.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section></part><part id="part-342"><num>VI</num><heading>PART VI CRIMINALS SURRENDERED TO KENYA</heading><section id="section-9560"><num>26</num><heading>SECTION 26 Trial of criminal surrendered.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>26.</xhtml:b>(1) Subject to subsection (2), where in pursuance of an agreement with another country any person accused or convicted of any crime described in the Schedule is surrendered by that country, that person shall not, until he has been restored or had an opportunity of returning to that country, be triable or tried for any offence committed before his surrender to Kenya other than such of the crimes as may be proved by the facts on which the surrender is grounded. 
<xhtml:p>(2) Nothing in this section shall apply in relation to a person surrendered or returned to Kenya by a country to which Part III applies.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section></part><part id="part-343"><num>VII</num><heading>PART VII TRANSITIONAL REPEAL AND APPLICATION</heading><section id="section-9561"><num>27</num><heading>SECTION 27 Transitional.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>PART VII - TRANSITIONAL, REPEAL AND APPLICATION </xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>27.</xhtml:b>(1) Subject to any order made under section 3 or section 23 of this Act - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>(a)</xhtml:i>a country to which Part I of the Fugitive Offenders Act 1881 of the United Kingdom (as in force in Kenya) applied immediately before the commencement of this Act; and </xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>(b)</xhtml:i>a country to which the Fugitive Criminals Surrender Act applied immediately before the commencement of this Act, </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>shall be a country to which Part II of this Act applies. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) The application of Part II of this Act by subsection (I) of this section shall have effect - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>(a)</xhtml:i>in the case of a country to which subsection (1) (a) of this section refers - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(i) notwithstanding that no agreement has been made with that country or that the terms of an agreement are not embodied in any order; and </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(ii) notwithstanding that no such provision or agreement as is referred to in section 16 (2) (a) of this Act is in force in or has been made with that country; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>and, unless provision is made by the Minister in an order under this section applying that paragraph to any such country, the surrender of a fugitive criminal to that country shall not be refused on the grounds set out in that paragraph; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>(b)</xhtml:i>in the case of a country to which subsection (1) (b) of this section refers, as if the terms of the relevant agreement and the conditions, exceptions and qualifications specified in any order made under the Fugitive Criminals Surrender Act and in force immediately before the commencement of this Act had been specified by order made under this Act. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section></part></body><outOfLines><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-9536" id="w675aab1b9b1" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Short title. 65 of 1968,s.19.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-9537" id="w675aab1b9b3" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Interpretation. 22 of 1987,Sch. L.N. 2/02</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-9538" id="w675aab1b9b5" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Application of Part. 65 of 1968,s. 19. Cap.77.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-9539" id="w675aab1b9b7" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Liability of fugitive criminals to surrender.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-9540" id="w675aab1b9b9" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Requisition for surrender.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-9541" id="w675aab1b9c11" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Issue of warrant.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-9542" id="w675aab1b9c13" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Hearing of case and evidence. 13 of 1982, 2nd Sch.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-9543" id="w675aab1b9c15" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Committal or discharge of prisoner.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-9544" id="w675aab1b9c17" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Surrender of fugitive criminal.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-9545" id="w675aab1b9c19" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Discharge of fugitive criminal.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-9546" id="w675aab1b9c21" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Application of Part. 65 of 1968, s. 19. Cap.77.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-9547" id="w675aab1b9c23" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Backing of warrants issued in another country.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-9548" id="w675aab1b9c25" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Provisional warrant.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-9549" id="w675aab1b9c27" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Return of prisoner.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-9550" id="w675aab1b9c29" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Discharge of prisoner.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-9551" id="w675aab1b9c31" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Restriction on surrender or return.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-9552" id="w675aab1b9c33" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Evidence.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-9553" id="w675aab1b9c35" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Authorization of warrants and depositions.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-9554" id="w675aab1b9c37" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Search warrants.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-9555" id="w675aab1b9c39" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Power to take photographs, X-rays, fingerpringts e.t.c. Cap. 75. L.N. 2/02</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-9556" id="w675aab1b9c41" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Declaration of application. 9 of l967,Sch.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-9557" id="w675aab1b9c43" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Discontinuance.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-9558" id="w675aab1b9c45" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Obtaining evidence in Kenya.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-9559" id="w675aab1b9c47" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Taking of evidence in Kenya for foreign criminal matters.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-9560" id="w675aab1b9c49" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Trial of criminal surrendered.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-9561" id="w675aab1b9c51" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Transitional.  
<xhtml:p>44 and 45 Vict., c.69. Cap. 77.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine></outOfLines></act></akomaNtoso>