<akomaNtoso xmlns:an="http://www.akomantoso.org/1.0"><act contains="singleVersion"><meta><identification source="#kenyalaw"><FRBRWork><FRBRthis value="/ke/act/1962-06-12/102/main"/><FRBRuri value="/ke/act/1962-06-12/102"/><FRBRdate date="1962-06-12" name="Generation"/><FRBRauthor as="#author" href="#parliament"/><components><component href="#emain" id="wmain" name="main" showAs="Main Document"/></components></FRBRWork><FRBRExpression><FRBRthis value="/ke/act/1962-06-12/102/eng@/main"/><FRBRuri value="/ke/act/1962-06-12/102/eng@"/><FRBRdate date="1962-06-12" name="Generation"/><FRBRauthor as="#author" href="#parliament"/><components><component href="#mmain" id="emain" name="main" showAs="Main Document"/></components></FRBRExpression><FRBRManifestation><FRBRthis value="/ke/act/1962-06-12/102/eng@/main.xml"/><FRBRuri value="/ke/act/1962-06-12/102/eng@/.akn"/><FRBRdate date="1962-06-12" name="Generation"/><FRBRauthor as="#author" href="#parliament"/><components><component href="#mmain" id="mmain" name="main" showAs="Main Document"/></components></FRBRManifestation></identification><publication date="1962-06-12" name="" showAs=""/><lifecycle source="#bungeni"><event date="1962-06-12" id="e1" source="#ro1" type="generation"/></lifecycle><references source="#kenyalaw"><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActTitle" id="TheActTitle" showAs="Act Title"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActLongTitle" id="TheActLongTitle" showAs="Act Description"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/AssentDate" id="AssentDate" showAs="Assent Date"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/CommencementDate" id="CommencementDate" showAs="Commencement Date"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActNumber" id="TheActNumber" showAs="Act Number"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActID" id="TheActID" showAs="Act ID"/><TLCConcept href="http://bungeni-lexmigrate.googlecode.com" id="bungeni" showAs="Lex Migrator"/><TLCConcept href="http://kenyalaw.org" id="kenyalaw" showAs="Kenya Law"/></references><proprietary xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" source="#kenyalaw"><kl:meta name="gokcatid" num="12"/><kl:meta name="gokcatname">General Administration</kl:meta><kl:meta name="lexyy" num="1962"/><kl:meta name="lexmm" num="6"/><kl:meta name="lexdd" num="12"/></proprietary></meta><preface><block name="preface"><docTitle id="ActTitle" refersTo="#TheActTitle">Commissions of Inquiry</docTitle><docTitle id="ActLongTitle" refersTo="#TheActLongTitle">An Act of Parliament to provide for the appointment of commissioners to inquire into and report on matters of a public nature referred to them by the President, to prescribe their powers, privileges and duties, and to provide for other matters relating thereto</docTitle><docDate date="1962-06-12" refersTo="#CommencementDate">Jun 12, 1962</docDate><docDate date="1111-11-11" refersTo="#AssentDate">Nov 11, 1111</docDate><docNumber id="ActNumber" refersTo="#TheActNumber">102</docNumber><docNumber id="ActIdentifier" refersTo="#TheActID">73</docNumber></block></preface><preamble><p>ARRANGEMENT OF SECTIONS</p><toc><tocItem href="#section-7909" level="2">1 Short title.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7910" level="2">2 Interpretation.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7911" level="2">3 Issue of commissions of inquiry.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7912" level="2">4 Power to appoint new commissioner and to revoke or amend commission.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7913" level="2">5 Oath of office by commissioner.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7914" level="2">6 Power to appoint secretary.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7915" level="2">7 Duties of commissioners.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7916" level="2">8 Division of opinion of commissioners.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7917" level="2">9 Commissioner&amp;apos;s power to regulate proceedings.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7918" level="2">10 Commissioner&amp;apos;s power to summon and examine witnesses.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7919" level="2">11 Expenses of witnesses.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7920" level="2">12 Appearance of advocates.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7921" level="2">13 Inquiry to be judicial proceeding for certain purposes.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7922" level="2">14 Privilege of commissioner and secretary from suit.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7923" level="2">15 Exemption from arrest under civil process.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7924" level="2">16 Police officers may be detailed to attend commissioner.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7925" level="2">17 Remuneration of commissioner and expenses of inquiry.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7926" level="2">18 Commissions, etc., to be published in Gazette.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7927" level="2">19 Regulations.</tocItem></toc></preamble><body><section id="section-7909"><num>1</num><heading>SECTION 1 Short title.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>1.</xhtml:b>This Act may be cited as the Commissions of Inquiry Act .</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7910"><num>2</num><heading>SECTION 2 Interpretation.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>2.</xhtml:b>In this Act, "commission", "commissioner" and "inquiry" mean respectively a commission issued, a commissioner appointed and an inquiry made under this Act.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7911"><num>3</num><heading>SECTION 3 Issue of commissions of inquiry.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>3.</xhtml:b>(1) The President, whenever he considers it advisable so to do, may issue a commission under this Act appointing a commissioner or commissioners and authorizing him or them, or any specified quorum of them, to inquire into the conduct of any public officer or the conduct or management of any public body, or into any matter into which an inquiry would, in the opinion of the President, be in the public interest.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) Every commission shall specify the matter to be inquired into, and shall direct where and when the inquiry shall be made and the report thereof rendered, and, where more commissioners than one are appointed, the commission may designate one such commissioner to be chairman, and, if the President so thinks fit, another such commissioner to be deputy chairman, of the commissioners.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) Without prejudice to any regulations made under section 19,vevery commission shall direct how the commission shall be executed and, in particular, shall in a suitable case contain the following directions to be observed by the commissioner - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>(a)</xhtml:i>that the commissioner shall conform with the following instructions - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(i) that evidence adversely affecting the reputation of any person, or tending to reflect in any way upon the character or conduct of any person, shall not be received unless the commissioner is satisfied it is relevant to the inquiry, and that all reasonable efforts have been made to give that person prior warning of the general nature of the evidence, and that, where no such warning has been given, the general nature of the evidence has been communicated to that person;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(ii) that that person shall be given such opportunity as is reasonable and practicable to be present, either in person or by his advocate, at the hearing of the evidence, to cross-examine any witness testifying thereto, and to adduce without unreasonable delay material evidence in his behalf in refutation of or otherwise in relation to the evidence;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(iii) that hearsay evidence which adversely affects the reputation of any person, or tends to reflect in any way upon the character or conduct of any person, shall not be received;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(iv) that no expression of opinion shall be received in evidence of the character, conduct or motives of any person, except in so far as the commissioner considers it essential, for ascertaining the truth of the matter into which he is commissioned to inquire, to depart from these instructions; and</xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>(b)</xhtml:i>that, in the event of any such departure from these instructions, the commissioner shall record his reasons therefore in the record of the inquiry, and shall report thereon, with his reasons therefore, in his report of the inquiry.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) A commission may direct that the public shall not be admitted to all or to any specified part of the proceedings of the inquiry; and subject to any such direction, every inquiry shall be held in public, but the commissioner may exclude any person or class of persons from all or any part of the proceedings of the inquiry if he is satisfied that it is desirable so to do for the preservation of order, for the due conduct of the inquiry, or for the protection of the person, property or reputation of any witness in the inquiry or any person referred to in the course of the proceedings thereof, and may, if he is satisfied that it is desirable for any of the purposes aforesaid so to do, order that no person shall publish the name, address or photograph of any such witness or person or any evidence or information whereby he would be likely to be identified, and any person who contravenes such an order shall, without prejudice to section 121 of the Penal Code, be guilty of an offence and liable to a fine not exceeding two thousand shillings.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7912"><num>4</num><heading>SECTION 4 Power to appoint new commissioner and to revoke or amend commission.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>4.</xhtml:b>(1) The President may at any time, if he considers it advisable so to do, revoke, or issue a commission amending a commission previously issued, and, without prejudice to the generality of the foregoing power, may by any such amending commission appoint an additional commissioner or commissioners, vary the designation of the chairman or deputy chairman of the commissioners, or appoint a new commissioner in the place of any commissioner who is or becomes unable or unwilling to act or dies or is, in the opinion of the President, for any reason unsuitable to continue to serve as a commissioner.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) Where the President issues an amending commission under subsection (1), it shall not be necessary, unless in the amending commission the President otherwise directs, for the inquiry to be begun afresh, and any proceedings which have taken place under or in pursuance of the commission before the amendment shall be deemed, for all the purposes of this Act, to be part of the proceedings taking place under or in pursuance of the commission as so amended.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7913"><num>5</num><heading>SECTION 5 Oath of office by commissioner.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>5.</xhtml:b>It shall be the duty of every commissioner appointed under this Act to make and subscribe before a judge of the High Court, prior to embarking on his duties as a commissioner, an oath in the prescribed form, and every such oath shall be deposited by the commissioner with the Attorney-General.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7914"><num>6</num><heading>SECTION 6 Power to appoint secretary.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>6.</xhtml:b>The President may appoint a person to be secretary to the commissioner or commissioners appointed by a commission issued under this Act.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7915"><num>7</num><heading>SECTION 7 Duties of commissioners.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>7.</xhtml:b>(1) It shall be the duty of a commissioner, after making and subscribing the prescribed oath, to make a full, faithful and impartial inquiry into the matter into which he is commissioned to inquire, to conduct the inquiry in accordance with the directions contained in the commission, and, in due course, to report to the President, in writing, the result of the inquiry and the reasons for the conclusions arrived at; and also, if so required by the President, to furnish to the President a full record of the proceedings of the commission.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) A commissioner may, and shall if so directed by the commission, include in his report recommendations as to any matter into which he is commissioned to inquire or any matter arising out of or connected with his inquiry.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7916"><num>8</num><heading>SECTION 8 Division of opinion of commissioners.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>8.</xhtml:b>If in any case the commissioners are divided on any question that arises during the proceedings of or in relation to their inquiry, the divergent views of the commissioners and the reasons therefor shall be recorded in the proceedings of the inquiry; and in the event of an equal division on any question requiring to be decided by the commissioners collectively, the chairman of the commissioners or, if the deputy chairman is presiding, the deputy chairman, shall have a second or casting vote:</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Provided that nothing in this section shall be construed as preventing any commissioner from submitting to the President a minority report on any matter in regard to which he dissents from the views or conclusions of all or any of his fellow commissioners.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7917"><num>9</num><heading>SECTION 9 Commissioner&amp;apos;s power to regulate proceedings.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>9.</xhtml:b>A commissioner (or the commissioners, if more than one) may make such rules, not inconsistent with any regulations made under section 19 or with the terms of the commission, for the conduct and management of the proceedings of the inquiry, and for specifying the hours and times and places for sittings, as he or they may from time to time think fit, and may from time to time adjourn for such time and to such place as he or they may think fit, subject only to any such regulations and to the terms of the commission.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7918"><num>10</num><heading>SECTION 10 Commissioner&amp;apos;s power to summon and examine witnesses.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>10.</xhtml:b>(1)Every commissioner shall have the powers of the High Court to summon witnesses, and to call for the production of books, plans and documents, and to examine witnesses on oath.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) All summonses for the attendance of witnesses or other persons, or for the production of documents, shall be in the prescribed form, and shall be signed by the commissioner, or by one of the commissioners if more than one, and oaths shall be administered by the commissioner, or by one of the commissioners if more than one, or by the secretary.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) Subject to the provisions of subsection (3) of section 3, where the commissioner considers it desirable for the purpose of avoiding expense or delay, or for any other good and sufficient reason, which shall be recorded in the record of the inquiry, he may receive evidence by affidavit.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7919"><num>11</num><heading>SECTION 11 Expenses of witnesses.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>11.</xhtml:b>(1) All persons summoned to attend and give evidence, or to produce books, plans or documents, at any sitting of a commissioner, shall be entitled to the same expenses as they would have been entitled to if they had been summoned to attend at the High Court in a criminal trial:</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Provided that the commissioner may disallow the whole or any part of those expenses in any case if he thinks fit to do so in the circumstances of the case.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) Orders for the payment of witnesses' expenses shall be made as nearly as practicable in the same form and in the same manner as orders for the payment of expenses made in the High Court, and payment shall be made in such manner as may be prescribed.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7920"><num>12</num><heading>SECTION 12 Appearance of advocates.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>12.</xhtml:b>Any person whose conduct is the subject of inquiry under this Act, or who is in any way implicated or concerned in any matter under inquiry, shall be entitled to be represented by an advocate in the proceedings of the inquiry or any part thereof, and any other person who desires to be so represented may, by leave of the commissioner, be so represented.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7921"><num>13</num><heading>SECTION 13 Inquiry to be judicial proceeding for certain purposes.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>13.</xhtml:b>(1) An inquiry shall be deemed to be a judicial proceeding for the purposes of Chapter XI and Chapter XVIII of the Penal Code. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) No person giving evidence in the proceedings of an inquiry shall be compellable to incriminate himself, and every person shall, in respect of any evidence given by him in any such proceedings, be entitled to all the privileges and immunities to which a witness giving evidence before the High Court is entitled in respect of evidence given by him before that court. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7922"><num>14</num><heading>SECTION 14 Privilege of commissioner and secretary from suit.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>14.</xhtml:b>A commissioner, and the secretary to any commissioner, shall not be liable to any civil action or suit for or in respect of any matter or thing done or omitted to be done by him in good faith as commissioner or secretary.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7923"><num>15</num><heading>SECTION 15 Exemption from arrest under civil process.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>15.</xhtml:b>No commissioner shall be liable to arrest under civil process while going to, presiding in or returning from the place where an inquiry under this Act is being held by him.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7924"><num>16</num><heading>SECTION 16 Police officers may be detailed to attend commissioner.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>16.</xhtml:b>The President may direct the Commissioner of Police to detail police officers to attend upon a commissioner to preserve order during the proceedings of the inquiry, to serve summonses on witnesses and to perform such administrative duties as the commissioner may direct.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7925"><num>17</num><heading>SECTION 17 Remuneration of commissioner and expenses of inquiry.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>17.</xhtml:b>(1) A commissioner shall not be entitled to any remuneration unless the commission otherwise provides.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) Subject to the general or special directions of the Minister, a commissioner shall be paid the expenses incurred by him in holding the inquiry, including the cost of employing a secretary and any other persons employed in or about the inquiry and any other expenses attendant upon the carrying out of the commission.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7926"><num>18</num><heading>SECTION 18 Commissions, etc., to be published in Gazette.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>18.</xhtml:b>Every commission, and every revocation of a commission, under this Act shall be published in the Gazette, and shall take effect, without prejudice to the provisions of subsection (2) of section 4, from the date of publication.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7927"><num>19</num><heading>SECTION 19 Regulations.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>19.</xhtml:b>The Minister may make regulations for prescribing anything which&#160;under this Act is required to be prescribed, and generally for carrying out the purposes of this Act. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section></body><outOfLines><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7909" id="w828aab1b9b1" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Short title.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7910" id="w828aab1b9b3" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Interpretation.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7911" id="w828aab1b9b5" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Issue of commission of inquiry. 29 of 1967, 1st Sch. Cap. 63.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7912" id="w828aab1b9b7" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Power to appoint new commissioner and to revoke or amend commission.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7913" id="w828aab1b9b9" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Oath of office by commissioner.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7914" id="w828aab1b9c11" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Power to appoint secretary.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7915" id="w828aab1b9c13" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Duties of commissioners.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7916" id="w828aab1b9c15" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Division of opinion of commissioners.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7917" id="w828aab1b9c17" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Commissioner's power to regulate proceedings.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7918" id="w828aab1b9c19" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Commissioner's power to summon and examine witnesses.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7919" id="w828aab1b9c21" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Expenses of witnesses.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7920" id="w828aab1b9c23" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Appearance of advocates.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7921" id="w828aab1b9c25" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Inquiry to be judicial proceeding for certain purposes. Cap. 63.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7922" id="w828aab1b9c27" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Privilege of commissioner and secretary from suit.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7923" id="w828aab1b9c29" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Exemption from arrest under civil process.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7924" id="w828aab1b9c31" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Police officers may be detailed to attend commissioner.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7925" id="w828aab1b9c33" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Remuneration o commissioner and expenses of inquiry.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7926" id="w828aab1b9c35" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Commissions, etc., to be published in Gazette.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7927" id="w828aab1b9c37" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Regulations.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine></outOfLines></act></akomaNtoso>