<akomaNtoso xmlns:an="http://www.akomantoso.org/1.0"><act contains="singleVersion"><meta><identification source="#kenyalaw"><FRBRWork><FRBRthis value="/ke/act/1111-11-11/109/main"/><FRBRuri value="/ke/act/1111-11-11/109"/><FRBRdate date="1111-11-11" name="Generation"/><FRBRauthor as="#author" href="#parliament"/><components><component href="#emain" id="wmain" name="main" showAs="Main Document"/></components></FRBRWork><FRBRExpression><FRBRthis value="/ke/act/1111-11-11/109/eng@/main"/><FRBRuri value="/ke/act/1111-11-11/109/eng@"/><FRBRdate date="1111-11-11" name="Generation"/><FRBRauthor as="#author" href="#parliament"/><components><component href="#mmain" id="emain" name="main" showAs="Main Document"/></components></FRBRExpression><FRBRManifestation><FRBRthis value="/ke/act/1111-11-11/109/eng@/main.xml"/><FRBRuri value="/ke/act/1111-11-11/109/eng@/.akn"/><FRBRdate date="1111-11-11" name="Generation"/><FRBRauthor as="#author" href="#parliament"/><components><component href="#mmain" id="mmain" name="main" showAs="Main Document"/></components></FRBRManifestation></identification><publication date="1111-11-11" name="" showAs=""/><lifecycle source="#bungeni"><event date="1111-11-11" id="e1" source="#ro1" type="generation"/></lifecycle><references source="#kenyalaw"><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActTitle" id="TheActTitle" showAs="Act Title"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActLongTitle" id="TheActLongTitle" showAs="Act Description"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/AssentDate" id="AssentDate" showAs="Assent Date"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/CommencementDate" id="CommencementDate" showAs="Commencement Date"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActNumber" id="TheActNumber" showAs="Act Number"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActID" id="TheActID" showAs="Act ID"/><TLCConcept href="http://bungeni-lexmigrate.googlecode.com" id="bungeni" showAs="Lex Migrator"/><TLCConcept href="http://kenyalaw.org" id="kenyalaw" showAs="Kenya Law"/></references><proprietary xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" source="#kenyalaw"><kl:meta name="gokcatid" num="12"/><kl:meta name="gokcatname">General Administration</kl:meta><kl:meta name="lexyy" num="1111"/><kl:meta name="lexmm" num="11"/><kl:meta name="lexdd" num="11"/></proprietary></meta><preface><block name="preface"><docTitle id="ActTitle" refersTo="#TheActTitle">Wakf Commissioners</docTitle><docTitle id="ActLongTitle" refersTo="#TheActLongTitle">An Act of Parliament to make better provision for the appointment of Wakf Commissioners, to prescribe their powers and duties and to amend the law relating to Wakf property</docTitle><docDate date="1111-11-11" refersTo="#CommencementDate">Nov 11, 1111</docDate><docDate date="1111-11-11" refersTo="#AssentDate">Nov 11, 1111</docDate><docNumber id="ActNumber" refersTo="#TheActNumber">109</docNumber><docNumber id="ActIdentifier" refersTo="#TheActID">80</docNumber></block></preface><preamble><p>ARRANGEMENT OF SECTIONS</p><toc><tocItem href="#section-7738" level="2">1 Short title and application.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7739" level="2">2 Interpretation.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7740" level="2">3 All wakfs to be administered in accordance with this Act.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7741" level="2">4 Validation of wakfs.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7742" level="2">5 Saving of previous judgments, orders or decrees.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7743" level="2">6 Constitution of Wakf Commissioners.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7744" level="2">7 Commissioners to be a body corporate with a common seal.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7745" level="2">8 Chairman and quorum.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7746" level="2">9 Secretary, officers and servants.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7747" level="2">10 Register of wakf property.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7748" level="2">11 Commissioners may take over administration of wakfs upon application.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7749" level="2">12 Commissioners may take over administration of wakfs which are being conducted in an improper or unauthorized manner.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7750" level="2">13 Trustees of wakfs may be called upon to produce evidence of proper administration of their trusts.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7751" level="2">14 Contracts or agreements relating to wakf property for more than one year must be sanctioned by commissioners.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7752" level="2">15 Titles to wakf property shall not be acquired by prescription or adverse possession after commencement of Act.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7753" level="2">16 How wakf property to be administered.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7754" level="2">17 Commissioners may dispose of wakf property in certain circumstances.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7755" level="2">18 Unclaimed property of deceased Muslims.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7756" level="2">19 Wakf property not to be used by commissioners towards another wakf while latter wakf property exists</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7757" level="2">20 Maintenance and reserve fund.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7758" level="2">21 Moneys to be paid into the surplus fund.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7759" level="2">22 Fees.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7760" level="2">23 Allowances to commissioners.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7761" level="2">24 Accounts and audit.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7762" level="2">25 Banking accounts.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7763" level="2">26 Rules.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7764" level="2">27 Saving.</tocItem></toc></preamble><body><section id="section-7738"><num>1</num><heading>SECTION 1 Short title and application.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>1.&#160; </xhtml:b>This Act may be cited as the Wakf Commissioners Act, and shall apply to such areas as the Minister may, by notice in the Gazette, direct. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7739"><num>2</num><heading>SECTION 2 Interpretation.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>2.&#160; </xhtml:b>In this Act, except where the context otherwise requires - 
<xhtml:p>"commissioner" means a member of the Wakf Commissioners appointed under section 6; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"Muslim" means an Arab, a member of the Twelve Tribes, a Baluchi, a Somali, a Comoro Islander, a Malagasy or a native of Africa, of the Muslim faith; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"trustee" includes any person, whether alone or jointly with another, in control of any property the subject of a wakf or in receipt of any rents or profits thereof; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"wakf" means the religious, charitable or benevolent endowment or dedication of any property in accordance with Muslim law; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"wakf Ahli" means a wakf made for the benefit of an individual or family, or for the performance of rites or ceremonies recognized by Muslim law as being for the benefit of the soul of an individual (including the dedicator) or of the souls of the members of a family; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"Wakf Commissioners" means the Wakf Commissioners of Kenya constituted under section 6; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"wakf Khairi" means a wakf, other than a wakf Ahli, made for any religious, charitable or benevolent public purpose recognized by Muslim law, including the provision and upkeep of cemeteries and burial grounds. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7740"><num>3</num><heading>SECTION 3 All wakfs to be administered in accordance with this Act.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>3.&#160; </xhtml:b>Every wakf made by or for the benefit of any Muslim shall be administered in accordance with the provisions of this Act: 
<xhtml:p>Provided that any person professing Islam who is not a Muslim within the meaning of section 2 may appoint the Wakf Commissioners to be the trustee of any property the subject of a wakf made by that person, and in every such case the Wakf Commissioners shall act as trustee thereof and the property shall be administered in accordance with this Act. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7741"><num>4</num><heading>SECTION 4 Validation of wakfs.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>4.&#160; </xhtml:b>(1) Every wakf heretofore or hereafter made by any Muslim which is made, either wholly or partly, for any of the following purposes - 
<xhtml:p><xhtml:em>(a)</xhtml:em> for the benefit, either wholly or partly, of the family, children, descendants or kindred of the maker or of any other person; or </xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:em>(b)</xhtml:em> the maker of the wakf is an Ibathi or Hanafi Mohammedan, for his own behalf during his lifetime, </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>is declared to be a valid wakf if - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(i) it is in every other respect made in accordance with Muslim law; and </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(ii) the ultimate benefit in the property the subject of the wakf is expressly, or, in any case in which the personal law of the person making the wakf so permits, impliedly, reserved for the poor or for any other purpose recognized by Muslim law as a religious, pious or charitable purpose of a permanent character: </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Provided that the absence of any reservation of the ultimate benefit in property the subject of a wakf for the poor or any other purpose recognized by Muslim law as a religious, pious or charitable purpose of a permanent character shall not invalidate the wakf if the personal law of the maker of the wakf does not require any such reservation. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) No wakf to which subsection (1) applies shall be invalid merely because the benefit in the property reserved by the wakf for the poor or any religious, pious or charitable purpose is not to take effect until after the extinction of the family, children, descendants or kindred of the maker of the wakf. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7742"><num>5</num><heading>SECTION 5 Saving of previous judgments, orders or decrees.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>5.</xhtml:b>Nothing in this Act shall affect any right, interest or estate in or to any property the title to which, whether vested or contingent, and whether in possession, reversion or remainder, accrued or was acquired before the commencement of this Act under any final judgment, order or decree of a court of competent jurisdiction.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7743"><num>6</num><heading>SECTION 6 Constitution of Wakf Commissioners.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>6.&#160; </xhtml:b>(1) There is hereby constituted a body to be known as the Wakf Commissioners of Kenya, which shall consist of eight persons, of whom - 
<xhtml:p><xhtml:em>(a)</xhtml:em> one shall be the Provincial Commissioner of the Coast Province, who shall be <xhtml:i>ex officio </xhtml:i>a member; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:em>(b)</xhtml:em> one shall be the Chief Kadhi, who shall be <xhtml:i>ex officio </xhtml:i>a member; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:em>(c)</xhtml:em> one shall be a Muslim appointed by the Minister on the nomination of the Provincial Commissioner of the Coast Province; and </xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:em>(d)</xhtml:em> five shall be Muslims appointed by the Minister from a panel of names submitted by the Provincial Commissioner of the Coast Province after taking into consideration Muslim opinion in relation thereto. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) Every commissioner appointed under paragraph <xhtml:em>(c)</xhtml:em> or paragraph <xhtml:em>(d)</xhtml:em> of subsection (1) shall hold office for a period of three years unless he sooner resigns or, for good cause, is removed by the Minister, but shall be eligible for reappointment. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) Any vacancy among the commissioners appointed under paragraphs <xhtml:em>(c) </xhtml:em>and <xhtml:em>(d)</xhtml:em> of subsection (1) shall be filled by some person appointed by the Minister in the same manner as the person whose vacancy is to be filled was appointed. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7744"><num>7</num><heading>SECTION 7 Commissioners to be a body corporate with a common seal.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>7.&#160; </xhtml:b>(1) The Wakf Commissioners shall be a body corporate having perpetual succession and a common seal, and shall have all the powers, functions and duties conferred and imposed by this Act. 
<xhtml:p>(2) The Wakf Commissioners may sue and be sued in its corporate name, and may for all purposes be described by that name. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) The seal of the Wakf Commissioners shall be authenticated by the signature of the chairman, or a commissioner authorized to act in that behalf, and the secretary, and the seal shall be officially and judicially noticed. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) All documents, other than those required by law to be under seal, made by, and all decisions of, the Wakf Commissioners may be signified under the hand of the chairman, any commissioner authorized in that behalf, or the secretary. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7745"><num>8</num><heading>SECTION 8 Chairman and quorum.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>8.&#160; </xhtml:b>(1) At the first meeting held in each year the Wakf Commissioners shall elect a prominent Moslem from among their members to be the chairman for the ensuing year. 
<xhtml:p>(2) The chairman shall preside over all meetings of the Wakf Commissioners at which he is present, and in his absence from any meeting the commissioners present shall elect a commissioner to preside over the meeting. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) A quorum of the Wakf Commissioners shall be three of whom one shall be an <xhtml:i>ex officio </xhtml:i>member. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7746"><num>9</num><heading>SECTION 9 Secretary, officers and servants.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>9.&#160; </xhtml:b>The Wakf Commissioners may, upon such terms and conditions as they may think fit, employ a secretary, who shall hold a professional qualification as an accountant or a secretary, and such other officers and servants as may be deemed requisite for the proper administration of the affairs of the Wakf Commissioners, and may dismiss any person so employed.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7747"><num>10</num><heading>SECTION 10 Register of wakf property.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>10.&#160; </xhtml:b>(1) The Wakf Commissioners shall keep, in such form and containing such particulars as may be prescribed, a register of all property the subject of a wakf. 
<xhtml:p>(2) Every trustee of property the subject of a wakf shall, within two months from the date of the making of the wakf, apply to the Wakf Commissioners to register it; and every application shall be in such form and shall contain such particulars and be accompanied by such fee as may be prescribed. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) All fees for the registration of property the subject of a wakf shall be credited by the Wakf Commissioners to a fund to be known as the general administration fund. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) Any trustee who fails to comply with the provisions of subsection (2) shall be guilty of an offence and liable to a fine not exceeding two thousand shillings or to imprisonment for a term not exceeding six months. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7748"><num>11</num><heading>SECTION 11 Commissioners may take over administration of wakfs upon application.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>11.&#160; </xhtml:b>On the application - 
<xhtml:p><xhtml:em>(a)</xhtml:em> in the case of wakf Khairi, of the trustee or trustees, as the case may be, of the wakf; and </xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:em>(b)</xhtml:em> in the case of wakf Ahli, of the trustee or trustees, as the case may be, with the consent of the majority of the beneficiaries of the wakf, </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>the Wakf Commissioners may take over, subject to such conditions as may be imposed by the Wakf Commissioners, the administration of the property the subject of the wakf and that property shall thenceforth vest in the Wakf Commissioners. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7749"><num>12</num><heading>SECTION 12 Commissioners may take over administration of wakfs which are being conducted in an improper or unauthorized manner.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>12.&#160; </xhtml:b>(1) In any case in which it appears to the Commissioners that - <xhtml:br/>(a) there is no properly constituted trustee of a wakf; or 
<xhtml:p>(b) any trustee is acting in an improper or unauthorized manner, </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>the Wakf Commissioners may, in the case of wakf Khairi of their own motion, and in the case of wakf Ahli on the motion of the majority of the beneficiaries, hold an inquiry. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) Written notice of such an inquiry shall be given to all persons having any interest in the wakf, and these persons shall by that notice be invited to appear and give evidence before the Wakf Commissioners. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) If, after holding an inquiry, the Wakf Commissioners find either that there is no properly constituted trustee of the wakf, or that any trustee is acting in an improper or unauthorized manner, the Wakf Commissioners may make an order either declaring that the property the subject of the wakf shall in future be administered by the Wakf Commissioners or appointing some other person or persons to be a trustee or trustees. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7750"><num>13</num><heading>SECTION 13 Trustees of wakfs may be called upon to produce evidence of proper administration of their trusts.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>13.&#160; </xhtml:b>(1) The Wakf Commissioners may at any time call upon any trustee of wakf property to satisfy it that the property is being properly administered, and may require the trustee to produce any document or books, whether of account or otherwise, in his possession or control relating to the property. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) Any trustee who fails to comply with a requirement to produce documents or books in his possession or control made by the Wakf Commissioners under subsection (1) shall be guilty of an offence and liable to a fine not exceeding two thousand shillings or to imprisonment for a term not exceeding six months. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7751"><num>14</num><heading>SECTION 14 Contracts or agreements relating to wakf property for more than one year must be sanctioned by commissioners.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>14.&#160; </xhtml:b>No contract or agreement of any description whatsoever purporting to sell or to lease or otherwise alienate any property the subject of any wakf for any period exceeding one year shall be valid unless the sanction in writing of the Wakf Commissioners has first been obtained. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7752"><num>15</num><heading>SECTION 15 Titles to wakf property shall not be acquired by prescription or adverse possession after commencement of Act.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>15.&#160; </xhtml:b>Notwithstanding anything to the contrary in any Act or law for the time being in force, no title to any property the subject of a wakf shall, after the commencement of this Act, be acquired by any person by reason of that person having been in adverse possession thereof or by reason of any law of prescription. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7753"><num>16</num><heading>SECTION 16 How wakf property to be administered.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>16.&#160; </xhtml:b>(1) Subject to the provisions of subsection (2), all property the subject of any wakf which is under the control of the Wakf Commissioners shall be administered by the Wakf Commissioners in accordance with the intentions of the maker of the wakf, if those intentions are lawful according to Muslim law and are capable, of being carried into effect, and whether those intentions are ascertainable by reference to tradition or by reference to any other evidence lawfully obtainable. 
<xhtml:p>(2) In any case where in the opinion of the Wakf Commissioners the intentions of the maker of a wakf are unlawful or unascertainable or are incapable of being carried out, or where any surplus revenue remains after fulfilling the intentions of the maker of the wakf, the Wakf Commissioners shall in the case of a wakf Khairi, apply the property the subject of the wakf or any surplus property or revenue therefrom, as the case may be, for such benevolent or charitable purposes on behalf of Muslims as appear to the Wakf Commissioners proper, and, in the case of a wakf Ahli, shall apply the property or surplus property or revenue in such manner as the wakf Commissioners think fit for the benefit of the beneficiaries of the wakf. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7754"><num>17</num><heading>SECTION 17 Commissioners may dispose of wakf property in certain circumstances.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>17.&#160; </xhtml:b>If it appears to the Wakf Commissioners that in respect of any wakf the intentions of the maker cannot reasonably be carried into effect and that it is accordingly expedient that the property the subject of the wakf or any part thereof should be sold, the Wakf Commissioners may cause that property or part thereof to be sold, and shall apply the proceeds of sale in the manner provided by subsection (2) of section 16: 
<xhtml:p>Provided that nothing in this section shall be deemed to authorize the sale of any land or any part thereof which under any wakf is to be used for a cemetery or burial ground or for the building of a mosque. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7755"><num>18</num><heading>SECTION 18 Unclaimed property of deceased Muslims.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>18.&#160; </xhtml:b>(1) Notwithstanding anything to the contrary in the Law of Succession Act, any property of a deceased Muslim to which no claim has been established within one year from the date upon which that property vested in the administrator of the estate or in the Public Trustee shall be handed over to<xhtml:br/>the Wakf Commissioners by the administrator or Public Trustee, as the case may be, and shall, if not handed over in the form of money, be converted into money and paid by the Wakf Commissioners into a special fund created for the purpose to be known as the surplus fund. 
<xhtml:p>(2) The surplus fund shall be utilized by the Wakf Commissioners for such benevolent or charitable purposes for the benefit of Muslims as the Wakf Commissioners may consider proper: </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Provided that if within twelve years from the date upon which any property of a deceased Muslim was handed over to the Wakf Commissioners pursuant to subsection (1), any person establishes a claim thereto, the Wakf Commissioners shall pay out of the surplus fund a sum equal to the amount paid into that fund in respect of the property of the deceased Muslim. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7756"><num>19</num><heading>SECTION 19 Wakf property not to be used by commissioners towards another wakf while latter wakf property exists</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>19.&#160; </xhtml:b>The Wakf Commissioners shall not utilize any property or any revenue from any property the subject of a wakf for any purpose connected with another wakf so long as there still exists any property the subject of the latter wakf: </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Provided that, if satisfied that any property the subject of a wakf Khairi is urgently in need of any expenditure for repairs or for any other purpose, the Wakf Commissioners may, notwithstanding that there exists property the subject of that wakf, utilize the revenue arising from property the subject of some other wakf Khairi for the purpose, if the Wakf Commissioners are satisfied that - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(i) that revenue is not then required in connation with the latter wakf Khairi; and </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(ii) the amount of the revenue so utilized will, without prejudice to the purposes of the wakf in connation with which it is used, be repaid out of the property of that wakf within five years from the date of being so utilized. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7757"><num>20</num><heading>SECTION 20 Maintenance and reserve fund.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>20.&#160; </xhtml:b>The Wakf Commissioners shall keep in respect of each wakf a maintenance and reserve fund, into which shall be paid, before any payment is made for the purpose of carrying out the intentions of the maker of the wakf, such sum as in the opinion of the Wakf Commissioners is necessary to maintain and preserve the property the subject of the wakf: 
<xhtml:p>Provided that the balance on hand in any maintenance and reserve fund shall not at any time exceed thirty per centum of the value of the property the subject of the wakf. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7758"><num>21</num><heading>SECTION 21 Moneys to be paid into the surplus fund.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>21.&#160; </xhtml:b>(1) If, in respect of any wakf - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) the intentions of the maker - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(i) are unlawful or unascertainable, or </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(ii) are incapable of being carried into effect, or </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(iii) cannot reasonably be carried into effect; or </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) the beneficiaries are unascertainable; or </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) any surplus revenue remains after making the payments required by section 20, and after carrying into effect the intention of the maker of the wakf. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>the Wakf Commissioners shall pay into the surplus fund created under section 18 the proceeds of sale of any property the subject of a wakf as is mentioned in paragraphs <xhtml:em>(a)</xhtml:em> and <xhtml:em>(b)</xhtml:em> of this subsection and any surplus revenue as is mentioned in paragraph <xhtml:em>(c)</xhtml:em> of this subsection. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) The Wakf Commissioners shall have power to place on deposit in any bank, or to invest in and upon such investments and securities as are allowed by law for the investment of trust funds, any moneys standing to the credit of the surplus fund, and income derived therefrom shall be paid to the credit of the general administration fund. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7759"><num>22</num><heading>SECTION 22 Fees.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>22.</xhtml:b>(1) There shall be charged by the Wakf Commissioners a fee of such amount as may from time to time be prescribed for the management of wakfs vested in the Wakf Commissioners; and until any other fee is prescribed, the Wakf Commissioners shall charge a fee at the rate of five per centum per annum of the revenue of the property of a wakf Khairi, and ten per centum per annum of the revenue of the property of a wakf Ahli. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) The money derived from such fees shall be paid into the general administration fund, and shall be utilized by the Wakf Commissioners first in defraying the expenses of management, and the surplus shall be used for such charitable purposes as the Wakf Commissioners may consider proper. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) No fees shall be prescribed under subsection (1) except after the passing of a resolution for that purpose by the majority of the commissioners present at a meeting of the Wakf Commissioners convened for the purpose. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7760"><num>23</num><heading>SECTION 23 Allowances to commissioners.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>23.&#160; </xhtml:b>The Wakf Commissioners may pay to any commissioner such allowance as the Minister may fix: </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Provided that the payment of any such allowance shall only be made after a resolution for the purpose has been passed by a majority of the commissioners present at a meeting of the Wakf Commissioners. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7761"><num>24</num><heading>SECTION 24 Accounts and audit.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>24.&#160; </xhtml:b>The Wakf Commissioners shall keep proper accounts of all property and money which comes into their hands, and such accounts shall be audited by an auditor approved by the Minister at such times as the Minister may direct.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7762"><num>25</num><heading>SECTION 25 Banking accounts.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>25.&#160; </xhtml:b>(1) The Wakf Commissioners shall open a banking account or banking accounts into which all moneys received by the Wakf Commissioners shall be paid, and out of which all payments authorized by the Wakf Commissioners shall be made. 
<xhtml:p>(2) Any such banking account shall be operated by the chairman, or a commissioner duly authorized in that behalf by the Minister, and the secretary. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7763"><num>26</num><heading>SECTION 26 Rules.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>26.&#160; </xhtml:b>The Wakf Commissioners may, with the approval of the Minister, make rules generally for the better carrying out of the provisions of this Act and for prescribing anything required by this Act to be prescribed.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7764"><num>27</num><heading>SECTION 27 Saving.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>27.&#160; </xhtml:b>All wakf property registered under the Wakf Commissioners Ordinance (now repealed) shall be deemed to have been duly registered under this Act.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section></body><outOfLines><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7738" id="w907aab1b9b1" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Short title and application. L.N.604/1963.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7739" id="w907aab1b9b3" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Interpretation.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7740" id="w907aab1b9b5" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">All wakfs to be administered in accordance with this Act.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7741" id="w907aab1b9b7" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Validation of wakfs. 19 of 1964, s. 2.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7742" id="w907aab1b9b9" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Saving of previous judgments, orders or decrees.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7743" id="w907aab1b9c11" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Constitution of Wakf Commissioners. 14 of 1971, Sch.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7744" id="w907aab1b9c13" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Commissioners to be a body corporate with a common seal.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7745" id="w907aab1b9c15" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Chairman and quorum. 14 of 1971, Sch.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7746" id="w907aab1b9c17" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Secretary, officers and servants. 14 of 1971, Sch.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7747" id="w907aab1b9c19" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Register of wakf property.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7748" id="w907aab1b9c21" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Commissioners may take over administration of wakfs upon application.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7749" id="w907aab1b9c23" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Commissioners may take over administration of wakfs which are being conducted in an improper or unauthorized manner.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7750" id="w907aab1b9c25" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Trustees of wakfs may be called upon to produce evidence of proper administration of their trusts.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7751" id="w907aab1b9c27" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Contracts or agreements relating to wakf property for more than one year must be sanctioned by commissioners.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7752" id="w907aab1b9c29" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Titles to wakf property shall not be acquired by prescription or adverse possession after commencement of Act.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7753" id="w907aab1b9c31" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">How wakf property to be administered.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7754" id="w907aab1b9c33" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Commissioners may dispose of wakf property in certain circumstances.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7755" id="w907aab1b9c35" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Unclaimed property of deceased Muslims. Cap. 160.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7756" id="w907aab1b9c37" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Wakf property not to be used by commissioners towards another wakf while latter wakf property exists.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7757" id="w907aab1b9c39" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Maintenance and reserve fund.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7758" id="w907aab1b9c41" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Moneys to be paid into the surplus fund.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7759" id="w907aab1b9c43" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Fees.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7760" id="w907aab1b9c45" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Allowances to commissioners 14 of 1971, Sch.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7761" id="w907aab1b9c47" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Accounts and audit. L.N.604/1963.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7762" id="w907aab1b9c49" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Banking accounts. 14 of 1971, Sch.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7763" id="w907aab1b9c51" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Rules. L.N.604/1963.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7764" id="w907aab1b9c53" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Saving. Cap. 47 (1948).</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine></outOfLines></act></akomaNtoso>