<akomaNtoso xmlns:an="http://www.akomantoso.org/1.0"><act contains="singleVersion"><meta><identification source="#kenyalaw"><FRBRWork><FRBRthis value="/ke/act/1111-11-11/128/main"/><FRBRuri value="/ke/act/1111-11-11/128"/><FRBRdate date="1111-11-11" name="Generation"/><FRBRauthor as="#author" href="#parliament"/><components><component href="#emain" id="wmain" name="main" showAs="Main Document"/></components></FRBRWork><FRBRExpression><FRBRthis value="/ke/act/1111-11-11/128/eng@/main"/><FRBRuri value="/ke/act/1111-11-11/128/eng@"/><FRBRdate date="1111-11-11" name="Generation"/><FRBRauthor as="#author" href="#parliament"/><components><component href="#mmain" id="emain" name="main" showAs="Main Document"/></components></FRBRExpression><FRBRManifestation><FRBRthis value="/ke/act/1111-11-11/128/eng@/main.xml"/><FRBRuri value="/ke/act/1111-11-11/128/eng@/.akn"/><FRBRdate date="1111-11-11" name="Generation"/><FRBRauthor as="#author" href="#parliament"/><components><component href="#mmain" id="mmain" name="main" showAs="Main Document"/></components></FRBRManifestation></identification><publication date="1111-11-11" name="" showAs=""/><lifecycle source="#bungeni"><event date="1111-11-11" id="e1" source="#ro1" type="generation"/></lifecycle><references source="#kenyalaw"><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActTitle" id="TheActTitle" showAs="Act Title"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActLongTitle" id="TheActLongTitle" showAs="Act Description"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/AssentDate" id="AssentDate" showAs="Assent Date"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/CommencementDate" id="CommencementDate" showAs="Commencement Date"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActNumber" id="TheActNumber" showAs="Act Number"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActID" id="TheActID" showAs="Act ID"/><TLCConcept href="http://bungeni-lexmigrate.googlecode.com" id="bungeni" showAs="Lex Migrator"/><TLCConcept href="http://kenyalaw.org" id="kenyalaw" showAs="Kenya Law"/></references><proprietary xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" source="#kenyalaw"><kl:meta name="gokcatid" num="12"/><kl:meta name="gokcatname">General Administration</kl:meta><kl:meta name="lexyy" num="1111"/><kl:meta name="lexmm" num="11"/><kl:meta name="lexdd" num="11"/></proprietary></meta><preface><block name="preface"><docTitle id="ActTitle" refersTo="#TheActTitle">Chiefs' Authority</docTitle><docTitle id="ActLongTitle" refersTo="#TheActLongTitle">An Act of Parliament to make provision in regard to the powers and duties of chiefs and to provide for matters incidental thereto</docTitle><docDate date="1111-11-11" refersTo="#CommencementDate">Nov 11, 1111</docDate><docDate date="1111-11-11" refersTo="#AssentDate">Nov 11, 1111</docDate><docNumber id="ActNumber" refersTo="#TheActNumber">128</docNumber><docNumber id="ActIdentifier" refersTo="#TheActID">95</docNumber></block></preface><preamble><p>ARRANGEMENT OF SECTIONS</p><toc><tocItem href="#section-7321" level="2">1 Short title.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7322" level="2">2 Interpretation.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-21005" level="2">3 Limitation as to powers of liwalis and mudirs.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7323" level="2">6 Duty of chief to maintain order.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7324" level="2">7 Chief may employ persons to assist him in carrying out duties.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-23156" level="2">7A Employment of village headpersons.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-23157" level="2">7B Number of village headpersons.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-23158" level="2">7C Removal from office. (No 3 of 2004).</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-23159" level="2">7D Transitional.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7325" level="2">8 Powers of chief in prevention of crime.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7326" level="2">10 Power of chief to issue orders for certain purposes.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7327" level="2">11 Further powers of chiefs to issue orders.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7328" level="2">12 Power to require work or services in emergency.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7329" level="2">13 Power to require work or services for conservation of natural resources.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7330" level="2">14 Remuneration and limitation on duration of work or services under section 13.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7331" level="2">15 Exemptions from section 13.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7332" level="2">16 Compensation for death or injury.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7333" level="2">17 Administrative officer may require chief to issue or cancel orders.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7334" level="2">18 Penalty for disobeying orders.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7335" level="2">20 Conduct of chiefs.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-7336" level="2">26 Rules.</tocItem></toc></preamble><body><section id="section-7321"><num>1</num><heading>SECTION 1 Short title.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>1.&#160; </xhtml:b>This Act may be cited as the Chiefs' Act.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7322"><num>2</num><heading>SECTION 2 Interpretation.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>2.</xhtml:b>In this Act, unless the context otherwise requires "chief" and "assistant chief" respectively mean the persons appointed for any area to the offices of chief and assistant chief, respectively, in the public service. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-21005"><num>3</num><heading>SECTION 3 Limitation as to powers of liwalis and mudirs.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:strong>3.</xhtml:strong>&#160; (Repealed by 10 of 1997, s.3)</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7323"><num>6</num><heading>SECTION 6 Duty of chief to maintain order.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>6.&#160; </xhtml:b>It shall be the duty of every chief or assistant chief to maintain order in the area in respect of which he is appointed, and for such purpose he shall have and exercise the jurisdiction and powers by this Act conferred upon him over persons residing or being within such area. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7324"><num>7</num><heading>SECTION 7 Chief may employ persons to assist him in carrying out duties.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>7.&#160; </xhtml:b>(1) A chief or assistant chief may employ any person or persons subject to his jurisdiction to assist him in carrying out the duties imposed upon him by this Act or otherwise by law, and any person so employed may carry out and give effect to any lawful order given by a chief or assistant chief.</xhtml:p>(2) A person employed under this section shall -<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(a) be known as a village headperson;<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(b) work under the direction and authority of the chief through the assistant chief.<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(3) The remuneration and terms of service of a person employed under this section shall be from public funds as determined by the Minister in consultation with the Treasury.<xhtml:br/><xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-23156"><num>7A</num><heading>SECTION 7A Employment of village headpersons.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">7A. (1) No persons shall be employed under subsection (1) of section 7 unless such person -  <xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(a) is a citizen of Kenya;<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(b) is of high integrity;<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(c) has attained a certificate in at least a primary level of education;<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(d) has resided in the area of service for a period of at least ten years immediately preceding the appointment;<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(e) has a good knowledge of the people and area of service.<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(2) Whenever there is a vacancy for the position of village headperson, the chief for the area of service shall -<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(a) advertise for the position on all Government premises within the area of service;<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(b) circulate the advertisements as widely as possible within the area of service.<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(3) The advertisement under subsection (2) shall set out -<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(a) the qualification as required under this Act;<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(b) duties of the village headperson;<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(c) the deadline for submitting applications which shall be not less than thirty days from the date of the advertisement.<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(4) Applications made pursuant to the advertisement under this section shall be delivered to the offices of the chief for the area of service who shall -<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(a) within twenty one days after expiry of the period within&#160; which the applications were to be submitted, make a short list of candidates from the applications received;<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(b) within thirty days after the short listing referred to in paragraph (a), invite all the shortlisted candidates for an interview.<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(5) The Chief may receive views from members of the public on a suitability of any candidates&#160; interviewed under this section and shall appoint the most suitable candidate to be the village headperson.<xhtml:br/></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-23157"><num>7B</num><heading>SECTION 7B Number of village headpersons.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">7B. (1) The number of village headpersons for each administrative district shall be determined by the Minister in accordance with the criteria set out in this section but the total number of village headpersons in the Republic shall, at any time, not exceed such number as may be prescribed.  <xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(2) All districts shall contain as nearly as possible equal numbers of village headpersons as appears to the Minister to be reasonably practicable.<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(3) The Minister may depart from the provisions of subsection (2) to the extent that it expedient in order to take into account the -<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(a) population density and trends so as to ensure that each village headperson has as nearly as possible the same number of people to serve;<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(b) the means of communication in the area;<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(c) geographical features of the area;<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(d) historical origin of the people of that area.<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-23158"><num>7C</num><heading>SECTION 7C Removal from office. (No 3 of 2004).</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">7C. (1) A village headperson appointed under this Act, shall be subject to the provisions of the Public Officer Ethics Act, 2003 and the provisions of section 20 of this Act.  <xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(2) Inquiry into the conduct of a village headperson may be instituted by the chief or upon complaint addressed to the chief in writing, made by or on behalf of any person.<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(3) The chief may require the complainant to file further particulars of any of the matters complained of and may require the complainant or any part thereof to be verified by affidavit.<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(4) Upon receipt of a complaint under this section, the chief shall notify the village headperson complained of, giving the grounds of the complaint but the chief may not disclose the identity of the complainants.<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(5) The chief may call upon the village headperson whose conduct is complained of or is under investigation to file, within ten days thereafter, an explanation in answer to the complaint and may require such explanation to be verified by affidavit.<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(6) The chief may summon any village headperson against whom any complaint has been lodged or whose conduct may appear to the chief to require investigation and may call upon sch person to produce any document or item under his control relating to or concerning the complaint or matter under investigation and may hear any evidence and inspect any document which the complainant or the village headperson may desire&#160; to adduce.<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(7) The village headperson against whom a complaint is made shall have the right to appear before the chief and to be heard either personally or through his advocate and may call such evidence and produce such evidence and produce such documents as may be relevant.<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(8) The chief, having inquired into the alleged misconduct of a village headperson may -<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(a) caution or censure the village headperson; or<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(b) suspend the village headperson from service for a period not exceeding six months; or<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(c) dismiss from service the village headperson.<xhtml:br/></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-23159"><num>7D</num><heading>SECTION 7D Transitional.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">7D. (1) Any person who, prior to the commencement of this Act, was serving as a village headperson&#160; shall, upon the coming into operation of this Act, continue to serve as such headperson as if appointed under this Act but subsequent&#160; appointments shall be made in accordance with the provisions of this Act.  <xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(2) The Minister shall, within thirty days after the coming into operation of this Act, cause to be carried out a census of all existing village headpersons for the purposes for the purpose of subsection (1).<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(3) Nothing in this Act shall be construed as imposing any financial obligations to the Government for any period prior to the commencement of this Act.<xhtml:br/></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7325"><num>8</num><heading>SECTION 8 Powers of chief in prevention of crime.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>8.&#160; </xhtml:b>(1) Any chief or assistant chief may interpose for the purpose of preventing, and shall to the best of his ability prevent, the commission of any offence by any person within the local limits of his jurisdiction. 
<xhtml:p>(2) Any chief or assistant chief knowing of a design by any person to commit an offence within the local 1imits of his jurisdiction may, if it appears to such chief or assistant chief that the commission of the offence cannot be otherwise prevented, arrest or direct the arrest of such person; and any person arrested under the powers conferred by this subsection shall, without delay, be taken to the nearest police station.<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(3) Every chief or assistant chief receiving information that any person who has committed a cognizable offence triable by any court or for whose arrest a warrant has been issued, is within the local limits of his jurisdiction shall cause such person to be arrested and to be taken forthwith before a court having jurisdiction in the matter. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) Every chief or assistant chief receiving information that any cattle or other livestock or other property of any description which has been stolen outside the local limits of his jurisdiction has been brought and is within such local limits shall cause such cattle or other livestock or other property to be seized and detained pending the orders of an administrative officer, and shall forthwith report such seizure and detention to an administrative officer. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7326"><num>10</num><heading>SECTION 10 Power of chief to issue orders for certain purposes.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>10.&#160; </xhtml:b>Any chief may from time to time issue orders to be obeyed by the persons residing or being within the local limits of his jurisdiction for any of the following purposes - 
<xhtml:p>(<xhtml:i>a</xhtml:i>) prohibiting or restricting the consumption or possession of intoxicating liquor by, and the supply of such liquor to, young persons; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(<xhtml:i>b</xhtml:i>) prohibiting or restricting the holding of drinking bouts; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(<xhtml:i>c</xhtml:i>) prohibiting or restricting the cultivation of poisonous or noxious plants, and the manufacture, transfer, sale and possession of noxious drugs or poisons;<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(<xhtml:i>d) </xhtml:i>prohibiting or restricting the carrying of arms;<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(<xhtml:i>e</xhtml:i>) prohibiting any act or conduct which in the opinion of the chief might cause a riot or a disturbance or a breach of the peace;<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(<xhtml:i>f</xhtml:i>) preventing the pollution of the water in any stream, watercourse or water-hole, and preventing the obstruction of any stream or watercourse;<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(<xhtml:i>g</xhtml:i>) regulating the cutting of timber and prohibiting the wasteful destruction of trees;<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(<xhtml:i>h</xhtml:i>) preventing the spread of disease, whether of human beings or animals;<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(<xhtml:i>i) </xhtml:i>prohibiting any act or thing which may cause damage to any public road or to any work constructed or maintained for the benefit of the community;<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(<xhtml:i>j) </xhtml:i><xhtml:i>Repealed by 10 of 1997.</xhtml:i></xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(<xhtml:i>k</xhtml:i>) <xhtml:i>Repealed by 10 of 1997</xhtml:i>.<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(<xhtml:i>l</xhtml:i>) destroying locusts in any stage of development;<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(<xhtml:i>m</xhtml:i>) <xhtml:i>Repealed by 10 of 1997.</xhtml:i><xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(<xhtml:i>n) </xhtml:i>controlling grass fires;<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(<xhtml:i>o) </xhtml:i>regulating the use of artificial water supplies constructed from public funds; and<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(<xhtml:i>p) </xhtml:i>for any other purpose authorized by this Act. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7327"><num>11</num><heading>SECTION 11 Further powers of chiefs to issue orders.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>11.&#160; </xhtml:b>Any chief may from time to time issue orders to be obeyed by the persons residing within the local limits of his jurisdiction for any of the following purposes - <xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(a) (<xhtml:i>Repealed by</xhtml:i>10 of 1997.) </xhtml:p><xhtml:p> </xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:br/>(b) (<xhtml:i>Repealed by</xhtml:i>10 of 1997.) </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) requiring persons to report the presence within the local limits of his jurisdiction of any property stolen or believed to have been stolen outside such local limits;<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(d) suppressing or controlling animal or insect pests or plant pests, noxious weeds or diseases;<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(e) (<xhtml:i>Repealed by</xhtml:i>10 0f 1997.)<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(f) requiring any person to report to his chief without delay the arrival in or the passage through his location from without of any cattle; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(g) (<xhtml:i>Repealed</xhtml:i>by 10 of 1997.)<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(h) requiring the proper burial of deceased persons in cemeteries or otherwise;<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(i) forbidding the deliberate exposure of persons supposed to be dying;<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(j) restricting or prohibiting the use of grazing by any form of stock in any area which has been set apart for the purpose of reconditioning or which has been planted with any fodder-producing plants or grass; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(k) (<xhtml:i>Deleted by</xhtml:i>L.N.101/1964.);<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(l) (<xhtml:i>Repealed by</xhtml:i>10 of 1997.)<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(m) for any of the purposes authorized by this Act. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7328"><num>12</num><heading>SECTION 12 Power to require work or services in emergency.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>12.&#160; </xhtml:b>Whenever it appears to the Minister that it is necessary for any work or service in connexion with an emergency consequent on fire, flood, earthquake, violent epidemic or epizootic disease, invasion by animal or insect pests or plant diseases or pests, or arising from circumstances which would endanger the existence of the whole or any part of the population, to be done or rendered, he may, in writing, authorize any chief to issue orders under this section to persons within the jurisdiction of such chief, and any chief so authorized may by any such order require any able-bodied adult person to perform any such work or render any such service as aforesaid specified in such order: 
<xhtml:p>Provided that - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(i) the Minister shall provide such food, housing and transport as he may consider necessary for persons engaged in performing any work or rendering any service under this section, while so engaged; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(ii) the Minister shall pay to any person who performs any work or renders any service under this section, and who by reason thereof is obliged to absent himself from his usual place of residence for a continuous period exceeding twelve hours, remuneration for such work or service at a rate not less favourable than the rate prevailing for similar work or service in the district in which the work is performed or the service rendered; and in any other case, if the Minister considers that it would be unjust or unreasonable to pay no remuneration for work performed or service rendered under this section, he may pay therefor such remuneration as he may consider just and reasonable; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(iii) any remuneration paid, and the cost of any food, housing or transport provided, under this section shall be paid from public funds. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7329"><num>13</num><heading>SECTION 13 Power to require work or services for conservation of natural resources.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>13.&#160; </xhtml:b>Whenever it appears to the Minister that it is necessary for any work or service in connexion with the conservation of natural resources to be done or rendered, the Minister may, by notice in the Gazette, authorize any chief to issue orders under this section to persons within the jurisdiction of such chief, and any chief so authorized may by any such order require any able-bodied adult male to perform any such work or to render any such service as aforesaid specified in such order:<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>Provided that a notice under this section shall not be issued unless the Minister is satisfied - 
<xhtml:p>(i) that the work to be done or the service to be rendered is of important direct interest to the community called upon to do the work or render the service;<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(ii) that the work or service is of present or imminent necessity;<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(iii) that it has been impossible to obtain voluntary labour for carrying out the work or rendering the service by the offer of rates of wages and conditions of employment not less favourable than those prevailing in the area concerned for similar work or service; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(iv) that the work or service will lay too heavy a burden on the community concerned, having regard to the labour available and its capacity to undertake the work; and </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(v) that the members of the community concerned, or their representatives, have been consulted in regard to the need for the work or service to be done or performed. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7330"><num>14</num><heading>SECTION 14 Remuneration and limitation on duration of work or services under section 13.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>14.&#160; </xhtml:b>(1) Any person required to do any work or render any service under section 13 shall be remunerated at a rate not less favourable than the rate prevailing for similar work or service in the district in which such work is performed or such service is rendered, and shall not be called upon to do any such work or render any such service for any period exceeding, or for any periods exceeding in the aggregate, sixty days, inclusive of any time spent in going to and returning from the place of work, in any one period of twelve months. 
<xhtml:p>(2) Every person who performs any work or renders any service under section 13 shall be furnished with a certificate showing the period or periods during which he has performed such work or rendered such service. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7331"><num>15</num><heading>SECTION 15 Exemptions from section 13.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>15.&#160; </xhtml:b>The following persons shall be exempt from the provisions of section 13 of this Act and from any order issued thereunder - 
<xhtml:p>(<xhtml:i>a) </xhtml:i>any person under the age of eighteen years or over the age of fifty years;<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(<xhtml:i>b</xhtml:i>) any teacher or student in a public school within the meaning of the Education Act or a school registered under Part IV of that Act; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(<xhtml:i>c</xhtml:i>) any person employed by the Government or any public local authority;<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(<xhtml:i>d</xhtml:i>) any person employed under the Employment Act; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:br/>(<xhtml:i>e</xhtml:i>) any person certified unfit for such work on health grounds by a medical practitioner or a medical officer. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7332"><num>16</num><heading>SECTION 16 Compensation for death or injury.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>16.&#160; </xhtml:b>Any person engaged in performing any work or rendering any service under section 12 or section 13 shall, while so engaged, be deemed, for the purposes of the Workmen's Compensation Act to be a workman employed by the Government, and, notwithstanding anything to the contrary contained therein, the provisions of that Act shall apply in respect of such person accordingly: 
<xhtml:p>Provided that, for the purposes of calculating the amount of any compensation payable under that Act by virtue of the provisions of this section, the rate of earnings of such person shall be deemed to be the rate of remuneration paid or payable to such person under section 12 or section 14,as the case may be, and, where no remuneration is so paid or payable, shall be the rate of remuneration prevailing in the district in which work was being performed or service rendered by such person under this Act for work or service similar thereto. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7333"><num>17</num><heading>SECTION 17 Administrative officer may require chief to issue or cancel orders.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>17.&#160; </xhtml:b>Whenever an administrative officer, considers that any order issued by a chief should not have been issued or should not be enforced he may direct the chief to cancel the order or to refrain from enforcing the order.<xhtml:br/></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7334"><num>18</num><heading>SECTION 18 Penalty for disobeying orders.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>18.&#160; </xhtml:b>Any person who, without lawful excuse, disobeys or fails to comply with any lawful order issued or given by a chief or assistant chief under this Act shall be guilty of an offence and liable to a fine not exceeding five hundred shillings and in default of payment, to extra mural penal employment for a period not exceeding fourteen days.<xhtml:br/></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7335"><num>20</num><heading>SECTION 20 Conduct of chiefs.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>20.&#160; </xhtml:b>(1) No chief shall - 
<xhtml:p>(a) engage in the activities of any political party or act as an agent of any such party; or </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) in the performance of his functions or the exercise of his powers under this Act - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(i) subject any person to torture or to any other cruel, inhuman or degrading treatment; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(ii) enter or search any private premises with a warrant duly issued by a magistrate; or </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(iii) demand or solicit any donations or collections in a manner likely to suggest that such donations or collections are a pre-condition for any service; or </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) maintain a cell or other place of confinement of persons. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) Without prejudice to the provisions of subsection (1), the minister may, in rules, prescribe a code of conduct to govern the conduct of chiefs in the exercise of their powers and the performance of their functions under this Act. </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) A chief who contravenes any of the provisions of this section or the provisions of any code of conduct prescribed under subsection (2) shall, without prejudice to any other penalty prescribed by law, be guilty of an offence and liable to a fine not exceeding ten thousand shillings, or to imprisonment for a term not exceeding one month, or to both. </xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-7336"><num>26</num><heading>SECTION 26 Rules.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>26.&#160; </xhtml:b>The Minister may make rules for the better carrying into effect of the provisions of this Act.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section></body><outOfLines><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7321" id="w1041aab1b9b1" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Short title. L.N.101/1964. 10 of 1997, Sch.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7322" id="w1041aab1b9b3" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Interpretation. L.N.461/1963, L.N.101/1964, 17 of 1967, 1st Sch., 13 of 1978, Sch.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-21005" id="w1041aab1b9b5" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Limitation as to powers of liwalis and mudirs.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7323" id="w1041aab1b9b7" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Duty of chief to maintain order. 43 of 1952, Sch., L.N.101/1964, 13 of 1978, Sch.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7324" id="w1041aab1b9b9" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p>Chief may employ persons to assist him in carrying out duties. 43 of 1952, Sch., 13 of 1978, Sch.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-23156" id="w1041aab1b9c11" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Employment of village headpersons.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-23157" id="w1041aab1b9c13" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Number of village headpersons.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-23158" id="w1041aab1b9c15" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Removal from office. (No 3 of 2004).</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-23159" id="w1041aab1b9c17" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Transitional.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7325" id="w1041aab1b9c19" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Powers of chief in prevention of crime. 43 of 1952, Sch., L.N.461/1963, L.N.101/1964, 9 of 1967, Sch., 17 of 1967, 1st Sch., 13 of 1978, Sch. 10 of 1997, Sch.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7326" id="w1041aab1b9c21" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Powers of chief to issue orders for certain purposes. L.N.362/1956, L.N.172/1960, L.N.461/1963, L.N.101/1964. 10 of 1997, Sch.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7327" id="w1041aab1b9c23" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Further powers of chiefs to issue orders. 43 of 1952, Sch., L.N.362/1956, L.N.172/1960, L.N.461/1963, L.N.101/1964. 10 of 1997, Sch.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7328" id="w1041aab1b9c25" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Power to require work or services in emergency. 43 of 1952, s. 3, L.N.461/1963, L.N.101/1964, 9 of 1967,Sch. 10 of 1997, Sch.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7329" id="w1041aab1b9c27" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Power to require work or services for conservation of natural resources. 43 of 1952, s. 3.  
<xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7330" id="w1041aab1b9c29" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Remuneration and limitation on duration of work or services under section 13. 43 of 1952, s. 3. L.N.101/1964.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7331" id="w1041aab1b9c31" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Exemptions from section 13. 43 of 1952, s.3. 10 of 1997, s. 3. 10 of 1997, Sch. Cap. 211.  
<xhtml:p>Cap. 226.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7332" id="w1041aab1b9c33" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Compensation for death or injury. 43 of 1952, s. 3 Cap. 236.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7333" id="w1041aab1b9c35" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Administrative officer may require chief to issue or cancel orders. 43 of 1952, Sch., L.N.461/1963. 10 of 1997, Sch.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7334" id="w1041aab1b9c37" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Penalty for disobeying orders. 43 of 1952, Sch., L.N.461/1963, L.N.101/1964, 17 of 1967, 1st. Sch., 13 of 1978, Sch. 10 of 1997, s. 8 10 of 1997, Sch..</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7335" id="w1041aab1b9c39" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Conduct of chiefs. 10 of 1997, Sch.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-7336" id="w1041aab1b9c41" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Rules. L.N.461/1963.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine></outOfLines></act></akomaNtoso>