<akomaNtoso xmlns:an="http://www.akomantoso.org/1.0"><act contains="singleVersion"><meta><identification source="#kenyalaw"><FRBRWork><FRBRthis value="/ke/act/1111-11-11/141/main"/><FRBRuri value="/ke/act/1111-11-11/141"/><FRBRdate date="1111-11-11" name="Generation"/><FRBRauthor as="#author" href="#parliament"/><components><component href="#emain" id="wmain" name="main" showAs="Main Document"/></components></FRBRWork><FRBRExpression><FRBRthis value="/ke/act/1111-11-11/141/eng@/main"/><FRBRuri value="/ke/act/1111-11-11/141/eng@"/><FRBRdate date="1111-11-11" name="Generation"/><FRBRauthor as="#author" href="#parliament"/><components><component href="#mmain" id="emain" name="main" showAs="Main Document"/></components></FRBRExpression><FRBRManifestation><FRBRthis value="/ke/act/1111-11-11/141/eng@/main.xml"/><FRBRuri value="/ke/act/1111-11-11/141/eng@/.akn"/><FRBRdate date="1111-11-11" name="Generation"/><FRBRauthor as="#author" href="#parliament"/><components><component href="#mmain" id="mmain" name="main" showAs="Main Document"/></components></FRBRManifestation></identification><publication date="1111-11-11" name="" showAs=""/><lifecycle source="#bungeni"><event date="1111-11-11" id="e1" source="#ro1" type="generation"/></lifecycle><references source="#kenyalaw"><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActTitle" id="TheActTitle" showAs="Act Title"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActLongTitle" id="TheActLongTitle" showAs="Act Description"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/AssentDate" id="AssentDate" showAs="Assent Date"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/CommencementDate" id="CommencementDate" showAs="Commencement Date"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActNumber" id="TheActNumber" showAs="Act Number"/><TLCConcept href="/ontology/concept/TheActID" id="TheActID" showAs="Act ID"/><TLCConcept href="http://bungeni-lexmigrate.googlecode.com" id="bungeni" showAs="Lex Migrator"/><TLCConcept href="http://kenyalaw.org" id="kenyalaw" showAs="Kenya Law"/></references><proprietary xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" source="#kenyalaw"><kl:meta name="gokcatid" num="13"/><kl:meta name="gokcatname">Children</kl:meta><kl:meta name="lexyy" num="1111"/><kl:meta name="lexmm" num="11"/><kl:meta name="lexdd" num="11"/></proprietary></meta><preface><block name="preface"><docTitle id="ActTitle" refersTo="#TheActTitle">Children and Young Persons (Repealed)</docTitle><docTitle id="ActLongTitle" refersTo="#TheActLongTitle">An Act of Parliament to make provision for the protection and discipline of children, juveniles and young persons, and for matters incidental thereto and connected therewith</docTitle><docDate date="1111-11-11" refersTo="#CommencementDate">Nov 11, 1111</docDate><docDate date="1111-11-11" refersTo="#AssentDate">Nov 11, 1111</docDate><docNumber id="ActNumber" refersTo="#TheActNumber">141</docNumber><docNumber id="ActIdentifier" refersTo="#TheActID">99</docNumber></block></preface><preamble><p>ARRANGEMENT OF SECTIONS</p><toc><tocItem href="#section-19063" level="2"> THE CHILDREN AND YOUNG PERSONS (APPROVED INSTITUTIONS) REGULATIONS</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-19064" level="2"> THE CHILDREN AND YOUNG PERSONS (REGISTRATION) REGULATIONS</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-19065" level="2"> THE CHILDREN AND YOUNG PERSONS (BOARDING-OUT) REGULATIONS</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11869" level="2">1 Short title</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11870" level="2">2 Interpretation.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11871" level="2">3 Juvenile courts.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11872" level="2">4 Sitting of Juvenile courts.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11873" level="2">5 Prohibition of publication</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11874" level="2">6 Prevention of persons under 16 associating with adult offenders.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11875" level="2">7 Children not allowed in court.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11876" level="2">8 Power to clear court.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11877" level="2">9 Power to require attendance of parent.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11878" level="2">10 Bail of persons under 18 arrested.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11879" level="2">11 Remand in custody.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11880" level="2">12 Jurisdiction of juvenile courts.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11881" level="2">13 Power to remit cases to juvenile courts</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11882" level="2">14 Considerations of welfare.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11883" level="2">15 Words &amp;quot;conviction&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;sentence&amp;quot; not to be used of children and young persons.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11884" level="2">16 Restrictions on punishments</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11885" level="2">17 Methods of dealing with offenders</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11886" level="2">18 Mental treatment.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11887" level="2">19 Power to order parent to pay fine, etc.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11888" level="2">20 Jurisdiction under Part III.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11889" level="2">21 Presumptions regarding custody, charge and care of children and juveniles.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11890" level="2">22 When child or juvenile is in need of protection or discipline.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11891" level="2">23 Penalty for cruelty to and neglecting children or juveniles.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11892" level="2">24 Proceedings in respect of children and juveniles in need of protection. or discipline.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11893" level="2">25 Powers of court in respect of children or juveniles in need of protection or discipline.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11894" level="2">26 Parent or guardian may be heard in any application.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11895" level="2">27 Application of trusts for maintenance of children or juveniles.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11896" level="2">28 Determination of court as to person&amp;apos;s home, etc., to be final.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11897" level="2">29 Warrants for search for children or juveniles.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11898" level="2">30 Arrest without warrant.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11899" level="2">31 Provisions as to orders of committal to fit persons</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11900" level="2">32 Contents of committal order.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11901" level="2">33 Transmission of order.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11902" level="2">34 Production of child or juvenile.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11903" level="2">35 Harbouring or concealing child or juvenile.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11904" level="2">36 Establishment of juvenile remand homes.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11905" level="2">37 Approval of schools.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11906" level="2">38 Minister may establish approved schools.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11907" level="2">39 Obligations of managers.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11908" level="2">40 Supervision of approved schools and juvenile remand homes.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11909" level="2">41 Establishment of advisory council.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11910" level="2">42 Leave of absence.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11911" level="2">43 Release on licence.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11912" level="2">44 Revocation of approved school order; duration of order.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11913" level="2">45 Transfers and supervision after release.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11914" level="2">46 Treatment of absconders and persons of bad character.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11915" level="2">47 Removal to hospital.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11916" level="2">48 Authority for detention in juvenile remand homes, approved schools and</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11917" level="2">49 Application of Part VI.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11918" level="2">50 Notification of taking possession of a person.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11919" level="2">51 Notification of change of residence or of death.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11920" level="2">52 Summary order for removal of person.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11921" level="2">53 Removal of person in respect of whom an offence has been committed.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11922" level="2">54 Appointment of chief inspector of children, inspectors of children and children&amp;apos;s officers.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11923" level="2">55 Duties of officers.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11924" level="2">56 Powers of officers.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11925" level="2">57 Obstruction.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11926" level="2">58 Appointment of local authorities.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11927" level="2">59 Application of powers and duties.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11928" level="2">60 Delegation of functions of county councils.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11929" level="2">61 Delegation of certain powers and duties by appointed local authorities.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11930" level="2">62 Powers of local authorities to incur expenditure in temporary care.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11931" level="2">63 Approval of approved societies.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11932" level="2">64 Appointment and powers of approved officers.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11933" level="2">65 Escapes from fit persons, etc</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11934" level="2">66 Approved societies and appointed local authorities to report escape.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11935" level="2">67 Escapes from juvenile remand homes and approved schools.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11936" level="2">68 Assisting escape, etc.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11937" level="2">69 Production of escaped person.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11938" level="2">70 Presumptions and determination of age.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11939" level="2">71 Contribution orders.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11940" level="2">72 Affiliation orders.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11941" level="2">73 International reciprocity.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11942" level="2">74 Bonds.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11943" level="2">75 Appeals.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11944" level="2">76 Regulations.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11945" level="2">77 Rules.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11946" level="2">78 Grants, and expenses of the Minister.</tocItem><tocItem href="#section-11947" level="2">79 Transitional provision.</tocItem></toc></preamble><body><section id="section-19063"><num/><heading>SECTION  THE CHILDREN AND YOUNG PERSONS (APPROVED INSTITUTIONS) REGULATIONS</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:table width="100%"><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%"><xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>L.N.268/1965.<xhtml:br/>Citation. 
  </xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="85%"><xhtml:b>THE CHILDREN AND YOUNG PERSONS (APPROVED INSTITUTIONS) REGULATIONS</xhtml:b><xhtml:p>1. These Regulations may be cited as the Children and Young Persons (Approved Institutions) Regulations.</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%">
    Interpretation.<xhtml:br/></xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="85%">
    2. In these Regulations, "administering authority" means the appointed local authority or the managing committee or governing body of any approved Voluntary society or approved voluntary institution, or children's home. 
  </xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%">
    General<xhtml:br/>principles of<xhtml:br/>administration.<xhtml:br/></xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="85%">
    3. It shall be the duty of the administering authority to make the necessary arrangements for every institution or children's home for which it is responsible to ensure that the affairs of the institution or children s home are conducted in a proper manner and on principles calculated to secure the well-being of the children. 
  </xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%">
    Visits by<xhtml:br/>administering<xhtml:br/>authority.<xhtml:br/></xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="85%">
    4. (1) Where the administering authority is not itself carrying on the day-to-day management of the institution or children's home it shall make arrangements for the institution or children's home to be visited at least once in every month by an authorized person who shall satisfy himself that the institution or children's home is conducted in the best possible interest and well-being of the children and shall furnish a report as to his findings of his visit to the administering authority, and shall enter in the record book referred to in paragraph 3 of the Schedule to these Regulations his name and the date of his visit. 
   <xhtml:p>(2) Where the administering authority is an appointed local authority or an approved society, it shall be secured by arrangement that the person visiting is a member of the appropriate welfare committee of the appointed local authority or a member of a subcommittee established by that committee or such officer or one of such officers of the appointed local authority or approved society.</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%">
    Person in charge<xhtml:br/>of institution or children's home. 
   <xhtml:p/></xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="85%">
    5. (1) The administering authority shall appoint a person to be in charge of the institution or children's home, as the case may be: 
   <xhtml:p>Provided that, where a person is in charge of the institution or children's home immediately before these Regulations come into force, that person shall be deemed to have been appointed to be in charge of the home under this paragraph.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) The person in charge of the institution shall compile the records specified in the Schedule to these Regulations and shall keep them available at all times for inspection by any person visiting the home under regulation 4 of these Regulations or by any inspector appointed under section 54 of the Act.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) The person in charge of ^the institution or children's home shall be responsible for the custody of the medical record of each child and shall at all times keep them available for inspection by a medical practitioner or any Inspector appointed under the Act or any person specifically authorized by the administering authority in that behalf.</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%">
    Worship. 
  </xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="85%">
    6. The administering authority shall secure that each child shall be given opportunity to attend such religious services or religious institutions according to his religious persuasion. 
  </xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%">
    Medical care.<xhtml:br/></xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="85%">
    7.<xhtml:b/>(1) The administering authority shall appoint a medical officer for the institution or children's home, as the case may be, for which it is responsible. 
   <xhtml:p>(2) The duties of the medical officer shall include - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) the general supervision of the health of children (including their dental health);</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(h) the general supervision of the hygienic condition of the institution or children's home;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) the carrying out of any medical examinations required under these Regulations; and</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(d) the supervision, compilation and maintenance of medical records of the children accommodated in the institution or children's home.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) Notwithstanding anything contained in this regulation the administering authority may at its discretion appoint more than one medical officer and may distribute duties specified in paragraph 2 of this regulation.</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%">
    Notification of death, serious illness or<xhtml:br/>accident.<xhtml:br/></xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="85%">
    8<xhtml:b>.</xhtml:b>(1) Where the administering authority is an appointed local authority or approved society, and in the case of an institution or children's home the person in charge shall forthwith notify the chief inspector of children of - 
   <xhtml:p>(a) the death of any child in the institution or children's home, the cause thereof and the relevant circumstances pertaining thereto;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) the relevant circumstances, in so far as they can by reasonable inquiry be ascertained, of the death of any child formerly in the institution or children's home who dies within two months of ceasing to be in the institution or children's home, if known to the appointed local authority or approved society or the person in charge of the institution or children's home as the case may be; and</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) any outbreak of any infectious or contagious disease among the children under five years of age in the institution or children's home which the medical officer notifies to the person in charge of the institution or children's home to be sufficiently serious.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) Where the administering authority is an appointed local authority or approved society, and in case of an institution or children's home, the person in charge of such institution or children's home shall forthwith notify to the parent or guardian of the child or such other person or body for the time being responsible for the child - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) of the death of any child in the institution or children's home, the cause thereof and the relevant circumstances pertaining thereto; and</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) of any accident to any child in the institution or children's home or illness from which such a child suffers which in the opinion of the medical officer as notified to the person in charge of the institution or children's home is sufficiently serious.</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%">
    Consultation<xhtml:br/>with fire<xhtml:br/>authority, and fin drill.<xhtml:br/></xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="85%">
    9. (1) The administering authority shall consult the fire authority of the area in which the institution or children's home is situated on fire precautions in the institution or children's home. 
   <xhtml:p>(2) The administering authority shall make arrangements to secure by means of fire drill and practices that the staff of the institution or children's home, and so far as practicable the children themselves, are well versed in the procedure of saving life in case of fire.</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%">
    Notification of outbreak of fire.<xhtml:br/></xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="85%">
    10. The administering authority shall notify the chief inspector of children forthwith of any outbreak of fire in the institution or children's home necessitating the removal of any children from the institution or children's home, or such part thereof in which the fire breaks out. 
  </xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%">
    Punishment. 
  </xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="85%">
    11. (1) No corporal punishment shall be administered by any person except the person in charge of the institution or children's home or, in the event of his illness or absence, a person deputed by him for that purpose. 
   <xhtml:p>(2) No corporal punishment shall be administered to any child under seven years of age except by smacking his hands with the bare hand of the person administering punishment.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) No corporal punishment shall be administered to girls who have attained the age of seven years, or boys who have attained the age of seventeen years.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) Corporal punishment must be inflicted on the buttocks with a cane or smooth light switch and in no event shall exceed six strokes.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(5) No corporal punishment shall be administered to any child known to be suffering from any physical or mental disability without the prior sanction of a medical officer.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(6) Corporal punishment must not be administered in the presence of other children and may only be inflicted after fuU inquiry.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(7) A record of every case of corporal punishment shall be entered in the punishment book referred to in paragraph 7 of the Schedule to these Regulations.</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%">
    Limitation as to number of children to be accommodated.<xhtml:br/></xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="85%">
    12. The chief inspector of children may give directions to the administering authority limiting the number of children who may at any one time be accommodated in the institution or children's home: 
   <xhtml:p>Provided that no institution or children's home shall be prevented by virtue of this regulation from giving care and shelter to a child where no alternative is available.</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%">
    Visiting by<xhtml:br/>parents or<xhtml:br/>guardians.<xhtml:br/></xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="85%">
    13. The administering authority shall in consultation with the chief inspector of children grant reasonable access to the parents and guardians of children in the institution or children's home to visit and communicate with the children. 
  </xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%">
    Change of<xhtml:br/>persons in<xhtml:br/>charge. 
   <xhtml:p/></xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="85%">
    14. The administering authority shall forthwith give notice to the chief inspector of children when a person in charge of an institution or children's home ceases to hold office as such and thereafter notify as soon as expedient to the chief inspector of children the name and particulars of the person appointed in his place. 
  </xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%">
    Application.<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>Cap.64. 
  </xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="85%">
    15. These Regulations shall apply to institutions and children's homes for which approved societies or approved voluntary institutions or appointed-local authorities are responsible, except - 
   <xhtml:p>(a) juvenile remand homes and approved schools; and</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) institutions established under the Probation of Offenders Act.</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr></xhtml:table><xhtml:p>&#160;</xhtml:p><xhtml:table width="100%"><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%"/><xhtml:td width="85%"><xhtml:table width="100%"><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="71%"><xhtml:p>SCHEDULE</xhtml:p></xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="29%"><xhtml:p>(rr.4(1), 5 and 11)</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr></xhtml:table><xhtml:p>RECORDS</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>1. A register in which shall be entered the date of admission and the date of discharge of every child accommodated in the institution or children's home.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>2. In institutions or children's homes accommodating more than twenty children, a register indicating every day child present in the institution or children's home on that day.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>3. A record book in which shall be recorded events of importance connected with the institution or children's home.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>4. A record of every fire practice or drill conducted in the institution or children's home.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>5. Records of the food provided for the children accommodated in the institution or children's home in sufficient detail to enable any person inspecting the records to judge whether the dietary is satisfactory.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>6 Where consultation under regulation 9 has taken place a record of fire Precautions agreed upon by the administering authority and the fire authority after such consultation as being practicable and suitable to the circumstances of the institution or children's home</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>7. A punishment book in which shall be entered a record of all corporal punishment administered.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>8. A case history file of each inmate.</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr></xhtml:table></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-19064"><num/><heading>SECTION  THE CHILDREN AND YOUNG PERSONS (REGISTRATION) REGULATIONS</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:table width="100%"><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%"><xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>L.N.289/1965 
  </xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="85%"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>THE CHILDREN AND YOUNG PERSONS (REGISTRATION) REGULATIONS<xhtml:br/></xhtml:b></xhtml:p><xhtml:p>1.These Regulations may be cited as the Children and Young Persons (Registration) Regulations.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>2.(1) The managers of any approved school, voluntary institution, children's home, nursery, boarding-out establishment, holiday, home ,place of safety and other similar institution, not being a school, hospital, convalescent home or similar institution where children are received and cared for, for reward or otherwise, shall register same by making application in the appropriate form provided by these Regulations.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) Any person who contravenes this regulation shall be guilty of an offence and liable to a fine not exceeding two thousand shillings</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>3. Every application for the registration of an approved school under section 37 (1) of the Act shall be made in the form in the First Schedule to these Regulations.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>4. Every application for the registration of an appointed local authority under section 58 (1)of the Act, or approved society under section 63 (1) of the Act, shall be submitted in the appropriate form in the Second Schedule to these Regulations.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>5. Every application for the registration of an approved voluntary institution under section 63 (1) of the Act. or children's home under the Second Schedule to the Act, shall be submitted in the form in the Third Schedule to these Regulations.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>6. Every application for "e registration of institutions, children's homes, nurseries, boarding-out establishments. holiday homes, places of safety or other similar institutions under section 76 (e) of the Act, in the area of any local authority, shall be submitted in the form in the Fourth Schedule to these Regulations.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>7.Every application for approval and gazetting of children's officers or approved officers shall be submitted in the form in the Fifth Schedule to these Regulations</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>8.A certificate of an approved school shall be in the form in the Sixth Schedule to these Regulations.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>9. A certificate of an appointed local authority, or an approved society, an approved institution or children's home, shall be in the appropriate form in the Seventh Schedule to these Regulations.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>10. A certificate of registration of institutions, children's homes nurseries, boarding-out establishments, holiday homes and places of safety in the area of any local authority shall be in the form in the Eighth Schedule to these Regulations.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>11.A warrant of authority shall be in the form in the Ninth Schedule to these Regulations.</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr></xhtml:table><xhtml:p>&#160;</xhtml:p><xhtml:table width="100%"><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%"/><xhtml:td width="85%"><xhtml:table width="100%"><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="87%"><xhtml:p>SECOND SCHEDULE</xhtml:p></xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="13%"><xhtml:p>(r. 4)</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr></xhtml:table><xhtml:p>FORM A</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>FORM OF APPLICATION FOR REGISTRATION OF AN APPOINTED<xhtml:br/>LOCAL AUTHORITY OR AUTHORITIES UNDER SECTION 58 (1) OF THE ACT</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>1. Name of Council or Councils.......................................................................<xhtml:br/>.......................................................................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>2. Postal address or addresses .......................................................................<xhtml:br/>.......................................................................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>3. Current office bearers - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>(a)</xhtml:i>President/Chairman/Mayor ...........................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>(b)</xhtml:i>Clerk/Executive Officer .................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>4. Number of nurseries - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>(a)</xhtml:i>Established .....................................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>(b)</xhtml:i>Proposed........................................................................................<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>5. Number of homes - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) Established......................................................................................<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>(b) Proposed ........................................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>6. Number of children's officers - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) Employed ........................................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) To be employed ...............................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>I hereby make application for the registration of the above- mentioned Council or Councils under section 58 (1) of the Children and Young Persons Act as an Appointed Local Authority.<xhtml:br/></xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Name ................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Designation .........................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Signature ...........................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Full postal address ..............................................<xhtml:br/>...........................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Date .........................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p> - - - - </xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%"/><xhtml:td width="85%">
    FORM B 
   <xhtml:p>FORM OF APPLICATION FOR REGISTRATION OF AN APPROVED<xhtml:br/>SOCIETY UNDER SECTION 63 (1) OF THE ACT</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>1. Name ..........................................................................................................<xhtml:br/>.....................................................................................................................<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>2. Postal address .............................................................................................<xhtml:br/>.....................................................................................................................<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>3. Societies Act Registration No. ..................... Date .....................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>4. Current office bearers - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) President/Chairman ...................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) Secretary ...................................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) Treasurer .....................................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(d) Executive Officer/Manager ....................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>5. Number of established branches ..................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>6. Number of established institutions/homes ......................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>7. Number of approved officers employed ........................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>To be employed ..........................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>I hereby make application for the registration of the above-mentioned Society as an Approved Society under section 63 (1) of the Children and Young Persons Act.<xhtml:br/></xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Name ...........................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Designation ...................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Signature .......................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Full postal address .........................................<xhtml:br/>.........................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Date ...................................<xhtml:br/></xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr></xhtml:table><xhtml:p>&#160;</xhtml:p><xhtml:table width="100%"><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%"/><xhtml:td width="85%"><xhtml:p>THIRD SCHEDULE (r.5)</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>FORM OF APPLICATION FOR REGISTRATION OF AN APPROVED<xhtml:br/>VOLUNTARY INSTITUTION OR CHILDREN'S HOME UNDER SECTION 63 (1) AND THE SECOND SCHEDULE<xhtml:br/>TO THE ACT<xhtml:br/></xhtml:p><xhtml:p>1. Full postal address of the voluntary institution or children's home<xhtml:br/>......................................................................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>2. Full name and address of the person in charge of the voluntary institution or children's home ...............................................................................................<xhtml:br/>......................................................................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>3. Full name and address of the Chairman of the organization<xhtml:br/>......................................................................................................................<xhtml:br/>4. Full name and address of the Secretary of the organization<xhtml:br/>.....................................................................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>5. Date on which the voluntary institution or children's home was opened, or on which it is intended to be opened, for the reception of children and young persons ............................................................................................................<xhtml:br/>.....................................................................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>6 Number of children or young persons (that is, persons under the age of 18) of each sex and age limits of the children or young persons for whom accommodation is, or is intended to be, provided in the voluntary institution or children's home ............................................................................................<xhtml:br/>.....................................................................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>7 Number of persons, other than staff, aged 18 or over for whom accommodation is, or is intended to be, provided in the voluntary institution or children's home ................................................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>8. The voluntary institution or children's home is/will be - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>*(a) supported wholly or partly by voluntary contributions;<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>*(b) a voluntary institution or children's home not being a school within the meaning of the Education Act (Cap. 211) which is not supported wholly or partly by voluntary contributions but is supported wholly or partly by endowments.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>I hereby make application for the registration of the above-mentioned voluntary institution or children's home under section 63 (1) of the Children and Young Persons Act.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:br/>Name ..........................................................................<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>Designation ..................................................................<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>Signature .....................................................................<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>Full postal address........................................................<xhtml:br/>.....................................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Date...................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>*Delete whichever is inapplicable.</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr></xhtml:table><xhtml:p>&#160;</xhtml:p><xhtml:table width="100%"><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%"/><xhtml:td width="85%"><xhtml:table width="100%"><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="85%"><xhtml:p>FOURTH SCHEDULE</xhtml:p></xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="15%"><xhtml:p>(r.6)</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr></xhtml:table><xhtml:br/>FORM OF APPLICATION FOR REGISTRATION OF INSTITUTIONS, CHILDREN'S HOMES, NURSERIES, BOARDING-OUT ESTABLISHMENTS, HOLIDAY HOMES, PLACES OF SAFETY AND SIMILAR INSTITUTIONS ESTABLISHED BY COUNCILS OR NON-REGISTERED BODIES IN THE AREA OF ANY LOCAL AUTHORITY UNDER SECTION 76 (e) OF THE ACT 
   <xhtml:p>1. Name of Council .......................................................................<xhtml:br/>being or about to be registered as Appointed Local Authority within the meaning of section 58 (1) of the Children and Young Persons Act, hereby applies to register or have registered the undermentioned Institution under section 76 (e) of the Act.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>2. Name of Institution ....................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>3. Purpose of Institution ..................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>4. Location ....................................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>5. Full postal address of Institution ...................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>6. Name of officer-in-charge ...........................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>7. Capacity: Boys .......... Girls ................... Total ..........................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>8. Presently accommodated: Boys ...... Girls ...... Total ......</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>9. Nature of accommodation provided: (temporary, semi-permanent,<xhtml:br/>permanent) ....................................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>10. Other facilities provided ............................................................<xhtml:br/>.......................................................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>11. Equipment installed ...................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>To be installed .....................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>12. Number of staff employed: Qualified ......... Unqualified .............<xhtml:br/>to be employed: Qualified ........ Unqualified ......</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>13. Housing for staff ........................................................................<xhtml:br/>........................................................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>14. Name ........................................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Designation ..............................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Signature ................................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>15. Full postal address ...................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Date ...........................................</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr></xhtml:table><xhtml:p>&#160;</xhtml:p><xhtml:table width="100%"><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%"/><xhtml:td width="85%"><xhtml:table width="100%"><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="85%"><xhtml:p>FIFTH SCHEDULE</xhtml:p></xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="15%"><xhtml:p>(r.7)</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr></xhtml:table><xhtml:br/>FORM A 
   <xhtml:p>FORM OF APPLICATION FOR APPOINTMENT OF A CHILDREN'S OFFICER</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>1. Name of Council or Councils........................................................<xhtml:br/>an appointed local authority within the meaning of section 58 (1) of the Children and Young Persons Act desires to appoint or have appointed the undermentioned person to be a Children's Officer within the meaning of section 54 (2) of the Act.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>2. Name of officer .........................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>3. Age ............................................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>4. Nationality and tribe ....................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>5. Present occupation .....................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>6. General education attained...........................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>7. Professional or technical training..................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>8. Single, married or widowed........................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>9. Number of children: Boys ................. Girls ...................... Total</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>10. Religion (if any) and whether practised........................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>11. Vernacular ...............................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>12. Other languages spoken (give details).......................................<xhtml:br/>......................................................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>13. Previous convictions, if any (give details of offences) .................<xhtml:br/>......................................................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>14. Any other relevant information...................................................<xhtml:br/>......................................................................................................<xhtml:br/>15. Name ...................................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Designation ............................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Signature ..............................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>16. Full postal address ..................................................................<xhtml:br/>.....................................................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Date.........................................<xhtml:br/></xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%"/><xhtml:td width="85%"><xhtml:br/>FORM B<xhtml:br/>FORM OF APPLICATION FOR APPOINTMENT OF APPROVED OFFICERS 
   <xhtml:p>1. Name of Society .......................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>a society approved within the meaning of section 63 (1) of the Children and Young Persons Act desires to appoint, or have appointed, the undermentioned person to be an Approved Officer<xhtml:br/>within the meaning of section 64 (1) of the Act.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>2. Name of officer .........................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>3. Age ..........................................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>4. Nationality and tribe ..................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>5. Present occupation ...................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>6. General education attained .......................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>7. Professional or technical training ..............................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>8. Single, married or widowed ....................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>9. Number of children: Boys ...... Girls .............. Total ................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>10. Religion (if any) and whether practised ..................................<xhtml:br/>....................................................................................................<xhtml:br/>11. Vernacular ............................................................................<xhtml:br/>12. Other languages spoken (give details) .....................................<xhtml:br/>.......................................................................................................<xhtml:br/>13. Previous convictions, if any (give details of offences) ................<xhtml:br/>.....................................................................................................<xhtml:br/>14. Any other relevant information ................................................<xhtml:br/>......................................................................................................<xhtml:br/>15. Name ...................................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Designation ............................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Signature ..............................................................................<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>16. Full portal address ....................................................................<xhtml:br/>......................................................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Date .............................</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr></xhtml:table><xhtml:p>&#160;</xhtml:p><xhtml:table width="100%"><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%"/><xhtml:td width="85%">
    SIXTH SCHEDULE (r. 8) 
   <xhtml:p>CERTIFICATE OF REGISTRATION OF AN APPROVED SCHOOL</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>THIS IS TO CERTIFY THAT - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Name of School .............................................................................<xhtml:br/>......................................................................................................<xhtml:br/>Managed by ...................................................................................<xhtml:br/>......................................................................................................<xhtml:br/>Postal address ..............................................................................<xhtml:br/>......................................................................................................<xhtml:br/>being a registered school under the Education Act (Cap. 211), is hereby declared to be an approved school and registered under section 37 (1) of the Children and Young Persons Act.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Registration Number ...................................................................<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>Gazette Notice Number ................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Date .....................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Dated this ........................... day of ................................. 19....</xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>Minister for Home Affairs.</xhtml:i></xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr></xhtml:table><xhtml:p>&#160;</xhtml:p><xhtml:table width="100%"><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%"/><xhtml:td width="85%">
    SEVENTH SCHEDULE (r. 9)<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>FORM A 
   <xhtml:p>CERTIFICATE OF AN APPOINTED LOCAL AUTHORITY<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>THIS IS TO CERTIFY THAT - <xhtml:br/>Name of Council or Councils .........................................................<xhtml:br/>.....................................................................................................<xhtml:br/>Postal address or addresses .........<xhtml:br/>.....................................................................................................<xhtml:br/>being a local authority or local authorities is/are hereby appointed to<xhtml:br/>exercise the aforesaid functions of an appointed local authority under<xhtml:br/>section 58 (1) of the Children and Young Persons Act.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Dated this .......................... day of ................................, 19....<xhtml:br/></xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>Minister for Home Affairs.</xhtml:i></xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="15%"/><xhtml:td width="85%">
    SEVENTH SCHEDULE (r. 9) 
   <xhtml:p>FORM B</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>CERTIFICATE OF REGISTRATION OF AN APPROVED SOCIETY, INSTITUTION OR CHILDREN'S HOME<xhtml:br/></xhtml:p><xhtml:p>THIS IS TO CERTIFY THAT - .<xhtml:br/>Name of Society or Institution .......................................................<xhtml:br/>.......................................................................................................<xhtml:br/>of [<xhtml:i>registered office or location</xhtml:i>] ..................................................<xhtml:br/>.......................................................................................................<xhtml:br/>Postal address ................................................................................<xhtml:br/>.......................................................................................................<xhtml:br/>being a voluntary society/institution/children's home is hereby registered under section 63 (1) of the Children and Young Persons Act.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Registration Number .............................. Date ...............................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Dated this ............................... day of .............................., 19......</xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:i>Minister for Home Affairs.</xhtml:i></xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr><xhtml:p>&#160;</xhtml:p></xhtml:table><xhtml:table width="100%"><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="14%"/><xhtml:td width="86%"><xhtml:table width="100%"><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="87%"><xhtml:p>EIGHTH SCHEDULE</xhtml:p></xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="13%">
       (r. 10) 
     </xhtml:td></xhtml:tr></xhtml:table><xhtml:p>CERTIFICATE OF REGISTRATION OF INSTITUTIONS, CHILDREN'S HOMES, NURSERIES, BOARDING-OUT ESTABLISHMENTS, HOLIDAY HOMES, PLACES OF SAFETY AND SIMILAR INSTITUTIONS ESTABLISHED BY<xhtml:br/>COUNCILS OR NON-REGISTERED BODIES IN THE AREAS OF LOCAL AUTHORITIES UNDER SECTION 76 (e) OF THE ACT</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>THIS IS TO CERTIFY THAT - <xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>Name of Institution ..........................................................................<xhtml:br/>Location .........................................................................................<xhtml:br/>Established by .................................................................................<xhtml:br/>Managed by [<xhtml:i>local authority</xhtml:i>] .......................................................<xhtml:br/>being [<xhtml:i>type of services rendered</xhtml:i>] ....................................................<xhtml:br/><xhtml:br/>is HEREBY REGISTERED under section 76 (e) of the Children and Young Persons Act.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Registration Number .................................. Date ............................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Dated this .................................... day of ......................, 19....</xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:br/><xhtml:i>Minister for Home Affairs.</xhtml:i></xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr></xhtml:table><xhtml:p>&#160;</xhtml:p><xhtml:table width="100%"><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="14%"/><xhtml:td width="86%"><xhtml:table width="100%"><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="50%"><xhtml:p>NINTH SCHEDULE</xhtml:p></xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="50%"><xhtml:p>(r. 11)</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr></xhtml:table><xhtml:p>WARRANT OF AUTHORITY</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>The bearer .......................................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>being a duly appointed (office) ..........................................................<xhtml:br/>under sections 54 (1), (2) or 64 (1) of the Children and Young Persons Act is hereby duly authorized to exercise the powers conferred by section 56 of the said Act.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Dated this ............................. day of .........................., 19....</xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:br/><xhtml:i>Minister for Home Affairs.</xhtml:i><xhtml:br/></xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr></xhtml:table></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-19065"><num/><heading>SECTION  THE CHILDREN AND YOUNG PERSONS (BOARDING-OUT) REGULATIONS</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:table width="100%"><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="14%">
    L.N229/1966.<xhtml:br/></xhtml:td><xhtml:td width="86%"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>THE CHILDREN AND YOUNG PERSONS (BOARDING-OUT) REGULATIONS</xhtml:b></xhtml:p><xhtml:p>1. These Regulations may be cited as the Children and Young Persons (Boarding-Out) Regulations.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>2. In these Regulations, except where the context otherwise requires - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"boarding-out means the placing of a foster child with a foster parent;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"foster child" means ; child, juvenile or young person committed to the care of an appointed local authority or approved society as a fit person under the provisions of the Act;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"foster parent "means persons or a person with whom a foster child is for the time being or is proposed to be boarded-out; and</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"visitor" means the chief inspector or inspectors of children and children's officers appointed under section 54 (1) of the Act, or any person who is appointed by an appointed local authority' or approved society for the purpose of assisting the appointed local authority or approved society in the performance of its functions under these Regulations and in particular, of exercising supervision over foster children and arranging for boarding them out.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>3. An appointed local authority or approved society shall, except as hereinafter provided, make arrangements for every person committed to its care to be boarded-out as soon as possible with a suitable foster parent and if within three months of the committal of any person to its care he has not been boarded-out, the appointed local authority or approved society shall report forthwith to the chief inspector of children the reasons therefor and apply for his consent to the making of alternative arrangements.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>4. A foster child shall not be boarded-out or be allowed to remain boarded-out - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) with a person who has at any time been convicted of an offence which renders him unfit to be a foster parent, or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) in any environment which is likely to be detrimental to the child.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>5. Before a foster child is boarded-out, the appointed local authority or approved society shall arrange for him to be examined by a medical practitioner and shall obtain from the medical practitioner a certificate as to his physical health and mental condition and his suitability for boarding-out.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>6. (1) An appointed local authority or approved society shall require a foster parent to sign in triplicate an agreement in respect of a foster child boarded-out with him in the form in the Schedule to these Regulations or in a form to the like effect.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) The said agreement shall be kept by the appointed local authority or approved society as the case may be, and a copy thereof shall be left with the foster parent and a further copy shall be sent to the chief inspector of children.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>7. A foster child shall not be boarded-out, or be allowed to remain boarded-out, with a foster parent who is a party to any contract conferring benefit on him under n insurance policy in the event of the illness or death of the child.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>8. An appointed local authority or approved society shall, where possible, board-out a foster child with a foster parent who either is of the same religious persuasion as the foster child or who gives undertaking that he will be brought up in that religious persuasion.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>9. No foster child shall be boarded-out unless the proposed foster parent and the home where .the foster child will live have been visited by a visitor who, being in possession of full information about the child, has made due inquiry and furnished a report in writing to the appointed local authority or the approved society stating in particular whether - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) the proposed foster parent is of good reputation;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) he is in a position to take proper care of the child:</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) the sleeping and living accommodation and other domestic conditions are satisfactory; and</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(d) the home is likely to suit the particular needs of the foster child.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>10. (1) The appointed local authority or approved society shall ensure that a visitor sees the foster child and visits the home of the foster parent - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) within one month of his being placed in the home and there- after as often as may be necessary, not being less than once in every two months;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) if a foster parent changes his address, within one month of the receipt by the local authority or approved society of notice of the new address:</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Provided that, where a foster child is over nine years of age and has been continuously for not less than two years in the same foster home, which is providing suitably for his needs, the appointed local authority or approved society may decide to reduce the number of periodical visits to not less than one in every three months.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) The appointed local authority or approved society shall require the visitor to make a report after every visit to a foster child as to the condition of the home (including the sleeping and living accommodation) and any complaints made by or concerning the foster child and whether the home appears to him to be suitable for the foster child.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>11. (1) The appointed local authority or approved society may remove a foster child from his foster home if he is no longer suitably placed in that home. (2) Where conditions in the home are found to be seriously detrimental to the health, safety or morals of a foster child, the visitor shall have the power to withdraw the child immediately from the home.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>12. (1) The appointed local authority or approved society shall ensure that a foster child is examined by a medical practitioner within one month after being boarded-out and thereafter at least once every year, and arrangements shall be made by the appointed local authority or approved society to obtain from the medical practitioner after each such examination a written report on the physical health and mental condition of the foster child.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) An appointed local authority or approved society shall provide adequate facilities for a foster child who is boarded-out to receive medical and dental attention as required.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) The appointed local authority or approved society shall require a foster parent to report to it all cases of serious illness or accident to a foster child and to summon a medical practitioner immediately in all such cases.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>13. In the event of the death of a foster child the appointed local authority or approved society shall arrange for a decent and proper burial of the foster child, and a report to that effect shall be submitted forthwith to the chief inspector of children.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>14. (1) In the case of a foster child who is above school age, the appointed local authority or approved society shall endeavour to make arrangements in consultation with the foster parent and the foster child with a view to placing him in suitable employment or training, and where the child cannot conveniently continue to be boarded-out with the foster parent, the appointed local authority or approved society shall arrange for him lo reside in ;i suitable hostel or lodging, except where he is placed in residential employment or training.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(.2) Where a foster child has been placed in employment or training, the appointed local authority or approved society shall arrange that a visitor shall visit him within one month of his taking up employment or training and thereafter, as often as may be necessary, not being less than once in every two months.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>15. An appointed local authority or approved society may and when required by the Minister shall, appoint an officer to act as a visitor for the purpose of assisting the appointed local authority or approved society in the performance of their functions under these Regulations and, in particular, of visiting foster children.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>16. Before an appointed local authority boards-out a foster child t a home outside the appointed local authority's area, the appointed local authority shall notify to the appointed local authority in whose area the home is situated - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) the address of the proposed home at which the foster child will boarded-out; and</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) whether or not they themselves will exercise supervision over the foster child.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>17. (1) An appointed local authority or approved society shall keep a written record containing the particulars specified in paragraphs (2) and (3) of this regulation of all foster children received into their care and of any with respect to whom they have undertaken super- vision under regulation 16 of the e Regulations, and shall forward a copy of the record to the chief inspector of children.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) The particulars to be entered in the case of every such foster child are his name, sex, date of birth or age, his religious persuasion the name and address of the authority by whom he is boarded-out, the dates on which boarding-out on each occasion begins and ceases and the reason why it ceases.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) There shall also be so entered - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) in the case of a foster child in respect of whom arrangements have been made under regulation 16 of these Regulations, a note of those arrangements;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) in the case of a foster child in me care of an appointed local authority boarded-out by an approved society, the name of e case authority; and</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) in the case of a foster child boarded-out by an approved society in relation to whom the appointed local authority are performing supervisory duties, a note of that fact.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) An appointed local authority or approved society who actually exercises supervision over a foster child and the foster parent, shall keep a written record as to the date of every visit to the foster child and the foster parent.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(5) Every written record kept under this regulation shall be preserved for at least five years after every foster child particulars about whom are entered therein has or would have attained the age of eighteen years, and shall be open to inspection at all reasonable times by any person duly authorized in that behalf by the Minister</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>18. (1) An appointed local authority or approved society to whose care a foster child has been committed, shall arrange for a review by an appropriate committee of the welfare, conduct, health ; progress of every child who is boarded-out by them from the dale on which the child was first committed to its care and shall further arrange for reviews at intervals of not more than once every six months.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) A note of the committee's consideration shall be entered in the record of each foster child.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>9. (1) An appointed local authority or approved society shall furnish to the Minister or to any of his officers appointed under section 54 (1) of the Act, when so required, information regarding foster children committed to its care or under its supervision.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) Any foster child may 'be visited at any time by an inspector of children or a children's officer and records of an appointed local authority or approved society pertaining to the foster child shall be made available to them for inspection.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>20. Where in the opinion of an appointed local authority or approved society it is desirable, having regard to the special circum- stances of a case, that the provisions of one or more of these Regulations should not apply, the Minister may, on application being made in that behalf, permit the appointed local authority or approved society to make different arrangements.</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr></xhtml:table><xhtml:p>&#160;</xhtml:p><xhtml:table width="100%"><xhtml:tr><xhtml:td width="14%"/><xhtml:td width="86%"><xhtml:p>SCHEDULE (r.6(1))<xhtml:br/></xhtml:p><xhtml:p>AGREEMENT OF FOSTER PARENT</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>1. We/I ............................................... of .................................... do<xhtml:br/>hereby agree with the .............. of ....................................................<xhtml:br/>that - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) we/I will receive ............................................................ (name of<xhtml:br/>foster child) into our/my home and feed, clothe and look after him and bring him up as carefully and kindly as we/I would a child of our/my own;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) we/I will help him to become a good citizen, send him to school/employment and to his church (chapel) and arrange for recreation suited to his age;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) we/I will look after his health and consult the doctor whenever he is ill, and in the event of his serious illness or accident we/I will also notify the appointed local authority approved society immediately;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(d) well will provide for the cleaning, mending and replacement of his clothing and its proper care;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(e) we/I will at all times permit any persons authorized by the chief inspector of children or by the appointed local authority/approved society to see the child, and his home and clothing, and we/I will attend to the advice of any such persons;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(f) we/I will allow him to be removed from our/my home when required by any persons so authorized, and</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(g) we/I will notify the appointed local authority/approved society within two weeks if we/I change our/my address.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>2.We /I make this agreement with the appointed local authority/approved society in consideration of our/ my receiving the sum of Sh. ........................per month. We / I acknowledge having received ...............................................(name of foster child) into our/my house on.......................................and certify that he brought with him the following personal possessions-</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) Clothing.........................................................................................<xhtml:br/>...........................................................................................................<xhtml:br/>(b) Cash...............................................................................................<xhtml:br/>(c) Other articles.................................................................................<xhtml:br/>............................................................................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:br/>Signature of foster parent..........................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Address.........................................................<xhtml:br/>............................................................</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Date......................................</xhtml:p></xhtml:td></xhtml:tr></xhtml:table></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11869"><num>1</num><heading>SECTION 1 Short title</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>1.</xhtml:b>This Act may be cited as the Children and Young Persons Act.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11870"><num>2</num><heading>SECTION 2 Interpretation.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>2.</xhtml:b>In this Act, except where the context otherwise interpretation. requires - 
<xhtml:p>"age", where actual age is not known, means apparent age;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"appointed local authority" has the meaning assigned to that expression by section 58 of this Act;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"approved officer" means a person appointed under section 64 of this Act to be an approved officer;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"approved school" means a school approved under section 37 or established under section, 38 of this Act;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"approved society" means a society /approved by the Minister under section 63 of this Act;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"approved voluntary institution" means a voluntary institution approved under section 63 of this Act;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"authorized officer" means a police officer, administration police officer, administrative officer, inspector of children, children's officer and approved officer, and a chief or sub chief appointed under the Chief's Authority Act;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>chief inspector of children" means the person appointed as such under section 54 of this Act;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"child" means a person under the age of fourteen years;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"children's officer" means a person appointed to be a children's officer under section 54 of this Act;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"guardian", in relation to a person under eighteen years of age, includes anyone who, in the opinion of the court, has charge or control of that person;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p><xhtml:br/>"home" means, in respect of any person under eighteen years of age. the place where, in the opinion of the court having cognizance of any case relating to him or in which he is concerned, his parent or guardian permanently resides or if there is no parent or guardian living, his parent or guardian last permanently resided:</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Provided that - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(d) in the case of a parent or guardian having, or having had, more than one permanent place of residence such parent or guardian shall be presumed to be. or to have been, permanently resident at that place of his principal permanent residence;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(ii) where the court is unable to determine the home of any such person he shall be deemed for the purposes of this Act to have his home in the area of jurisdiction of the local authority in whose area he is found;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"inspector of children" means any person appointed to be an inspector of children under section 54 of this Act;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"juvenile" means a person who is of the age of fourteen years or more and is under the age of sixteen years:</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"juvenile court", without prejudice to the powers and Jurisdiction of the High Court, means a court constituted in accordance with section 3 of this Act; "Juvenile remand home" means a remand home established for the detention of persons under sixteen years of age or an institution agreed to be used as a juvenile remand home under section 36 of this Act;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"nursery" means any institution or place at which, for the time being, five or more children under the age of seven years are received and cared for regularly for reward;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"place of safety" means any mission, institution, hospital or other suitable place whether or not similar to the foregoing the occupier of which is willing to accept the temporary care of a child or Juvenile; and where no such place is available a Juvenile remand home or police station shall be deemed a place of safety for the purposes of this Act;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"voluntary institution" means a home or institution for the care of persons under eighteen years of age, whether for reward or not, supported wholly or partly by voluntary contributions or endowments, not being a school within the cap. 211. meaning of the Education Act;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>"young person" means a person who is of the age of sixteen years or more and is under the age of eighteen years.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11871"><num>3</num><heading>SECTION 3 Juvenile courts.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>3.</xhtml:b>(1) For the purpose of hearing all charges against persons under eighteen years of age, except in cases where they are charged jointly with any person or persons over the age of eighteen years, and for the purpose of exercising any other jurisdiction conferred on juvenile courts by or under this or any other written law, there shall be courts called juvenile courts constituted in accordance with the provisions of this section. 
<xhtml:p>(2) The Chief Justice may. by notice in the Gazette, in respect of any area appointed magistrate to be chairman or deputy chairman, and such number of other suitable persons as he may think fit. to constitute a panel of persons to try juvenile cases.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) The Chief Justice may from time to time, by notice in the Gazette, revise the composition of any panel by adding persons thereto or by removing persons therefrom or by substituting one person for another.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) Every juvenile court shall consist of either the chairman or the deputy chairman and a number of members of the panel in manner prescribed by rules made under section 77 of this Act. exercising jurisdiction within the area for which it is constituted, or of a magistrate sitting alone or m such other manner as may be so prescribed.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(5) Where in the course of any proceedings in a juvenile court it appears to the court that the person charged or to whom the proceedings relate is over eighteen years of age, or where in the course of any proceedings in any court other than a juvenile court it appears to the court that the person charged or to whom the proceedings relate is under eighteen years of age nothing in this section shall prevent the court if it thinks fit from proceeding with the hearing and determination of the case.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(6) Where any conviction or sentence made or passed by a court other than a juvenile court is appealed against or is brought before the High Court for confirmation or revision and it appears that the person convicted was at the time of the commission of the offence under eighteen years of age, the latter court shall have power to substitute for the conviction a finding of guilty in accordance with section 15 and to substitute for the sentence an order under section 17, of this Act.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11872"><num>4</num><heading>SECTION 4 Sitting of Juvenile courts.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>4.</xhtml:b>A juvenile court shall sit in a different building or room, or on different days, or at different times, from those in which sittings of courts other than juvenile courts are held and no person shall be present at any sitting of a juvenile court except - 
<xhtml:p>(a) members and officers of the court;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) parties to the case before the court, their advocates and witnesses and other persons directly concerned in the case;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) parents or guardians of any person brought before the court;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(d) bona fide representatives of newspapers or news agencies;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(e) such other persons as the court may specially authorize to be present.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11873"><num>5</num><heading>SECTION 5 Prohibition of publication</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>5.</xhtml:b>(1) No person shall publish the name or address of any person before a juvenile court, nor the name or address of any school which such person is or has been attending, nor any photograph of any such person, nor any matter likely to lead to the identification of such person, save with the permission of he court or in so far as is required by the provisions of this Act, 
<xhtml:p>(2) Any person who contravenes the provisions of this section shall be guilty of an offence and liable to a fine not exceeding one thousand shillings.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11874"><num>6</num><heading>SECTION 6 Prevention of persons under 16 associating with adult offenders.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>6.</xhtml:b>Arrangements shall be made for preventing persons under sixteen years of age while detained in a police station or while being conveyed to or from any court, or while waiting to attend in or leave any court, from associating with adults charged with or convicted of any offence other than an offence with which a person under sixteen years of age is jointly charged or convicted.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11875"><num>7</num><heading>SECTION 7 Children not allowed in court.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>7.</xhtml:b>No child except an infant in arms shall, unless required by the court, be present in any court during the hearing of any case or during any proceedings preliminary thereto save with the permission of the court.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11876"><num>8</num><heading>SECTION 8 Power to clear court.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>8.</xhtml:b>Where in any proceedings in relation to an offence against, or any conduct contrary to, decency or morality a person who, in the opinion of the court, is under eighteen years of age is called as a witness, the court may direct that all or any persons, not being members or officers of the court, or parties to the case or their advocates, or persons otherwise directly concerned in the case, shall be excluded from the court during the taking of the evidence of that witness.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11877"><num>9</num><heading>SECTION 9 Power to require attendance of parent.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>9.</xhtml:b>Where a person under eighteen years of age is charged i with any offence or is for any other reason brought before a court, his parent or guardian may in any case, and shall, if he can be found and resides within a reasonable distance, be required to attend at the court before which the case is heard or determined during all stages of the proceedings, unless the court is satisfied that it would be unreasonable to require his attendance.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11878"><num>10</num><heading>SECTION 10 Bail of persons under 18 arrested.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>10.</xhtml:b>Where a person apparently under the age of eighteen years is apprehended with or without warrant and cannot be brought forthwith before a court, the police or administrative officer to whom such person is brought shall inquire into the case, and may in any case, and unless - 
<xhtml:p>(a) the charge is one of murder or manslaughter or other grave crime; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) it is necessary in the interests of such person to remove him from association with any undesirable person; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) such officer has reason to believe that the release of such person would defeat the ends of justice, shall, release such person on a recognizance being entered into by his parent or guardian or other responsible person, with or without sureties, for such amount as will, in the opinion of such officer, secure the attendance of such person upon the hearing of the charge.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11879"><num>11</num><heading>SECTION 11 Remand in custody.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>11.</xhtml:b>(1) A court, on remanding any person under eighteen years of age in custody, shall order him to be detained for the period for which he is remanded - 
<xhtml:p>(a) if he is under sixteen years of age, in a juvenile remand home:</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Provided that if there is no juvenile remand home within a reasonable distance of the court, the court shall make such order as to his safe custody as it deems fit;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) if otherwise, in a remand prison:</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Provided that in the case of a juvenile the court may commit him to custody in a prison if it is satisfied that he is of so unruly a character that he cannot safely be remanded in custody to a juvenile remand home or that safely be remanded in custody to a juvenile remand home or that he is of so depraved a character that he is not a fit person to be so remanded.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) A remand to a juvenile remand home under this section may be varied and, in the case of a person who is over the age of fourteen years and who proves to be of so unruly a character that he cannot safely be detained in a juvenile r emand home or to be of so depraved a character that he is not a fit person to be so detained may be revoked by the court and the person remanded to prison.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11880"><num>12</num><heading>SECTION 12 Jurisdiction of juvenile courts.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>12.</xhtml:b>(1) Notwithstanding the provisions of Parts II and VII of the Criminal Procedure Code. a juvenile court may try a person under eighteen years of age for any offence other than manslaughter or an offence punishable by death except in cases where he is charged jointly with a person over eighteen years of age: 
<xhtml:p>Provided that a young person brought before a juvenile court for an offence which would, apart from the provisions of this section, be triable only by the High Court, other than manslaughter or an offence punishable by death, may nevertheless elect to be tried before the High Court.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) References to subordinate courts of any class, in the First Schedule to Criminal procedure code, include a juvenile court.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11881"><num>13</num><heading>SECTION 13 Power to remit cases to juvenile courts</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>13.</xhtml:b>(1) Subject to any rules or directions made or issued by the Chief Justice, where it appears to a court other than a juvenile court at any stage of the proceedings that a person charged before it with an offence other than murder manslaughter is under the age of eighteen years the court may and where within the area of a subordinate court's jurisdiction there is established a juvenile court having jurisdiction he subordinate court shall, remit the case to a Juvenile court: 
<xhtml:p>Provided that - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(i) a charge made jointly against, such person and a person who has attained the age of eighteen years shall be heard by a court other than a juvenile</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(ii) where a person under the age of eighteen years is charged with an offence the charge may be heard by a court other than a juvenile court if a person who has attained the age of eighteen years is charged at the same time with aiding, abetting, causing, procuring. allowing or permitting that offence;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(iii) nothing m this subsection shall be construed as preventing a court, if it considers in the circumstances (including the stage reached in the proceedings that it is proper so to do, from proceeding with the hearing and determination of the charge.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) Where in accordance with the Provisions of subsection a case is remitted to a juvenile court after a finding that the person charged is guilty of the offence  which the case has been remitted may deal with any in which it might have dealt with him if he had been tried and found guilty by that court</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) No appeal shall lie against an order of remission made under this section, but nothing in this section shall affect any right of appeal against the verdict or finding on which such an order is founded, and if a person ha been found guilty by the High Court and remitted to a juvenile court for an order under section 17 of this Act, he may appeal against such finding-to the Court of Appeal for East Africa</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) A court by which an order remitting a case to a Juvenile court is made under this section may give such directions as appear to be necessary with respect to the custody of the offender or for his release on bail or bond until he can be Brought before the Juvenile court, and shall cause to be transmitting to the clerk of the juvenile court a certificate out the nature of the offence and stating the stage reached in the case, and that the case has been remitted for the purpose of being dealt with under this section.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11882"><num>14</num><heading>SECTION 14 Considerations of welfare.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>14.</xhtml:b>Every court dealing with a person under eighteen years of age who is brought before it shall have regard to his welfare and shall, in a proper case, take steps for removing him from undesirable surroundings and for securing that proper provision be made for his maintenance, education and training.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11883"><num>15</num><heading>SECTION 15 Words &amp;quot;conviction&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;sentence&amp;quot; not to be used of children and young persons.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>15.</xhtml:b>The words "conviction" and "sentence" shall cease to be used m relation to persons under eighteen years of age dealt with by Juvenile courts, and any reference in any written law to a person convicted, a conviction or a sentence shall, in the case of such persons ,be construed as including a reference to a person found guilty of an offence, a finding of guilt or an order made upon such a finding, as the case may be</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11884"><num>16</num><heading>SECTION 16 Restrictions on punishments</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>16.</xhtml:b>(1) No child shall be ordered to imprisonment nor to R, detention m a detention camp. 
<xhtml:p>(2) No child under the age of ten years shall be ordered by a juvenile court to be sent to an approved school unless there is no fit person or approved voluntary institution who is willing to take care of him, or unless for some other good reason the court considers that he cannot suitably be dealt with otherwise.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) (a) No juvenile or young person shall be ordered to imprisonment unless the court is of the opinion that he cannot be suitably dealt with in any other way permitted by law and the court shall duly record such opinion and the reason therefor.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) Any order of imprisonment made by virtue of this subsection shall be subject to confirmation by the High Court, and the offender shall be detained as an unconvicted prisoner in a prison pending confirmation and may not elect to commence his term of imprisonment forthwith.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) A juvenile or young person ordered to imprisonment shall where practicable, be confined apart from, and shall not be allowed to associate with, adult prisoners during his term of imprisonment.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(5) Where a juvenile or young person is ordered to imprisonment, the warrant of committal shall clearly show that such person is a juvenile or young person, as the case</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11885"><num>17</num><heading>SECTION 17 Methods of dealing with offenders</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>17.</xhtml:b>Notwithstanding the provisions of any other law offenders, and subject to the provisions of this Act, where a person under eighteen years of age is tried for an offence, and the court is satisfied of his guilt, the court may deal with the case in one or more of the following ways- 
<xhtml:p>(a) by discharging the offender under section 35 (1) of the Penal Code;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) by discharging the offender on his entering into a recognizance, with or without sureties;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) by making a probation order against' the offender under the provisions of the Probation of Offenders Act;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(d) by committing the offender to the care of a fit person whether a relative or not, r an approved society or approved voluntary institution, willing to undertake his care;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(e) if the offender is under sixteen years of age by ordering him to be sent to an approved school suitable to his needs and attainments;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(f) subject to section 27 of the Penal Code. by ordering the offender in accordance with that section to undergo corporal punishment;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(g) by ordering the offender to pay a fine, compensation or costs, or any or all of them;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(h) by ordering the parent or guardian of the offender to pay a fine, compensation or costs as hereinafter provided;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(i) by ordering the parent or guardian of the offender to give security for his good behaviour as hereinafter provided;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(j) where the offender is a juvenile or young person, by ordering him to be imprisoned;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(k) in the case of a person who has attained the age of fifteen years, to deal with him in accordance with any Act which provides for the establishment and regulation of borstal institutions;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(l) in any other lawful manner:</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Provided that a court committing an offender to an approved school shall, not order him to undergo corporal punishment as well, but a court may order a probationer to undergo corporal punishment for any breach of the probation order made against him without discharging the said order.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11886"><num>18</num><heading>SECTION 18 Mental treatment.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>18.</xhtml:b>If it appears to the court on the evidence of a medical practitioner that a child or young person, although not of unsound mind, requires or may benefit from mental treatment, the court when making a probation order against him, may require him to undergo mental treatment at the hands or under the direction of a medical practitioner for a period not exceeding twelve months, subject to review by the court, as a condition of the probation order.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11887"><num>19</num><heading>SECTION 19 Power to order parent to pay fine, etc.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>19.</xhtml:b>(1) Where a person under eighteen years of age is charged with an offence for the commission of which a fine, compensation or costs may be imposed, if the court is of the opinion that the case would be best met by the imposition of a tine. compensation or costs, whether with or without any<xhtml:br/>other, punishment, the court may in any case, and shall if the offender is a child, order that the fine, compensation or costs imposed or awarded be paid by his parent or guardian instead of by the offender, unless the court is satisfied that the parent or guardian cannot be found or that he has not conduced to the commission of the offence by neglecting to exercise due<xhtml:br/>care of the offender. 
<xhtml:p>(2) Where a person under eighteen years of age is charged with an offence, the court may order his parent or guardian to give security for his good behaviour.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) An order under this section may be made against a parent or guardian who, having been required to attend, has failed to do so, but, save as aforesaid, no such order shall be made without giving the parent or guardian an opportunity of being heard.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) Any sums imposed and ordered to be paid by a parent or guardian under this section, or on forfeiture of any such security as aforesaid, may be recovered from him in like manner as if the order had been made on the conviction of the parent or guardian of the offence with which the offender was charged.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(5) A parent or guardian may appeal to the High Court against an order made under this section by a subordinate court.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11888"><num>20</num><heading>SECTION 20 Jurisdiction under Part III.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>20.</xhtml:b>A juvenile court shall have jurisdiction to make an order or give a judgment under this Part notwithstanding that any act, matter, thing or circumstance giving rise to such order or judgment did not occur or arise within the area of jurisdiction of the court.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11889"><num>21</num><heading>SECTION 21 Presumptions regarding custody, charge and care of children and juveniles.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>21.</xhtml:b>For the purposes of this Part - 
<xhtml:p>(a) any person who is the parent or guardian of a child or juvenile or who is legally liable to maintain him shall be presumed to have the custody of him,<xhtml:br/>subject to any provision made under section 30 of the Matrimonial Causes Act or under any other written law;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) any person to whose charge a child or juvenile is committed by any person who has the custody of him shall be presumed to have charge of him;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) any other person having actual possession or control of a child or juvenile shall be presumed to have care of him;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(d) any person employing a child or juvenile who is not resident with his parent or guardian shall be deemed to have care of that child or juvenile.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11890"><num>22</num><heading>SECTION 22 When child or juvenile is in need of protection or discipline.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>22.</xhtml:b>For the purposes of this Part a child or juvenile is in need of protection or discipline - 
<xhtml:p>(a) who has no parent or guardian, or has been deserted by his parent or guardian, or is destitute or a vagrant; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) who cannot be controlled by his parent or guardian or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) whose parent or guardian does not, or is unable or unfit to, exercise proper care and guardianship; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(d) who is falling into bad associations or is exposed to moral or physical danger; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(e) who is being kept in any premises which, in the opinion of a medical officer, are overcrowded insanitary or dangerous; or overcrowded,</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(f) who is prevented from receiving compulsory education, or is an habitual truant; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(g) who frequents any public bar or gambling house, or who is found buying or receiving or in possession of any drug which is deemed to be dangerous or habit terming; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(h) who is found begging or receiving alms or inducing the giving of alms, whether or not there is any pretence of singing, playing or performing; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(i) if any of the offences mentioned in the First Schedule to this Act has been committed against him, or if he is a member of the same household as a child or juvenile against whom any such offence has been committed, or is a member of the same household as a person who has been convicted of such an offence against a child or juvenile.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11891"><num>23</num><heading>SECTION 23 Penalty for cruelty to and neglecting children or juveniles.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>23.</xhtml:b>(1) If any person who has the custody, charge or i care of any child or juvenile - 
<xhtml:p>(a) wilfully assaults, ill-treats, neglects, abandons or exposes him, or causes or permits him to be assaulted, ill-treated, neglected, abandoned or exposed in any manner likely to cause him unnecessary suffering or injury to health (including injury to or loss of sight, hearing, limb or organ of the body, and mental derangement); or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) by any act or omission, knowingly or wilfully causes that child or juvenile to become, or conduces to his becoming, in need of protection or discipline. he shall be guilty of an offence and liable to a fine not exceeding five thousand shillings or to imprisonment for a term not exceeding six months or to both such fine and such imprisonment :</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Provided that the court, at any time in the course of proceedings for an offence under this subsection, may direct that the person charged shall be charged with and tried for an offence under the Penal Code, if the court is of the opinion that the acts or omissions of the person charged are of a serious or aggravated nature.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) For the purpose of this section, a person having custody, charge or care of a child or juvenile shall be deemed a manner likely to cause injury to his health if he has failed to provide adequate food, clothing medical aid or lodging for him.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3)(a) Any person charged under this section may be charged before the same juvenile court as that before which the child or juvenile is brought as being in need of protection or discipline, and at the same time.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) Both issues shall be tried simultaneously and the same court shall sentence the person charged, if convicted, and make an order under section 25 of this Act if the child or juvenile is found to be in need of protection or discipline.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) A person may be convicted of an offence under this section notwithstanding that - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) actual suffering or injury to health, or the likelihood of actual suffering or injury to health, of the child or juvenile, was obviated by the action of another person; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) the child or juvenile in question has died.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>5. If it is proved that a person convicted of an offence under this section was directly or indirectly in any accruing or payable in the event of the death of the child or juvenile, and had knowledge that money was accruing or becoming Payable then he shall be liable to a fine not exceeding ten thousand shillings or to imprisonment for a term not exceeding one year or to both such fine and such imprisonment. g</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(6) For the purposes of subsection (5) of this section a person shall be deemed to be directly or indirectly interested in any property or sum of money if he has any share in or any benefit from that property or the payment of that money although the money or property is not legally payable to him'</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(7) Nothing in this section shall affect the right of any parent, teacher or other person having the lawful control or charge of a child or juvenile to administer reasonable punishment to nun.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11892"><num>24</num><heading>SECTION 24 Proceedings in respect of children and juveniles in need of protection. or discipline.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>24.</xhtml:b>(1) Any authorized officer having reasonable grounds for believing that a child or juvenile is in need of protection or discipline may apprehend him without warrant and in such case shall without delay bring him before a court; and an inspector of children or a children's officer shall bring before a court any child or juvenile who appears to him to be in need of protection or discipline unless proceedings are about to be taken by some other person. 
<xhtml:p>(2) Any authorized officer may take to a place of safety any child or juvenile who is about to be brought before a court as being in need of protection or discipline, and a child or juvenile so taken to a place of safety, or who has taken refuge in a place of safety, may be detained there until he can be brought before a court.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) Where an application is to be made to a court for an order under section 25 of this Act and the child or juvenile is not in a place of safety, the court may issue a summons requiring him to be brought before the court, and thereupon the provisions of subsection (3) of that section shall apply for enabling the court to make an interim order for the temporary detention of the child or juvenile in a place of safety or for his temporary committal to the care of a fit person.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) Where under the provisions of this section a child or juvenile is taken to or ordered to be detained in a place of safety, the person who so takes him, or as the case may be, the person bringing him before the court, shall forthwith send a notice to the court specifying the grounds on which the child or juvenile is to be brought before the court, and shall send particulars to his parent or guardian warning him to attend at the court before which the child or juvenile will appear.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(5) Where any application is to be made to a court for an order under section 25 of this Act, the person intending to make the application shall forthwith notify the appointed local authority, if any, of the name and address of the child or juvenile and the day and hour when, and the nature of the grounds on which, he is to be brought before the court.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(6) A local authority having received a. notice under sub- section (5) of this section shall make such investigations and render available to the court such information as to the home, circumstances, age, health, character and general antecedents of the child or juvenile as may be necessary to assist the court.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(7) When it appears to an appointed local authority or approved society that a child or juvenile in its area is in need of protection or discipline and that its intervention is necessary, the local authority or approved society may receive him into its care and need not bring him before a court:</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Provided that - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) a monthly report is rendered to the chief inspector of children of all children and juveniles received and held;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) all cases are investigated by the local authority or approved society;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) the local authority or approved society shall not retain the child or juvenile in its care if his parent or guardian seeks to assume the care of the child or juvenile;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(d) the local authority or approved society shall, when it appears to be in the interests of the welfare of the child or juvenile, endeavour to secure that the care of the child or juvenile is assumed by a parent or guardian, or by some relative or friend who should, if possible, be of the same religion, race, tribe or clan as the child or juvenile.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(8) A local authority or approved society which receives la child or juvenile into its care under the provisions of this section shall be entitled to recover the cost of maintenance of such child or juvenile from his parent or guardian.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11893"><num>25</num><heading>SECTION 25 Powers of court in respect of children or juveniles in need of protection or discipline.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>25.</xhtml:b>(1) If a court is satisfied that any child or juvenile, or in the case of paragraph (d) of this subsection any child, juvenile or young person, brought before it is in need of protection or discipline the court may - 
<xhtml:p>(a) order him to be returned to his parent or guardian; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) order his parent or guardian to execute a bond with or without sureties to exercise proper care and guardianship; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) commit him to the care of a fit person, whether a relative of the child or juvenile or not, or an approved society, willing to undertake his care; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(d) commit him to the care of the appointed local authority, if any, where there does not appear to the court to be any fit person, approved society or<xhtml:br/>approved voluntary institution willing to undertake his care; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(e) without making any other order, or in addition to making an order under paragraph (a), (b) or (c) of this subsection, make an order placing him for a specified period, not exceeding three years, under the supervision of an approved officer, an inspector of children, a children's officer, or some other person appointed for the purpose by the court; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(f) where it is satisfied that it is in his best interests, commit him to an approved school suitable to his needs and attainments.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) (a) The court may from time to time of its own motion or on the application of any person, review, vary or revoke any order made under this section.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(6) The court may order that a juvenile remain in the custody of an appointed local authority, an approved society or fit person until the age of eighteen years or such lesser age as the court may decide.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) (a) If a court before which any child or juvenile is brought is unable to decide whether any order, or what order, ought to be made in respect of him, it may make such interim order as it thinks fit for his detention or continued detention in a place of safety not being a police station, or for his committal to the care of a fit person, whether a relative or not, who is willing to undertake the care of him.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) An interim order under this subsection shall not remain in force for more than twenty-eight days; but if at the expiration of that period the court deems it expedient so to do, it may continue to make further interim orders.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11894"><num>26</num><heading>SECTION 26 Parent or guardian may be heard in any application.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>26.</xhtml:b>(1) Where a child or juvenile is brought before a court as being in need of protection or discipline, the court shall allow his parent or guardian to be heard on any application made in relation to the child or juvenile. 
<xhtml:p>(2) Where the parent or guardian cannot be found or cannot in the opinion of the court reasonably be required to attend, the court may allow any relative or other responsible person to take the place of the parent or guardian for the purposes of this section.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11895"><num>27</num><heading>SECTION 27 Application of trusts for maintenance of children or juveniles.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>27.</xhtml:b>(1) Where a child or juvenile is, by ah order of the court made under this Part, removed from the care of any person, and that person is entitled under any trust to receive any sum of money in respect of his maintenance the court may order the whole or any part of the sums so payable under the trust to be paid to the person, approved society or appointed local authority to whose care the child or juvenile is committed, to be applied for his benefit in such manner as the court, having regard to the terms of the trust, may direct. 
<xhtml:p>(2) A person making default in complying with an order of the court made under this section shall be punished in the prescribed manner, or if no punishment is prescribed may in the discretion of the court be ordered to pay a sum not exceeding twenty shillings for every day during which he is in default or to be imprisoned or dealt with under section 71' (5) of this Act until he has remedied his default.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) An appeal shall lie to the High Court from an order made under this section.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11896"><num>28</num><heading>SECTION 28 Determination of court as to person&amp;apos;s home, etc., to be final.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>28.</xhtml:b>Whenever a child or juvenile is brought before a court as being in need of protection or discipline and the court determines that he has his home or, as the case may be, has been found within the area of jurisdiction of a particular local authority, such determination shall, for the purposes of this Act, be final and conclusive: 
<xhtml:p>Provided that a court may, whenever it thinks it convenient so to do. remit any such case to another court to be dealt with by that court, without prejudice, however, to the provisions of section 59 of this Act.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11897"><num>29</num><heading>SECTION 29 Warrants for search for children or juveniles.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>29.</xhtml:b>(1) If it appears to a magistrate on information laid by at least two persons who, in the opinion of the magistrate, are acting in the interests of a child or juvenile that there is reasonable cause to suspect - 
<xhtml:p>(a) that one of the offences specified in the First Schedule to this Act has been or is being or is about to be committed against the child or juvenile; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) that he is in need of protection or discipline,</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>the magistrate may issue a warrant authorizing any police officer of or above the rank of Assistant Inspector and named therein to search for the child or juvenile, and, if it appears to such police officer that any offence as aforesaid has been or is being or is about to be committed against the child or juvenile or that he is in need of protection or discipline, to take him to and detain him in a place of safety until he can be brought before a court.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) Any police officer of or above the rank of Assistant Inspector authorized by warrant under this section to search for any child or juvenile may enter (if need be by force) any house, building or other place specified in the warrant, and subject as aforesaid may remove him therefrom.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) A police officer executing a warrant under this section shall take with him any person laying or joining in the laying of the information who desires to accompany him, unless the magistrate issuing the warrant otherwise directs; and may also, if such magistrate so directs, be accompanied by a medical practitioner.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>4) It shall not be necessary in any information or warrant under this section to name the child or juvenile.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(5) A magistrate issuing" a warrant under this section may by the same warrant cause any person accused of an offence against the child or juvenile to be apprehended and brought before a court, and proceedings to be taken against him according to law.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(6) A refusal to allow the chief inspector of children, an inspector of children, children's officer or an approved officer to enter any place or dwelling in the exercise of his powers under this Act shall for the purposes of subsection (1) of this section be deemed to be a reasonable cause to suspect that a child or juvenile therein is in need of protection or discipline.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(7) The provisions of this section shall be in addition to, and not in derogation of, those of the Criminal Procedure Code in relation to entry of premises and arrest of persons.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11898"><num>30</num><heading>SECTION 30 Arrest without warrant.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>30.</xhtml:b>A police officer may arrest without warrant any person who he has reason to believe has committed any offence under this Part or any other offence involving bodily injury to a child or juvenile, if the police officer has reasonable ground for believing that the person will abscond or if he does not know and is unable immediately to ascertain the person's name and address.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11899"><num>31</num><heading>SECTION 31 Provisions as to orders of committal to fit persons</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>31.</xhtml:b>(1) A court making an order committing a person under eighteen years of age to the care of a fit person or approved society shall, if practicable, select a person or society of the same religion as the person committed.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) Every such order shall be in writing, shall contain a declaration as to the age and religion of the person committed and may be made in his absence; and the consent of the fit person or approved society to undertake such care shall be proved in such manner as the court may think sufficient to bind that person or society.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) The court making an order committing a person under eighteen years of age to the care of a fit person, approved society or appointed local authority shall cause to be</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11900"><num>32</num><heading>SECTION 32 Contents of committal order.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>32.</xhtml:b>Where an order of committal to an approved school has been made by a court against a child or juvenile on a finding of guilty of an offence, the committal order shall specify the grounds of committal, contain a declaration as to the age and religion of the offender, and specify the school to which he is first to be sent and the person or authority which is to convey him to the school.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11901"><num>33</num><heading>SECTION 33 Transmission of order.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>33.</xhtml:b>The court making an order of committal to an approved school shall send it, together with a record in the prescribed form of such information regarding the person committed as the court thinks necessary, to the manager of the school.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11902"><num>34</num><heading>SECTION 34 Production of child or juvenile.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>34.</xhtml:b>Where a person authorized to escort a child or juvenile to an approved school is unable to find or obtain possession of him, the court may, if satisfied by information on oath that some person named in the information can produce the child or juvenile, issue a summons requiring the person so named to attend at the court on a certain day and produce the child or juvenile, and if the person so summoned fails without reasonable cause to attend he shall, in addition to any other liability to which he may be subject under the provisions of any law including this Act, be guilty of an offence and liable to a fine not exceeding five hundred shillings.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11903"><num>35</num><heading>SECTION 35 Harbouring or concealing child or juvenile.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>35.</xhtml:b>Where a child or juvenile has been committed to an approved school, any person who harbours or conceals him after the time fixed for him to enter the approved school shall be guilty of an offence and liable to imprisonment for a term not exceeding two months or to a fine not exceeding two thousand shillings or to both such imprisonment and such fine.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11904"><num>36</num><heading>SECTION 36 Establishment of juvenile remand homes.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>36.</xhtml:b>(1) Subject as hereinafter provided, the Minister may establish such juvenile remand homes as he considers necessary. 
<xhtml:p>(2) The managers of any institution other than a prison or detention camp may enter into an agreement for the use of that institution or any part thereof as a juvenile remand home on such terms as may be agreed between them and the Minister.<xhtml:br/></xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11905"><num>37</num><heading>SECTION 37 Approval of schools.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>37.</xhtml:b>(1) The manager of any school which is suitable for the reception, maintenance and training of children and juveniles ordered to be sent to an approved school under this Act may apply to the Minister to approve the school for that purpose, and the Minister may by notice in the Gazette declare the school to be an approved school and issue a certificate of approval to the manager. 
<xhtml:p>(2) If at any time the Minister is dissatisfied with the condition or management of an approved school, or considers its continuation as an approved school unnecessary he may give to the manager not less than six months' notice in writing of his intention to withdraw the certificate of approval, and upon the expiration of the notice the certificate of approval shall be deemed to have been withdrawn and the school shall cease to be an approved school:</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Provided that the Minister, instead of withdrawing the certificate of approval, may, by notice served on the manager of the school, prohibit the further admission of persons to the school for such time as may be specified in the notice, or until the notice is revoked.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) The manager of an approved school may, after giving not less than six months' notice in writing to the Minister of his intention so to do, surrender the certificate of approval of the school, and upon the expiration of the notice (unless the notice is previously withdrawn) the certificate shall be deemed to have been surrendered and the school shall cease to be approved.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) No person shall be received into an approved school under the provisions of this ct after notice has been given of intention to withdraw or surrender the certificate of approval; but the obligations of the manager with respect to persons under his care at the date of the notice shall continue until the withdrawal or surrender takes effect.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(5) The Minister shall cause any notice of intention to withdraw or surrender a certificate of approval to be published forthwith in the Gazette.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11906"><num>38</num><heading>SECTION 38 Minister may establish approved schools.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>38.</xhtml:b>The Minister may, by notice .in the Gazette, establish approved schools for the reception, maintenance and training of persons ordered to be sent to an approved school under this Act.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11907"><num>39</num><heading>SECTION 39 Obligations of managers.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>39.</xhtml:b>The manager of an approved school shall be bound to accept every person who is duly sent or transferred to the school or otherwise committed to hi&amp; care, unless - 
<xhtml:p>(a) the school is a school for persons of a different religion or of a different sex from that of the person whom it is proposed to send or transfer there; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) the manager of the school satisfies the Minister that it is undesirable that any more persons should be admitted to the school or otherwise committed to his care.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11908"><num>40</num><heading>SECTION 40 Supervision of approved schools and juvenile remand homes.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>40.</xhtml:b>The chief inspector of children shall be responsible for the supervision of all approved schools and juvenile remand homes and for this purpose shall periodically visit them or cause them to be visited.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11909"><num>41</num><heading>SECTION 41 Establishment of advisory council.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>41</xhtml:b>. (1) There shall be established by the Minister, by notice in the Gazette, an advisory council, to be known as the Advisory Council on Children and Young Persons, which shall consist of such persons qualified to deal with matters relating to the welfare of children, juveniles and young persons as the Minister thinks fit and such local panels of official visitors to approved schools and juvenile remand homes as he considers expedient. 
<xhtml:p>(2) The advisory council shall advise the Minister on matters relating to the exercise of his powers and the performance of his duties under this Act.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) The advisory council may make representations to the Minister on any matters arising out of the exercise of its functions.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11910"><num>42</num><heading>SECTION 42 Leave of absence.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>42.</xhtml:b>The manager of an approved school may, with the consent of the chief inspector of children, grant leave of absence to any person detained in an approved school for such period and on such conditions as he deems fit and may at any time terminate such leave and direct the person to return to the school.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11911"><num>43</num><heading>SECTION 43 Release on licence.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>43.</xhtml:b>At any time during the period of a person's detention in an approved school, the chief inspector of children may by licence in writing permit him to live with his parent or with any fit person who is willing to receive and take charge of him, and may at any time by writing under his hand revoke such licence, and direct the person to whom it was granted to return to the school.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11912"><num>44</num><heading>SECTION 44 Revocation of approved school order; duration of order.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>44.</xhtml:b>(1) The chief inspector of children may in his discretion, if satisfied that a person who has been ordered to be committed to an approved school should not remain subject to the order, may, by further order in writing, revoke the committal order. 
<xhtml:p>(2) The court may at any time, of its own motion or on the application of any person, revoke an order committing a person to an approved school, but before doing so it shall call for all the relative records of the court which made the order, and all relative records of any court which may previously have considered an application under this section.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) Notwithstanding anything in this Act, an order committing a person to an approved school shall not remain in force beyond the date on which the person attains the age of twenty years, nor shall any such order remain in force for longer than three years at a time except by order of the court.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) On an application for an order under subsection (2) or subsection (3) of this section, the manager of the approved school where the person is shall cause the person to be brought before the court, unless the court otherwise orders.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11913"><num>45</num><heading>SECTION 45 Transfers and supervision after release.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>45.</xhtml:b>(1) The chief inspector of children may at any time order a person to be transferred from one approved school to another, but so that the period of his detention shall not be increased thereby. 
<xhtml:p>(2) A person committed to an approved school shall after the expiration of the period of his detention be under the supervision of such person as the chief inspector of children shall appoint, for a period of two years or until he attains the age of twenty-one years, whichever shall be the shorter period.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11914"><num>46</num><heading>SECTION 46 Treatment of absconders and persons of bad character.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>46.</xhtml:b>(1) Where the chief inspector of children is of the opinion that a person committed to an approved school is a persistent absconder, or is exercising a bad influence on the other inmates of the school, he may apply to the court having jurisdiction in the place where the school is situate_ 
<xhtml:p>(a) in the case of a person under the age of sixteen years to have the period of committal increased by a period not exceeding six months; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) in the case of persons over the age of fifteen years, to have the person sent to a borstal institution.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) Where the chief inspector of children is of the opinion that a person over the age of fourteen years committed to an approved school is of so depraved and unruly a character that he cannot benefit from approved school training, he may apply to the court having jurisdiction in the place where the school is situate to vary the whole or part of the unexpired portion of the person's term to one of imprisonment.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11915"><num>47</num><heading>SECTION 47 Removal to hospital.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>47.</xhtml:b>(1) In the case of serious illness of a person detained in a juvenile remand home or an approved school, the manager, on the advice of a medical officer or medical practitioner, may make an order for his removal to a hospital. 
<xhtml:p>(2) Whenever the medical officer in charge of a hospital considers that the health of a person removed to the hospital under the provisions of this section no longer requires treatment therein, he shall notify the manager of the approved school from whence he was removed to hospital, who shall thereupon cause such person to be brought back to the school if he is still-liable to be detained therein.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) Every reasonable precaution shall be taken by the medical officer in charge of the hospital to prevent the escape of any person who is confined therein under this section:</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Provided that nothing shall be done under the authority of this section which in the opinion of the medical officer in charge of the hospital is likely to be prejudicial to the health of the person confined.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11916"><num>48</num><heading>SECTION 48 Authority for detention in juvenile remand homes, approved schools and</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>48.</xhtml:b>The order committing a person to custody in a juvenile remand home or ordering him to be sent to an approved school shall be sufficient authority for his detention in that place in accordance with the tenor thereof, or in a hospital under section 47 of this Act, and a person while so detained and while being conveyed to or from a juvenile remand home or an approved school, or to or from a hospital, as the case may be, shall be deemed to be in lawful custody.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11917"><num>49</num><heading>SECTION 49 Application of Part VI.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:p><xhtml:b>49</xhtml:b>. (1) Subject to the provisions of subsection (3) of this section, this Part shall have effect where arrangements are made for placing a person under eighteen years of age in the care and possession of a person who is resident in Kenya and is not a parent, guardian or relative of his, and another person, not being a parent or guardian of his, participates in the arrangements.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) For the purposes of this Part, a person shall be deemed to participate in the arrangements for placing a person under eighteen years of age in the care and possession of another person - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(<xhtml:i>a</xhtml:i>) if he enters into or makes any agreement or arrangement for, or for facilitating, the placing of the person in the care and possession of that other person; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(<xhtml:i>b</xhtml:i>) if he initiates or takes part in any negotiations of which the purpose or effect is the conclusion of any agreement or the making of any arrangement<xhtml:br/>therefor, or if he causes another to do so.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) The provisions of this Part shall not have effect where possession of a person under eighteen years of age has been, is or is proposed to be taken - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(<xhtml:i>a</xhtml:i>) by any person for a purely temporary purpose;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(<xhtml:i>b</xhtml:i>) by a fit person, approved society or appointed local authority to whose care the person has been committed under this Act;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(<xhtml:i>c</xhtml:i>) by a school, hospital, convalescent home or other similar institution;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(<xhtml:i>d</xhtml:i>) by an institution to which a person has been committed under the provisions of the Mental Treatment Act; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(<xhtml:i>e</xhtml:i>) by an approved school or remand home.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) The provisions of this Part shall cease to have effect |in relation to a person under eighteen years of age - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(<xhtml:i>a</xhtml:i>) if an adoption order or an interim order is made in respect of him under the Adoption Act, upon the making of such order; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(<xhtml:i>b</xhtml:i>) if no such order has been made, on the date on which he attains the age of eighteen years.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11918"><num>50</num><heading>SECTION 50 Notification of taking possession of a person.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>50</xhtml:b>. (1) Not less than seven days before possession is taken of a person pursuant to any arrangements made under this Part, every person who participates in the arrangements, not being a parent or guardian of the person concerned, shall give notice of the arrangements to the chief inspector of<xhtml:br/>children. 
<xhtml:p>(2) The notice required by this section shall state the name and sex of the person concerned, the date and place of his birth and the name and address of the person in whose care and possession he is placed, and if it is given orally shall be recorded by the chief inspector of children.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) Any person who fails to give any notice required by subsection (1) of this section to be given shall be guilty of an offence and liable to imprisonment for a term not exceeding two months or to a fine not exceeding two thousand shillings or to both such imprisonment and such fine.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11919"><num>51</num><heading>SECTION 51 Notification of change of residence or of death.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>51.</xhtml:b>(1) Where a person who has in his care and possession a person in relation to whom this Part has effect changes r his residence, he shall, not less than one week before the  change or, it the change is made in an emergency, not later than one week after the change, give notice of the change of address, in writing or orally, to a District Commissioner, who shall report it to the chief inspector of children. 
<xhtml:p>(2) If a person in relation to whom this Part has effect dies the person in whose care and possession he was at his death shall within forty-eight hours of the death give notice of the death, in writing or orally, to the District Commissioner of the district in which the person dies, who shall report it to the chief, inspector of children.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) Any person who fails to give any notice required by this section to be given shall be guilty of an offence and liable to imprisonment for a term not exceeding two months or to a fine not exceeding two thousand shillings o to both such imprisonment and such fine.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11920"><num>52</num><heading>SECTION 52 Summary order for removal of person.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>52.</xhtml:b>(1) If a person in relation to whom this Part has effect - 
<xhtml:p>(a) is about to be received into, or is being kept by any person in, any premises which are overcrowded, insanitary or dangerous, or an environment which is detrimental to him; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) is in the care and possession of a person who, by reason of old age. infirmity, ill-health, ignorance, negligence, intemperance, immorality or criminal conduct, or for any other reason, is unfit to have care of him,</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>a court may, on an application made by or on behalf of the chief inspector of children, make an order for the removal of the person to a place of safety until he can be restored to his parents or guardian or until other arrangements can be made for him.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) Upon proof that there is imminent danger to the health or well-being of the person concerned, any magistrate, acting if he deems it necessary,<xhtml:i>ex parte</xhtml:i>, may upon the application of an inspector of children or children's officer exercise the powers conferred upon a court by subsection (1) of this section.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) Any order made under the provisions of this section may be enforced by an inspector of children, children's officer or approved officer and any person who refuses to comply with such an order on its being produced, or who obstructs an officer in the enforcement of such order shall be guilty of an offence and liable to imprisonment for a term not exceeding six months or to a fine not exceeding five thousand shillings or to both such imprisonment and such fine.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11921"><num>53</num><heading>SECTION 53 Removal of person in respect of whom an offence has been committed.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>53.</xhtml:b>Where any person is convicted of an offence under the provisions of this Part, the court may order any person under eighteen years of age in respect of whom the offence was committed to be removed to a place of safety until he can be restored to his parents or guardian or until other arrangements can be made for him. 
<xhtml:p><xhtml:br/></xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11922"><num>54</num><heading>SECTION 54 Appointment of chief inspector of children, inspectors of children and children&amp;apos;s officers.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>54</xhtml:b>. (1) The Minister shall appoint a chief inspector of children and such number of inspectors of children and children s officers as he may think fit. 
<xhtml:p>(2)An appointed local authority may with the consent of the Minister, by notice in the Gazette, appoint children's officers for the area of its jurisdiction.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11923"><num>55</num><heading>SECTION 55 Duties of officers.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>55.</xhtml:b>(1) The chief inspector of children shall have the functions conferred on him by this Act. and shall perform such supervisory and other duties in relation to inspectors of children, children's officers and approved officers as the Minister may from time to time direct. 
<xhtml:p>(2) Inspectors of children and children's officers shall have the functions conferred on them by this Act. and shall a so be responsible for the inspection of voluntary institutions places of safety, boarding-out establishments, holiday homes and nurseries whether or not established by a local authority and persons under eighteen years of age committed to the care of fit persons, approved societies and appointed local authorities under this Act.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11924"><num>56</num><heading>SECTION 56 Powers of officers.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>56.</xhtml:b>The chief inspector of children, any inspector of children and any children's officer may, after producing, if asked to do so, some duly authenticated document showing that he is so authorized, enter any voluntary institution, place of safety, boarding-out establishment, holiday home or nursery or the dwelling of any person in whose care a person under eighteen years of age has been placed under this Act, and may make such examination into the state and management thereof and the condition and treatment of any person under eighteen years of age therein, as he thinks requisite.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11925"><num>57</num><heading>SECTION 57 Obstruction.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>57.</xhtml:b>Any person who obstructs the chief inspector of Obstruction. children, an inspector of children, children's officer or approved officer in the execution of his duties Or powers under this Act shall be guilty of an offence and liable to a fine not exceeding five hundred shillings.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11926"><num>58</num><heading>SECTION 58 Appointment of local authorities.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>58.</xhtml:b>(1) The Minister may from time to time, with the agreement or at the request of a municipal or county council. or group of such councils, by order appoint such council or group of councils, to be an appointed local authority for the purposes of this Act, and a council or group of councils so appointed shall, subject to the provisions of section 59 of , perform the duties imposed and have the powers conferred upon appointed local authorities under this Act. 
<xhtml:p>(2) A local authority either by itself or jointly with other local authorities may make welfare schemes for persons under eighteen years of age embracing any or all of the items set out in the Second Schedule to this Act and the Minister may by order appoint such local authority or joint local authorities to be an appointed local authority for the purpose and to the extent set out in such schemes.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) The provisions of this Part shall not operate to impose any duties or confer any powers, other than those imposed or conferred by section 62 of this Act, upon any local authority which is not for the time being an appointed local authority.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11927"><num>59</num><heading>SECTION 59 Application of powers and duties.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>59.</xhtml:b>(1) Where any powers or duties are by this Part conferred or imposed on an appointed local authority as such, those powers and duties shall, in the case of a person under eighteen years of age who has his home - 
<xhtml:p>(a) within a municipality or township, be powers and duties of the municipal council or the District Com- missioner as local authority of the township, as the case may be;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) in a county outside a municipality or township, be powers and duties of the county council.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) Where, for any district, there is for the time being no appointed local authority having jurisdiction therein, the Minister may, with the concurrence of the Treasury, by order appoint the District Commissioner of the district to have the functions of an appointed local authority under this Part, and the District Commissioner shall then perform the duties and have the powers imposed and conferred upon appointed local authorities under this Part in respect of all persons under eighteen years of age having their homes within the district.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11928"><num>60</num><heading>SECTION 60 Delegation of functions of county councils.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>60</xhtml:b>. (1) A county council which is an appointed local authority may with the concurrence of the council of any county division within the county, delegate to such council, with or without restrictions or conditions, any of its functions as an appointed local authority. 
<xhtml:p>(2) Where functions are delegated to the council of a county division under this section, such council, in the discharge of those functions, shall act as agent for the county council.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11929"><num>61</num><heading>SECTION 61 Delegation of certain powers and duties by appointed local authorities.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>61.</xhtml:b>An appointed local authority may, with the approval of the Minister, delegate its powers, and duties relating to investigations under section 24 (6) of this Act to an approved society or an approved officer.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11930"><num>62</num><heading>SECTION 62 Powers of local authorities to incur expenditure in temporary care.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>62.</xhtml:b>Any local authority, whether an appointed local authority or not, and any District Commissioner, may incur expenditure in or about the temporary care of any child or juvenile in need of care including his maintenance in a place of safety or in the return of any such child or juvenile to his parent or guardian or the area of the appointed local authority, if any, notwithstanding that in the case of an appointed local authority such child or juvenile has not been committed to its care under the provisions of this Part.<xhtml:br/></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11931"><num>63</num><heading>SECTION 63 Approval of approved societies.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>63.</xhtml:b>(1) The managing committee or governing body of any society of persons working for the care. protection or control of children, juveniles and young persons, or of any voluntary institution, may apply to the Minister for the society or voluntary institution to be approved for that purpose, and the Minister, after making such inquiries as he thinks fit, may approve the society or voluntary institution for that purpose and issue a certificate of approval accordingly. and upon the expiration of the notice the certificate shall be deemed to have been withdrawn and the society or voluntary institution shall cease to be an approved society or approved voluntary institution. 
<xhtml:p>(3) The managing committee or governing body of an approved society or approved voluntary institution may give to the Minister not less than three months' notice in writing of its intention to surrender the certificate of approval, and upon the expiration of the notice (unless the notice is previously withdrawn) the certificate shall be deemed to have been surrendered and the society or voluntary institution shall cease to be an approved society or approved voluntary institution.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) No child or juvenile shall be committed or received into the care of an approved society or approved voluntary institution under this Act after notice has been given of intention to withdraw or surrender the certificate of approval, but the obligations of the approved society or approved voluntary institution with respect to persons under its care at the date of the notice shall continue until the society or voluntary institution ceases to be an approved society or approved voluntary institution.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(5) The Minister shall, within one month after the date thereof, cause every grant of a certificate of approval and every notice of intention to withdraw or surrender a certificate of approval to be published in the Gazette.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) If at any time the Minister considers that the continuance of any approved society or approved voluntary institution as an approved society or approved voluntary Institution is unnecessary or undesirable, he may give to the managing committee or governing body of the society or voluntary institution not less than three months' notice in writing of his intention to withdraw the certificate of approval</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11932"><num>64</num><heading>SECTION 64 Appointment and powers of approved officers.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>64.</xhtml:b>(1) An approved society may with the approval of the Minister, by notice in the Gazette, appoint one or more officers to be approved officers, to further those purposes of the society which relate to the care, protection and control of children and juveniles: 
<xhtml:p>Provided that no approved officer shall enter upon the exercise of his functions as such in the area of any appointed local authority without the concurrence of such authority.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) The appointment of an approved officer may be revoked by the approved society or by the Minister, and any such revocation shall be published in the Gazette.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) Approved officers shall have such powers as the Minister may prescribe.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11933"><num>65</num><heading>SECTION 65 Escapes from fit persons, etc</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>65.</xhtml:b>A person under eighteen years of age who runs away from a fit person, approved society or appointed local authority to whose care he has been committed under this Act, or from any person or institution with whom he has been placed by an approved society or appointed local authority under any regulations made under this Act, may be apprehended without warrant and brought back to that person, society, authority. or institution if he or it is wiling to receive him, or may be brought before a juvenile court having jurisdiction in the place where he was residing immediately before he ran away and that court may - 
<xhtml:p>(a) in the case of a person committed under Part II of this Act - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(i) commit him to the care of some other fit person or approved society; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(ii) order him to be sent to an approved school; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(iii) make any order which a court may make under section 46 of this Act;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) in the case of a person committed under Part III of this Act - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(i) where he was committed to the care of an appointed local authority, order that he be returned to such care; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(ii) make any order which a court can make under section 25 of this Act; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(iii) order him to be sent to an approved school.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11934"><num>66</num><heading>SECTION 66 Approved societies and appointed local authorities to report escape.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>66</xhtml:b>. Whenever a person under eighteen years of age runs away from any person or institution with whom or with which he has been placed by an approved society or appointed local authority as aforesaid, it shall be the duty of the secretary, clerk or other appropriate officer of such society or authority, within forty-eight hours of such occurrence coming to his knowledge, to notify the chief inspector of children thereof; and any secretary, clerk or other officer as aforesaid who contravenes the provisions of this subsection shall be guilty of an offence and liable to a fine not exceeding two<xhtml:br/>hundred shillings.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11935"><num>67</num><heading>SECTION 67 Escapes from juvenile remand homes and approved schools.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>67.</xhtml:b>(1) Any person who escapes from a juvenile remand home or while being conveyed thereto or therefrom, may be apprehended without warrant and brought back to a juvenile remand home. 
<xhtml:p>(2) Any person who has been committed to an approved school and who - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) escapes from the approved school or from any hospital, home or institution in which he is receiving medical or other treatment, or while being conveyed to or from any such place; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) being absent from his school on leave of absence or on licence, runs away from the person in whose charge he has been placed, or fails to return to the school upon the expiration of his leave or upon the revocation of his licence, may be apprehended without warrant and shall be brought back to the approved school and may be brought before a court having jurisdiction where the approved school is situate to be dealt with under the provisions of section 46 of this Act.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) Where a person is brought back to his approved school under subsection (2) of this section, whether or not he is brought before a court, the period of his committal shall be increased, over and above any increase ordered by the court, by a period equal to the period during which he was at large and should have been at the approved school.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11936"><num>68</num><heading>SECTION 68 Assisting escape, etc.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>68.</xhtml:b>If any person knowingly - 
<xhtml:p>(a) assists or induces a person - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(i) to run away from a fit person, approved society or appointed local authority to whose care he has been committed, or from any person or institution with whom or with which he has been placed by an approved society or appointed local authority under or by virtue of this Act or any regulations made thereunder; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(ii) to do any of the things specified in section 67 (2) of this Act; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) harbours or conceals a person who has so run away or has done any of such things as aforesaid; or</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) prevents such a person from returning, or induces such a person not to return, to the care of the person to which he has been committed, or to any place in which he should be, he shall be guilty of an offence and liable to imprisonment for a term not exceeding three months, or to a fine not exceeding three thousand shillings or to both such imprisonment and such fine.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11937"><num>69</num><heading>SECTION 69 Production of escaped person.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>69.</xhtml:b>If a court is satisfied by information on oath that Production there are reasonable grounds for supposing that a person has run away, or done any of the things specified in section 67 (2) f this Act, and that some other person named in the information can produce him, the court may issue a summons requiring that other person to attend at the court and produce the person, and, if that other person fails to do so without reasonable excuse, he shall be guilty of an offence and, in addition to any other liability to which he may be subject under the pro-visions of this Act, liable to a fine not exceeding five hundred shillings.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11938"><num>70</num><heading>SECTION 70 Presumptions and determination of age.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>70.</xhtml:b>(1) Where a person, whether charged with an offence or not. is brought before any court otherwise than for the purpose of giving evidence, and it appears to the court that he is under eighteen years of age, the court shall make due inquiry as to the age of that person, and for that purpose shall take such evidence, including medical evidence as it may require, but an order or judgment of the court shall not be invalidated by any subsequent proof that the age of that person has not been correctly stated to the court, and the age presumed or declared by the court to be the age of the person so brought before it shall, for the purposes of this Act and of all proceedings thereunder, be deemed to be the true age of the person. 
<xhtml:p>(2) A certificate purporting to be signed by a medical practitioner as to the age of a person under eighteen years of age shall be evidence thereof and shall be receivable by a court without proof of signature unless the court otherwise directs.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11939"><num>71</num><heading>SECTION 71 Contribution orders.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>71.</xhtml:b>(1) A court making an order committing a person to the care of a fit person, approved society or appointed local authority or ordering him to be sent to an approved school may also, at the same time or subsequently, make an order (hereinafter referred to -as a contribution order) requiring either or both of the parents or the guardian, or, in the case of a young person, the young person himself if he is engaged in remunerative full-time work, to contribute such sums for such periods as the court shall think fit towards the maintenance of the person concerned. 
<xhtml:p>(2) The contribution order shall name the person to whom the sums are to be paid.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) A contribution order may be made on the complaint or application of the fit person, approved society or appointed local authority to whose care the person has been committed or the manager of the approved school to which he has been ordered to be sent, and may require that contributions shall be made from the date of the committal of the person; and every sum contributed in accordance with the order shall be applied to or towards his maintenance.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) A court which has made a contribution order under this section may at any time vary, suspend or rescind the order, or revive the order after it has been rescinded, but no contribution order shall be made, varied, suspended, rescinded, or revived unless the court is satisfied that the person liable to make payments under the order and the person, approved society, appointed local authority or manager of the approved school to whom such payments are due, or are to become due, has received due notification of the complaint or application and had an opportunity to appear before the court on the hearing thereof.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(5) Arrears of contributions shall be recovered in the manner provided in sections 334 to 342 of the Criminal Procedure Code for the levying of fines imposed by a court in criminal proceedings, and the court shall be empowered to make an attachment order against the defaulter's salary or other source of income, subject always to any written law protecting pensions or other sources of income from attachment.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(6) A person against whom a contribution order has been made shall, if he changes his address, forthwith give notice thereof to the person entitled to receive the contribution and if e fails to do so shall be guilty of an offence and liable to a fine not exceeding two hundred shillings.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(7) For the purposes of this section, "parent" includes step-father, step-mother and adoptive parent.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11940"><num>72</num><heading>SECTION 72 Affiliation orders.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>72.</xhtml:b>(1) Where a person under sixteen years of age who is Affiliation ordered by a court to be committed to the care of a fit person, orders' approved society or appointed local authority or to be sent to an approved school is illegitimate, and an affiliation order for his maintenance is in force, that court may at the same time, and any court having jurisdiction in the place where the putative father is for the time being residing may subsequently at any time, order the payments under the affiliation order to be made to the person who is from time to time entitled under section 71 of this Act to receive contributions in respect of the person concerned.<xhtml:br/><xhtml:p>(2) Applications for orders under subsection (1) of this section may be made by the persons by whom, and in the circumstances in which, applications for contribution orders1 may be made. i</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) Where an order made under subsection (1) of this section with respect to an affiliation order is in force - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) any powers conferred on courts by the Affiliation Act shall as regards that affiliation order be exercisable, and exercisable only, by a court having jurisdiction in the place where the person liable is for the time being residing;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) any sums received under the affiliation order shall be applied in like manner as if they were contributions received under a contribution order.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) The making of an&lt; order under subsection (1) of this section shall not extend the duration of the affiliation order. and the affiliation order shall not in any case remain in force (except for the purpose of the recovery of arrears) - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(a) in the case of a person committed to the care of a fit person, approved society or appointed local authority, after the order for his committal has ceased to be in force; Win the case of a person ordered to be sent to an approved school, after he has been released from his school, either absolutely or on licence or under supervision :</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>Provided that where an affiliation order would, but for the provisions of this subsection, have continued in force, the mother, or any person entitled to make an application for an order under section 6 (2) of the Affiliation Act, may apply to a court having jurisdiction in the place where she or he is for the time being residing for an order that the affiliation order may be revived and that payments thereunder may until the expiration thereof be made to the applicant at such rate (not exceeding the maximum rate allowed by that Act) as may be proper, and the court may make such an order accordingly, and where such an order is so made any power to vary, revoke or again revive the affiliation order or any part thereof, being a power which would but for the provisions of this subsection be vested in the court which originally made the affiliation order, shall be exercisable, and exercisable only, by the court which made the order under this subsection.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11941"><num>73</num><heading>SECTION 73 International reciprocity.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>73.</xhtml:b>(1) It shall be lawful for the Minister with the consent of the National Assembly, to enter into an agreement with the Government of any other country or territory on such terms and conditions as he may think fit, whereby a person has been ordered by a court under the Provisions of this Act to be sent to an approved school or other institution or committed to the care of a fit person may be received into hat country or territory and there detained in an approved institution approved under the relevant legislation of that country or territory, or received into the care of a person or returned to his parent or guardian. 
<xhtml:p>(2) It shall be lawful for the Minister, with the consent of the National Assembly to enter into an agreement with the Government of any other country or territory on such terms and conditions as he may think fit been ordered by a court of such country or territory to be sent to an approved school or other institution or committed to the care of a fit person may be received in Kenya and there detained in an approved school or other institution or received into the care of a fit person, or of his parent or guardian.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(3) Any person who has been ordered under the provisions of this Act to be detained in an approved school or other institution, or committed to the care of a fit person may, while still subject to such order, by warrant signed by the Minister, be removed in custody into any other country or agreement has been concluded under subsection (1) of this section, and there detained in an approved school or other institution, or placed in the care of a parent or guardian in accordance with the law m force m the country or territory authorising such detention until the expiration of the order or until he is sooner released according to law.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(4) An order of a court of a country or territory with which an agreement has been entered into in accordance with he provisions of subsection (2) of this section which could lawfully have been made by a court in Kenya if the person had been within its jurisdiction shall upon the person being received in Kenya have the same effect and be enforceable as if the order had been made by a court in Kenya</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11942"><num>74</num><heading>SECTION 74 Bonds.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>74.</xhtml:b>The provisions of the Criminal Procedure Code with respect to bonds for good behaviour (including the provisions as to their enforcement ) shall apply to bonds entered into under this Act.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11943"><num>75</num><heading>SECTION 75 Appeals.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>75</xhtml:b>. (1) An appeal to the High Court from an order Under this Act may be made m the following cases and by the following persons - 
<xhtml:p>(a) in the case of an order committing a person under eighteen years of age to the care of a fit person approved society or appointed local authority or placing a person under supervision, a probation order or an .order of committal to an approved school, by the person himself or his parent or guardian on his behalf;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) in the case of an order requiring a parent or guardian to give security for the good behaviour of a person under eighteen years of age, by the person required to give security, or, where a person under eighteen years of age is himself required to give such security by him or his parent or guardian;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) in the case of an order requiring a person to contribute in respect of himself or any other person, by the person required to contribute;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(d) in the case of an order requiring all or any part of the payments under an affiliation order to be paid to some other person, by the person who would but for the order be entitled to the payments.</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(2) Nothing in this section shall restrict the rights of appeal to the High Court conferred by Part XI of the Criminal Procedure Code.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11944"><num>76</num><heading>SECTION 76 Regulations.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>76.</xhtml:b>The Minister may make regulations generally for the better carrying out of the provisions and purposes of this Act. and without prejudice to the generality of the foregoing power such regulations may make provision - 
<xhtml:p>(a) for the remuneration of persons to the care of whom persons are committed;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) for the prevention of infectious and contagious diseases in approved schools and juvenile remand homes and for the medical examination of their inmates;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) for causing photographs or fingerprints to be taken of persons in juvenile remand homes and approved schools, and for recording them; (<xhtml:br/>in relation to the care of children, including the inspection of premises maintained by such societies wholly or partly for the care of children; </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(e) for the compulsory registration of voluntary institutions, nurseries, children's homes, boarding out establishments, holiday homes, places of safety and other institutions, not being schools, hospitals, convalescent homes or similar institutions, where children are received and cared for for reward;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(f) for the inspection of voluntary institutions, children's homes and nurseries, boarding out establishments, holiday homes and places of safety.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11945"><num>77</num><heading>SECTION 77 Rules.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>77.</xhtml:b>The Chief Justice may make rules - 
<xhtml:p>(a) for regulating the manner in which juvenile courts shall be constituted under this Act and for providing a chairman thereof;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(b) to provide for the transfer of proceedings to juvenile courts;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) to provide for the procedure to be followed by juvenile courts and in particular as to the recording of evidence and the manner of arriving at and recording findings and orders;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(d) prescribing the punishment which may be imposed under section 27 (2) of this Act;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(e) providing for appeals against any order imposing any such punishment;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(f) providing for the appointment of suitable persons to assist and advise the court in the exercise of its jurisdiction under this Act and for the functions of such persons, regard being had to the desirability of securing that in any case concerning a child belonging to a particular community such persons as aforesaid shall be persons belonging to the same community.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11946"><num>78</num><heading>SECTION 78 Grants, and expenses of the Minister.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>78.</xhtml:b>There shall be paid out of moneys provided by Parliament - 
<xhtml:p>(a) such sums on such conditions as the Minister may authorize towards - </xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(i) the expenses of the manager of an approved school;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(ii) the expenses of the manager of a juvenile remand home;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(h) such sums as grants or grants-in-aid to appointed local authorities or approved societies as may be authorized by the Minister from time to time;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(c) such sums as may be authorized by the Minister for the relief of destitute or vagrant children or for the boarding out of persons under eighteen years of age with fit persons;</xhtml:p><xhtml:p>(d) any other expenses incurred by the Minister in the administration of this Act.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></content></section><section id="section-11947"><num>79</num><heading>SECTION 79 Transitional provision.</heading><content><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><xhtml:b>79.</xhtml:b>Any person who immediately before the commencement of this Act was detained in an approved school under the provisions of the Juvenile Act, 1934 (now repealed), shall, if that school is not an approved school under the provisions of this Act, forthwith on the commencement of this Act to be transferred to an appropriate approved school.</xhtml:div></foreign></content></section></body><outOfLines><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-19063" id="w1085aab1b9b1" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"/></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-19064" id="w1085aab1b9b3" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"/></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-19065" id="w1085aab1b9b5" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"/></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11869" id="w1085aab1b9b7" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Short title</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11870" id="w1085aab1b9b9" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Interpretation.  
<xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p> Cap.128.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11871" id="w1085aab1b9c11" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Juvenile courts. 10 of 1970,Sch.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11872" id="w1085aab1b9c13" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Sitting of juvenile courts.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11873" id="w1085aab1b9c15" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Prohibition of publication.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11874" id="w1085aab1b9c17" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Prevention of persons under 16 associating with adult offenders.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11875" id="w1085aab1b9c19" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Children not allowed in court.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11876" id="w1085aab1b9c21" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Power to clear court.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11877" id="w1085aab1b9c23" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Power to require attendance of parent.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11878" id="w1085aab1b9c25" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Bail of persons under 18 arrested.  
<xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11879" id="w1085aab1b9c27" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Remand in custody.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11880" id="w1085aab1b9c29" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Jurisdiction of juvenile courts. Cap. 75.  
<xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11881" id="w1085aab1b9c31" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Jurisdiction of juvenile courts.  
<xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11882" id="w1085aab1b9c33" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Considerations of welfare.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11883" id="w1085aab1b9c35" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Words "conviction" and "sentence" not to be used of children and young persons.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11884" id="w1085aab1b9c37" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Restrictions on punishments.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11885" id="w1085aab1b9c39" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Methods of dealing with offenders.  
<xhtml:p>Cap. 63. Cap. 64.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11886" id="w1085aab1b9c41" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Mental treatment.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11887" id="w1085aab1b9c43" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Power to order parent to pay fine, etc.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11888" id="w1085aab1b9c45" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Jurisdiction under Part III</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11889" id="w1085aab1b9c47" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Presumptions regarding custody, charge and care of children and juveniles. Cap.152.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11890" id="w1085aab1b9c49" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">When child or juvenile is in need of protection or discipline.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11891" id="w1085aab1b9c51" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Penalty for cruelty to and neglecting children or juveniles.  
<xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p>Cap.63</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11892" id="w1085aab1b9c53" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Proceedings in respect of children and juveniles in need of protection. or discipline.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11893" id="w1085aab1b9c55" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Powers of court in respect of children or juveniles in need of protection or discipline.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11894" id="w1085aab1b9c57" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Parent or guardian may be heard in any application.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11895" id="w1085aab1b9c59" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Application of trusts for maintenance of children or juveniles.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11896" id="w1085aab1b9c61" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Determination of court as to person's home, etc., to be final.  
<xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11897" id="w1085aab1b9c63" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Warrants for search for children or juveniles.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11898" id="w1085aab1b9c65" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Arrest without warrant.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11899" id="w1085aab1b9c67" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Provisions as to orders of committal to fit persons L.N.149/1964.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11900" id="w1085aab1b9c69" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Contents of committal order.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11901" id="w1085aab1b9c71" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Transmission of order.  
<xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11902" id="w1085aab1b9c73" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Production of child or juvenile.  
<xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11903" id="w1085aab1b9c75" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Establishment of juvenile remand homes</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11904" id="w1085aab1b9c77" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Establishment of juvenile remand homes  
<xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11905" id="w1085aab1b9c79" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Approval of schools.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11906" id="w1085aab1b9c81" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Minister may establish approved schools.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11907" id="w1085aab1b9c83" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Obligations of managers.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11908" id="w1085aab1b9c85" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Supervision of approved schools and juvenile remand homes</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11909" id="w1085aab1b9c87" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Leave of absence.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11910" id="w1085aab1b9c89" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Leave of absence.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11911" id="w1085aab1b9c91" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Release on licence.  
<xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11912" id="w1085aab1b9c93" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Revocation of approved school order: duration of order.  
<xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11913" id="w1085aab1b9c95" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Transfers and supervision after release.  
<xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11914" id="w1085aab1b9c97" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Treatment of absconders and persons of bad character.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11915" id="w1085aab1b9c99" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Removal to hospital</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11916" id="w1085aab1b9d101" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Authority for detention in juvenile remand homes, approved schools and hospitals.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11917" id="w1085aab1b9d103" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Application of Part VI.  
<xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p> Cap. 248 </xhtml:p><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p> Cap. 143.</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11918" id="w1085aab1b9d105" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Notification of taking possession of a person.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11919" id="w1085aab1b9d107" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Notification of change of residence or of death.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11920" id="w1085aab1b9d109" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Summary order for removal of person.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11921" id="w1085aab1b9d111" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Removal of person in respect of whom an offence has been committed.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11922" id="w1085aab1b9d113" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Appointment of chief inspector of children, inspectors of children and children's officers. L.N. 149/1964.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11923" id="w1085aab1b9d115" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Duties of officers  
<xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11924" id="w1085aab1b9d117" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Powers of officers.  
<xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11925" id="w1085aab1b9d119" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Obstruction</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11926" id="w1085aab1b9d121" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Appointment of local authorities. L.N.256/1963.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11927" id="w1085aab1b9d123" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Application of powers and duties. L.N.256/1963.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11928" id="w1085aab1b9d125" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Delegation of functions of county councils. L.N.256/1963.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11929" id="w1085aab1b9d127" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Delegation of certain powers and duties by appointed local authorities.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11930" id="w1085aab1b9d129" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Powers of local authorities to incur expenditure in temporary care.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11931" id="w1085aab1b9d131" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Approval of approved societies.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11932" id="w1085aab1b9d133" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Appointment and powers of approved officers.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11933" id="w1085aab1b9d135" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Escapes from fit persons, etc</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11934" id="w1085aab1b9d137" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Approved societies and appointed local authorities to report escape.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11935" id="w1085aab1b9d139" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Escapes from juvenile remand homes and approved schools.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11936" id="w1085aab1b9d141" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Assisting escape, etc.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11937" id="w1085aab1b9d143" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Production of escape person</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11938" id="w1085aab1b9d145" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Presumptions and determination of age.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11939" id="w1085aab1b9d147" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Contribution orders.  
<xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p>Cap. 75</xhtml:p></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11940" id="w1085aab1b9d149" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Affiliation orders.  
<xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p> </xhtml:p><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p> Cap 142</xhtml:p><xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11941" id="w1085aab1b9d151" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">International reciprocity L.N.149/1964  
<xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11942" id="w1085aab1b9d153" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Bonds. Cap. 75.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11943" id="w1085aab1b9d155" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Appeals.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11944" id="w1085aab1b9d157" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Regulation.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11945" id="w1085aab1b9d159" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Rules.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11946" id="w1085aab1b9d161" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Grants, and expenses of the Minister.  
<xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/><xhtml:p/></xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine><outOfLine xmlns:kl="http://kenyalaw.org/metadata" href="#section-11947" id="w1085aab1b9d163" type="sideNote"><foreign><xhtml:div xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">Transitional provision. 22 of 1934.</xhtml:div></foreign></outOfLine></outOfLines></act></akomaNtoso>