<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../../../../../../XSD/styles/kenya.xsl"?><!--Akoma_Ntoso document--><akomantoso xmlns="http://www.akomantoso.org/1.0" xmlns:cirsfid="http://www.cirsfid.unibo.it/proprietary" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><act contains="OriginalVersion"><meta><identification source="#au1"><Work><uri href="/ken/act/1997-08-22/3"/><date date="2007-03-14" name="Generation"/><author id="au1" href="parliament"/></Work><Expression><uri href="/ken/act/1997-08-22/3/eng"/><date date="2007-03-14" name="Generation"/><author id="au2" href="http://www.cirsfid.unibo.it"/><components><component id="ce1" href="ken/act/1997-08-22/3/eng/main" showAs="main"/></components></Expression><Manifestation><uri href="/ken/act/1997-08-22/3/eng.xml"/><date date="2007-03-14" name="Generation"/><author href="#au2"/><components><component id="cm1" href="ken/act/1997-08-22/3/eng/main.xml" showAs="main"/></components></Manifestation></identification><publication name="internal" date="1997-08-29" showAs=""/><lifecycle source="#au1"><event id="e1" date="1997-08-29" source="#ro1" type="Generation"/></lifecycle><references source="#au1"><Original id="ro1" href="ken/act/1997-08-22/3/eng/main" showAs="Original"/><Attachment id="ran1" href="main/schedule" type="integralAttachment" showAs=""/></references><proprietary source="#au1"><cirsfid:proprietary><cirsfid:MissingInfo><cirsfid:mDocType>act</cirsfid:mDocType></cirsfid:MissingInfo></cirsfid:proprietary></proprietary></meta><preface><p>Kenya Gazette Supplement No. 63 (Acts No. 4)<eol/>REPUBLIC OF KENYA<eol/>KENYA GAZETTE SUPPLEMENT<eol/>ACTS, 1997<eol/>NAIROBI, 29th August, 1997<eol/><ActTitle id="ActTitle">THE RETIREMENTS BENEFITS ACT, 1997</ActTitle><eol/>No. <ActNumber>3</ActNumber> of 1997<eol/>Date of Assent: <ActDate date="1997-08-22">22nd August, 1997</ActDate><eol/>Date of Commencement:-By-Notice<eol/>ARRANGEMENT OF SECTIONS<eol/>PART I<eol/>PRELIMINARY<eol/>1. Short title and commencement.<eol/>2. Interpretation.<eol/>PART II<eol/>THE RETIREMENT BENEFITS AUTHORITY<eol/>3. Establishment and incorporation of the Retirement Benefits Authority.<eol/>4. Headquarters.<eol/>5. Object and functions of the Authourity<eol/>6. Board of directors.<eol/>7. The powers of the Board.<eol/>8. Conduct of business and affairs of the Board.<eol/>9. Delegation by the Authority.<eol/>10. Remuneration of Board members.<eol/>11. The Chief Executive Officer.<eol/>12. Staff of the Authority.<eol/>13. The common seal of the Authority.<eol/>14. Protection from personal liability.<eol/>15. Liability of the Authority for damages.<eol/>16. The Retirement Benefits Levy.<eol/>17. The Retirement Benefits Authority Fund.<eol/>18. Investment of funds.<eol/>19. Financial year.<eol/>20. Annual estimates.<eol/>21. Accounts and audit.<eol/>PART III<eol/>REGISTRATION OF RETIREMENT BENEFITS SCHEMES AND MANAGERS<eol/>22. Retirement benefits schemes and managers to be registered.<eol/>23. Registration.<eol/>24. Requirements for registration of schemes.<eol/>25. Requirements for registration of managers.<eol/>26. Requirements with regard to trustees.<eol/>27. Refusal of registration.<eol/>28. Deregistration.<eol/>29. Duration of certificate of registration.<eol/>30. Register.<eol/>31. Use of register in evidence.<eol/>PART IV<eol/>REGULATION AND SUPERVISION OF RETIREMENT BENEFITS SCHEMES<eol/>32. Scheme funds.<eol/>33. Statutory contributions.<eol/>34. Annual report and accounts.<eol/>35. Actuarial evaluations.<eol/>36. Protection against attachment.<eol/>37. Investment of funds.<eol/>38. Restrictions on use of scheme funds.<eol/>39. Unsafe and unsound practices.<eol/>40. General obligations of trustees and managers.<eol/>PART V<eol/>INSPECTION AND APPOINTMENT OF INTERIM ADMINISTRATOR<eol/>41. Inspection.<eol/>42. Powers of the inspector.<eol/>43. Inspection report.<eol/>44. Directions to trustees or manager.<eol/>45. Appointment of interim administrator.<eol/>PART VI<eol/>APPEALS<eol/>46. Appeals to the Chief Executive Officer.<eol/>47. Appeals to the Tribunal.<eol/>48. Powers of Appeals Tribunal.<eol/>49. Establishment of Appeals Tribunal.<eol/>50. Refusal or failure to give evidence.<eol/>51. Costs.<eol/>52. Rules for appeals to the Appeals Tribunal.<eol/>PART VII<eol/>MISCELLANEOUS<eol/>53. General penalty.<eol/>54. Offences by corporate bodies, partnerships, principals and employees.<eol/>55. Regulations.<eol/>56. Exemption from Cap. 446.<eol/>57. Transitional provisions.<eol/>58. Supersession.<eol/>SCHEDULE<eol/>PROVISIONS AS TO THE CONDUCT OF THE BUSINESS AND AFFAIRS OF THE BOARD.</p></preface><preamble id="preamble"><p>THE RETIREMENT BENEFITS ACT. 1997<eol/>An Act of Parliament to establish a Retirement Benefits Authority for the regulation, supervision and promotion of retirement benefits schemes, the development of the retirement benefits sector and for connected purposes<eol/>ENACTED by the Parliament of Kenya as follows -</p></preamble><clauses><part id="prtI"><num>PART I</num><title>PART I - PRELIMINARY</title><article id="art1"><num>1.</num><title>Short title and commencement.</title><clause id="art1-cla1"><p>This Act may be cited as the Retirement Benefits Act. 1997. and shall come into operation on such date as the Minister may. by notice in the Gazette, appoint and different dates may be appointed for different provisions.</p></clause></article><article id="art2"><num>2.</num><title>Interpretation.</title><clause id="art2-cla1"><p>In this Act, unless the context otherwise requires - <eol/>"Actuary" means a fellow of the Institute of Actuaries in F.ngland. or of the Faculty of Actuaries in Scotland, or of the Canadian Institute of Actuaries, or a person holding such equivalent qualification as the Board may, by notice in the Gazette, prescribe;<eol/>"Authority" means the Retirement Benefits Authority established by section 3;<eol/>"Board" means the Board of Directors of the Authority constituted under section 6;<eol/>"Chief Executive Officer" means the Chief Executive Officer of the Authority appointed under section 11;<eol/>"financial year" means the financial year of the Authority prescribed by section 19;<eol/>"Fund" means the Retirement Benefits Authority Fund established by section 17;<eol/>"Levy" means the Retirement Benefits Levy to be imposed under section 16;<eol/>"manager" means the manager of a scheme fund;<eol/>"member" means a member of a retirement benefits scheme and includes a person entitled to or receiving a benefit under a retirement benefits scheme;<eol/>"Minister" means the Minister for the time being responsible for matters relating to finance;<eol/>"retirement benefits scheme" means any scheme or arrangement (other than a contract for life assurance) whether established by a written law for the time being in force or by any other instrument, under which persons are entitled to benefits in the form of payments, determined by age, length of service, amount of earnings or otherwise and payable primarily upon retirement, or upon death, termination of service, or upon the occurrence of such other event as may be specified in such written law or other instrument;<eol/>"scheme" means a retirement benefits scheme; <eol/>"scheme fund" means the retirement benefits scheme fund to be established pursuant to the provisions of section 32;<eol/>"scheme rules" means the rules specifically governing the constitution and administration of a particular scheme;<eol/>"sponsor" means a person who establishes a scheme;<eol/>"Tribunal" means the Appeals Tribunal established under section 48;<eol/>"trustee" means a trustee of a scheme fund.</p></clause></article></part><part id="prtII"><num>PART II</num><title>PART II - THE RETIREMENT BENEFITS AUTHORITY</title><article id="art3"><num>3.</num><title>Establishment and incorporation of the Retirement Benefits Authority</title><clause id="art3-cla1"><num>(1)</num><p>There is established an Authority to be known as the Retirement Benefits Authority.</p></clause><clause id="art3-cla2"><num>(2)</num><p>The Authority shall be a body corporate with perpetual succession and a common seal and shall in its corporate name be capable of -</p><ul id="ul1"><li id="art3-cla2-itma"><p>(a) suing and being sued;</p></li><li id="art3-cla2-itmb"><p>(b) taking, purchasing or otherwise acquiring, holding, charging or disposing of movable and immovable property;</p></li><li id="art3-cla2-itmc"><p>(c) borrowing or lending money: and</p></li><li id="art3-cla2-itmd"><p>(d) doing or performing all other things or acts for the furtherance of the provisions of this Act. which may be lawfully done or performed by a body corporate.</p></li></ul></clause></article><article id="art5"><num>5.</num><title>Object and functions of the Authority</title><clause id="art5-cla5"><p>The object and functions of the Authority shall be to -</p><ul id="ul2"><li id="art5-cla5-itma"><p>(a) regulate and supervise the establishment and management of retirement benefits schemes:</p></li><li id="art5-cla5-itmb"><p>(b) protect the interests of members and sponsors of retirement benefits schemes:</p></li><li id="art5-cla5-itmc"><p>(c) promote the development of the retirement benefits sector:</p></li><li id="art5-cla5-itmd"><p>(d) advise the Minister on the national policy to be followed with regard to retirement benefits schemes and to implement all Government policies relating thereto; and</p></li><li id="art5-cla5-itme"><p>(e) perform such other functions as are conferred on it by this Act or by any other written law.</p></li></ul></clause></article><article id="art6"><num>6.</num><title>Board of Directors</title><clause id="art6-cla1"><p>The management of the Authority shall vest in a Board of Directors of the Authority which shall comprise -</p><ul id="ul3"><li id="art6-cla1-itma"><p>(a) a chairman to be appointed by the Minister from amongst the members appointed under paragraph (0);</p></li><li id="art6-cla1-itmb"><p>(b) the Chief Executive Officer appointed under section 11:</p></li><li id="art6-cla1-itmc"><p>(c) the Permanent Secretary in the Ministry for the time being responsible for matters relating to finance or his representative;</p></li><li id="art6-cla1-itmd"><p>(d) the Commissioner of Insurance;</p></li><li id="art6-cla1-itme"><p>(e) the Chief Executive of the Capital Markets Authority; and</p></li><li id="art6-cla1-itmf"><p>(f) five members, not being public officers, appointed by the Minister by virtue of their knowledge or experience in matters relating to the administration of scheme funds, banking, insurance, law or actuarial studies.</p></li></ul></clause></article><article id="art7"><num>7.</num><title>Powers of the Board.</title><clause id="art7-cla1"><p>The Board shall have all powers necessary for the performance of its functions under this Act and in particular, the Board shall have power to -</p><ul id="ul4"><li id="art7-cla1-itma"><p>(a) control, supervise and administer the assets of the Authority in such manner and for such purposes as best promote the purpose for which the Authority is established;</p></li><li id="art7-cla1-itmb"><p>(b) determine the provisions to be made for capital and recurrent expenditure and for reserves of the Authority;</p></li><li id="art7-cla1-itmc"><p>(c) receive any grants, gifts, donations or endowments on behalf of the Authority and make legitimate disbursements therefrom;</p></li><li id="art7-cla1-itmd"><p>(d) enter into association with other bodies or organisations within or outside Kenya as the Board may consider desirable or appropriate and in furtherance of the purpose for which the Authority is established;</p></li><li id="art7-cla1-itme"><p>(e) open a banking account or banking accounts for the funds of the Authority; and</p></li><li id="art7-cla1-itmf"><p>(f) invest the funds of the Authority not currently required for its purposes in the manner provided in section 18.</p></li></ul></clause></article><article id="art8"><num>8.</num><title>Conduct of business and affairs of the Board.</title><clause id="art8-cla1"><p>The conduct and regulation of the business and affairs of the Board shall be as provided in the Schedule but subject thereto, the Board shall regulate its own procedure.</p></clause></article><article id="art9"><num>9.</num><title>Delegation by the Board.</title><clause id="art9-cla1"><p>The Board may, by resolution either generally or in any particular case, delegate to any committee of the Board or to any member, officer, employee or agent of the Authority, the exercise of any of the powers or the performance of any of the functions or duties of the Authority under this Act or under any other written law.</p></clause></article></part></clauses><attachments><attachment id="ann1-ken_act_19970822_3_eng" href="main/schedule" showAs="SCHEDULE (s.S) PROVISIONS AS TOTHE CONDUCT OF BUSINESS AND AFFAIRS OF THE BOARD."/></attachments></act></akomantoso>