<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../../../../../../XSD/styles/nigeria.xsl"?><!--Akoma_Ntoso document--><akomantoso xmlns="http://www.akomantoso.org/1.0" xmlns:cirsfid="http://www.cirsfid.unibo.it/proprietary" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><act contains="SingleVersion"><meta><identification source="#au1"><Work><uri href="/nga/act/1979-04-20/30"/><date date="2007-03-21" name="Generation"/><author href="parliament" id="au1"/></Work><Expression><uri href="/nga/act/1979-04-20/30/eng@1992-12-28"/><date date="2007-03-21" name="Generation"/><author href="http://www.cirsfid.unibo.it" id="au2"/><components><component href="nga/act/1979-04-20/30/eng@1992-12-28/main" id="ce1" showAs="main"/></components></Expression><Manifestation><uri href="/nga/act/1979-04-20/30/eng@1992-12-28.xml"/><date date="2007-03-21" name="Generation"/><author href="#au2"/><components><component href="nga/act/1979-04-20/30/eng@1992-12-28/main.xml" id="cm1" showAs="main"/></components></Manifestation></identification><publication date="1979-04-30" name="" showAs=""/><lifecycle source="#au1"><event date="1979-04-30" id="e1" source="#ro1" type="Generation"/><event date="1992-12-28" id="e2" source="#rp1" type="Amendment"/></lifecycle><analysis source="#au1"><PassiveModifications><Textual id="pm1" type="Insertion"><source href="nga/act/1992-12-28/109/eng/main#ref11"/><destination href="#art4-cla2"/></Textual><Textual id="pm2" type="Insertion"><source href="nga/act/1992-12-28/109/eng/main#ref8"/><destination href="#art1-cla1"/></Textual></PassiveModifications></analysis><references source="#au1"><Original href="nga/act/1979-04-20/30/eng/main" id="ro1" showAs="Original"/><PassiveRef href="nga/act/1992-12-28/109/eng/main" id="rp1" showAs=""/></references><notes source="#au1"><note id="n1"><p>
1. Insertion. The text  - (d) if he suspends or gives notice that he is about to suspend payment of his debts to any of his creditors; or (e) if under a credit agreement the creditor becomes entitled to file a bankruptcy petition; or (f) if, in Nigeria or elsewhere, he makes a conveyance or assignment of his property to a trustee or trustees for the benefit of his creditor generally; or(g) if, in Nigeria or elsewhere, he makes a fraudulent conveyance gift, delivery or transfer of his property or any part thereof, with an intent to defeat or delay the claim of his creditors; or (h) if, in Nigeria or elsewhere, he makes any conveyance or transfer of his property or any part thereof; or created any charge thereon, which would under this or any other Act be void as a fraudulent preference if he were adjudged bankrupt; or(i) if, with intent to defeat or delay the claims of his creditors, he departs out of Nigeria, or being out of Nigeria remains out of Nigeria, or departs from his dwelling, or otherwise absents himself, or begins to keep house. -   has been inserted.						<eol/>
Modification effective as from: 28/12/1992.						<eol/><a href="nga/act/1992-12-28/109/eng/main#ref8" title="modifiyng">Modificatory document</a>
: act n. 109 28/12/1992 (language: en).					</p></note><note id="n2"><p>
2. Insertion. The text  - (3) Notwithstanding the provisions of any other law or enactment and without prejudice to any other rights of the debtor, a creditor who is entitled to present a bankruptcy petition on or before the end of December, 1992 shall not be disentitled from presenting a petition by virtue only of the provisions of section 4(1) (c) of this Act if the petition is presented before the expiration of a period of six months. -   has been inserted.						<eol/>
Modification effective as from: 28/12/1992.						<eol/><a href="nga/act/1992-12-28/109/eng@main#ref11" title="modifiyng">Modificatory document</a>
: act n. 109 28/12/1992 (language: en).					</p></note></notes><proprietary source="#au1"><cirsfid:proprietary><cirsfid:MissingInfo><cirsfid:mDocType>act</cirsfid:mDocType></cirsfid:MissingInfo></cirsfid:proprietary></proprietary></meta><preface><p><ActTitle id="ActTitle">Bankruptcy Act</ActTitle><eol/>
Chapter				<ActNumber>30</ActNumber><eol/>
Laws of the Federation of Nigeria 1990				<eol/><ActDate date="1979-04-20">20th April 1979</ActDate></p></preface><preamble id="preamble"><p>An Act to make provisions for declaring as bankrupt any person who can not pay his debts of a specified amount and to disqualify him from holding certain elective and other public offices or from practising any regulated profession (except as an employee).</p></preamble><clauses><part id="prtI"><title>Part I Proceedings from act of bankruptcy to discharge</title><article id="art1"><clause id="art1-cla1"><num>(a)</num><p>A debtor commits an act of bankruptcy in each of the following cases-</p><list id="art1-cla1-lst1"><item id="art1-cla1-itma"><p>if a creditor -</p><list id="art1-cla1-itma-lst1"><item id="art1-cla1-itma-itmi"><num>(i)</num><p>has obtained a final judgment or final order against him for any amount, and execution thereon not having been stayed, has a bankruptcy notice served on him, and</p></item><item id="art1-cla1-itma-itmii"><num>(ii)</num><p>does not, within fourteen days after service of the notice, comply with the requirements of the notice or satisfy the court that he has a counter-claim, set off or cross demand which equals or exceeds the amount of the judgment debt or sum ordered to be paid, and which he could not set up in the action in which the judgment was obtained or the proceedings in which the order was obtained, and for the purposes of this paragraph and of section 4. any person who is for the time being entitled to enforce a final judgment or final order shall be deemed to be a creditor who has obtained a final judgment or final order;</p></item></list></item><item id="art1-cla1-itmb"><num>(b)</num><p>
if execution against him has been levied by seizure of his goods under process in an action, or proceedings in the court, and the goods have either been sold or held by the bailiff for twenty-one days:									<eol/>
Provided that, where an inter-pleader summons has been taken out in regard to the goods seized, the time elapsing between the date at which such summons is taken out and the date at which the proceedings on such summons are finally disposed of, settled or abandoned shall not be taken into account in calculating such period of twenty-one days;								</p></item><item id="art1-cla1-itmc"><num>(c)</num><p>if he files in the court a declaration of his inability to pay his debts or presents a bankruptcy petition against himself</p></item><item id="art1-cla1-itmd" startEfficacy="e2"><num><b><b>(d)</b></b></num><p><b>if he suspends or gives notice that he is about to suspend payment of his debts to any of his creditors; or</b></p></item><item id="art1-cla1-itme" startEfficacy="e2"><num><b><b>(e)</b></b></num><p><b>if under a credit agreement the creditor becomes entitled to file a bankruptcy petition; or</b></p></item><item id="art1-cla1-itmf" startEfficacy="e2"><num><b><b>(f)</b></b></num><p><b>if, in Nigeria or elsewhere, he makes a conveyance or assignment of his property to a trustee or trustees for the benefit of his creditor generally; or</b></p></item><item id="art1-cla1-itmg" startEfficacy="e2"><num><b><b>(g)</b></b></num><p><b>if, in Nigeria or elsewhere, he makes a fraudulent conveyance gift, delivery or transfer of his property or any part thereof, with an intent to defeat or delay the claim of his creditors; or</b></p></item><item id="art1-cla1-itmh" startEfficacy="e2"><num><b><b>(h)</b></b></num><p><b>if, in Nigeria or elsewhere, he makes any conveyance or transfer of his property or any part thereof; or created any charge thereon, which would under this or any other Act be void as a fraudulent preference if he were adjudged bankrupt; or</b></p></item><item id="art1-cla1-itmi"><num><b><b>(i)</b></b></num><p><b>if, with intent to defeat or delay the claims of his creditors, he departs out of Nigeria, or being out of Nigeria remains out of Nigeria, or departs from his dwelling, or otherwise absents himself, or begins to keep house.</b><b><noteref href="n1" num="1"/></b>
.								</p></item></list></clause></article><article id="art2"><clause id="art2-cla1"><num>(b)</num><p>shall not be invalidated by reason only that the sum specified in the notice as the amount due exceeds the amount actually due, unless the debtor within the time allowed for payment gives notice to the creditor that he disputes the validity of the notice on the ground of such mis-statement; but if the debtor does not give such notice, he shall be deemed to have complied with the bankruptcy notice if within the time allowed he takes such steps as would have constituted a compliance with the notice had the actual amount due been correctly specified therein.</p></clause></article><article id="art3"><clause id="art3-cla1"><p>3. Subject to the conditions hereinafter specified, if a debtor commits an act of bankruptcy the court may, on a bankruptcy petition being presented either by a creditor or by the debtor, make an order, in this Act called a receiving order, for the protection of the estate.</p></clause></article><article id="art4"><clause id="art4-cla1"><num>(d)</num><p>the debtor is ordinarily resident in Nigeria, or within a year before the date of the presentation of the petition, has ordinarily resided or had a dwelling-house or place of business in Nigeria, or has carried on business in Nigeria, personally or by means of an agent or manager, or is or within the said period has been a member of a firm or partnership of persons which has carried on business in Nigeria by means of a partner or partners or an agent or manager.</p></clause><clause id="art4-cla2"><p>
(2) If the petitioning creditor is a secured creditor he shall in his petition either state that he is willing to give up his security for the benefit of the creditors in the event of the debtor being adjudged bankrupt, or give an estimate of the value of his security; in the latter case he may be admitted as a petitioning creditor to the extent of the balance of the debt due to him after deducting the value so estimated in the same manner as if he were an unsecured creditor							<eol/><b><span start="#e2">
(3) Notwithstanding the provisions of any other law or enactment and without prejudice to any other rights of the debtor, a creditor who is entitled to present a bankruptcy petition on or before the end of December, 1992 shall not be disentitled from presenting a petition by virtue only of the provisions of section 4(1) (c) of this Act if the petition is presented before the expiration of a period of six months.									<noteref href="n2" num="2"/></span></b>
.						</p></clause></article><article id="art5"><clause id="art5-cla1"><num>(c)</num><p>the right of a creditor to present a bankruptcy petition against the firm, and the jurisdiction of the court to make a receiving order or an adjudication of bankruptcy against the firm, shall not be affected by the fact, if it is so, that all or any of the partners of the firm are not citizens of Nigeria or are not resident in Nigeria.</p></clause></article><article id="art6"><clause id="art6-cla1"><p>6. (1) Immediately on the filing of any petition the Official Receiver may in cases where he has reason to believe that any offence under this Act or any fraud has been or is about to be perpetrated, by notice delivered to the debtor in person or by ordinary post, summon the debtor to attend before him to give such information as he requires, and may, either by himself or his agent authorised by him in writing, enter on any premises occupied by the debtor between the hours of 8 a.m. and 6 p.m. for the purpose of inspecting his property, stock in trade and books of account.</p></clause><clause id="art6-cla2"><p>It shall be the duty of the debtor to furnish the Official Receiver with all such information as it is in the debtor's power to give or to obtain.</p></clause><clause id="art6-cla3"><num>(c)</num><p>authorises or permits any obstruction,the debtor shall be liable on summary conviction to imprisonment for a term not exceeding six months.</p></clause><clause id="art6-cla4"><num>(4)</num><p>Every person who takes any part in any obstruction mentioned in subsection (3)(b) and (c) of this section, whether authorised or permitted by the debtor or not, shall be liable to the like penalty.</p></clause></article></part></clauses></act></akomantoso>